<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="7">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 22, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00011492</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>010099</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>01-DC-0099</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00011492</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00045071</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Patient Evaluation for Head and Neck Surgery Branch Studies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation for NIDCD Head &amp; Neck Surgery Branch Clinical Research Protocols</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders (NIDCD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Federal Government</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This protocol offers evaluation and, in some cases, standard treatment for patients with
      head and neck cancer in NIDCD s Head and Neck Surgery Branch (HNSB). The study is not
      designed to test new treatments. Its purpose is twofold: 1) to identify patients who may be
      eligible for investigational protocols. (Participants in this protocol will not be required
      to join a research study; the decision will be voluntary.); and 2) to provide standard
      treatment for patients who are not eligible for an investigational study but who present an
      education and training opportunity for HNSB physicians and clinical fellows.

      Patients with head and neck cancer may enroll in this study. Participants may undergo
      various tests, described below, to determine their eligibility for participation in a
      specific clinical trial. Other tests may also be required, depending on the protocol or
      treatment for which the patient is being considered:

        -  Blood tests About 3 to 5 tablespoons of blood will be drawn for routine tests, HLA
           typing and hepatitis and HIV screening.

        -  Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) This imaging procedure uses a powerful magnetic field
           to produce pictures of parts of the body in small section views. The test does not use
           radiation and may be done with or without a contrast dye material.

        -  Computerized tomography (CT) This procedure uses x-rays to produces three-dimensional
           images of body organs in small section views. A contrast dye may or may not be used.

        -  Positron emission tomography (PET) PET scans allow the doctor to see the activity of
           cells in specific body tissues. It requires injection of a radioactive material that
           attaches to a sugar fluid. The fluid goes to very active cells, such as cancer cells,
           revealing tumors.

        -  Pulmonary function tests These tests use a machine the patient breathes into to measure
           the volume of air the patient can move in and out of the lungs.

        -  Arteriogram, or angiogram The anatomy of the blood vessels can be seen using this
           procedure, which involves placing a small catheter (plastic tube) into an artery and
           injecting a contrast solution. Special X-rays are then taken to show the blood vessels.

        -  Endoscopy This procedure is done to evaluate the mouth and throat. A tube with a light
           on the end and special fibers is inserted down the throat to allow the surgeon to
           examine the throat and, if needed, biopsy a piece of tissue for microscopic study. The
           test is usually done under general anesthesia in the operating room.

        -  Biopsy A piece of tissue or tumor is removed for examination under the microscope. When
           a biopsy is done in the neck area, a small amount of anesthetic is injected into the
           area of the biopsy. The biopsy may be done with 1) a small needle to pull out some
           tissue, 2) a cookie-cutter-like instrument to punch out a small piece of tissue, or 3)
           a small knife to cut out a piece of tissue. A knife biopsy may be done in the operating
           room or the clinic depending on the location of the biopsy and precautions required.

      When the tests are done, the physician will discuss the results with the patient. Patients
      eligible for a research study will be offered participation. For those not eligible for a
      study, other therapies will be discussed and the patient will return to the care of his or
      her primary physician. In special circumstances, patients may be offered standard
      non-experimental treatment at NIH.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This protocol will provide a means for screening potential candidates for head and neck
      surgery branch protocols. No investigational treatments will be administered in this
      protocol. The PI may, however, approve a patient who has been determined to be ineligible
      for HNSB protocols to undergo standard treatment because they present a unique clinical
      experience for maintaining skills of HNSB physicians and clinical fellows.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2001</start_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Time Perspective: Prospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To permit evaluation of patients to NIDCD Head and Neck Branch in order to identify suitable candidates for NIDCD NCI Head and Neck protocols or other NCI-based Head and Neck Cancer protocols.</measure>
    <time_frame>12/31/2018</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Head and Neck Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Pharyngeal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Oral Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</condition>
  <condition>Laryngeal Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:

        Patients at risk. Suspected of having, or with a biopsy proven neoplastic disease of the
        head and neck.

        Patient, parent or guardian (if a minor) able to provide informed consent.

        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:

        Candidates who do not meet the inclusion criteria.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carter Van Waes, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders (NIDCD)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Susannah S Wargo, C.R.N.P.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-4887</phone>
    <email>swargo@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Carter Van Waes, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 402-4216</phone>
    <email>vanwaesc@nidcd.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Patient Recruitment and Public Liaison Office (PRPL)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@mail.cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2001-DC-0099.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 11, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 22, 2001</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Oral Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Squamous Cell Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Head and Neck Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Laryngeal Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharnygeal Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Squamous Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mouth Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
