<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="155">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02423343</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15702</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>H9H-MC-JBEF</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02423343</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Galunisertib (LY2157299) in Combination With Nivolumab in Advanced Refractory Solid Tumors and in Recurrent or Refractory NSCLC, Hepatocellular Carcinoma, or Glioblastoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b/2 Dose Escalation and Cohort Expansion Study of the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of a Novel Transforming Growth Factor-beta Receptor I Kinase Inhibitor (Galunisertib) Administered in Combination With Anti-PD-1 (Nivolumab) in Advanced Refractory Solid Tumors (Phase 1b) and in Recurrent or Refractory Non-small Cell Lung Cancer, Hepatocellular Carcinoma, or Glioblastoma (Phase 2)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eli Lilly and Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Eli Lilly and Company</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and efficacy of the
      study drug known as galunisertib in combination with nivolumab in participants with advanced
      refractory solid tumors and in recurrent or refractory non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC),
      hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) or glioblastoma.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 1b: Maximum Tolerated Dose of Galunisertib in Combination with Nivolumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 through Cycle 2 (Estimated up to 2 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics (PK): Minimum Concentration (Cmin) of Nivolumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 through Cycle 4 Day 1 (Estimated up to 4 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PK: Steady State Concentration of Galunisertib</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 through Cycle 4 Day 1 (Estimated up to 4 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Anti-Nivolumab Antibodies When Administered in Combination with Galunisertib</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 through Follow-up (Estimated up to 6 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Measured Progressive Disease or Death (Estimated up to 18 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Number of Participants who Achieve Best Overall Tumor Response of Complete Response or Partial Response: Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Measured Progressive Disease (Estimated up to 18 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Duration of Response (DoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Date of Complete Response (CR) or Partial Response (PR) to Date of Objective Disease Progression or Death Due to Any Cause (Estimated up to 18 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Time to Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Date of Complete Response (CR) or Partial Response (Estimated up to 4 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 2: Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Death from Any Cause (Estimated up to 30 Months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Recurrent</condition>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma Recurrent</condition>
  <condition>Glioblastoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (Phase 1b)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Galunisertib in escalating dose cohorts given orally daily or twice a day (BID) for the first 14 days of each 4 week cycle in combination with nivolumab given intravenously (IV) every 2 weeks for 2 cycles.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (NSCLC) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Galunisertib given orally BID for the first 14 days of each 4 week cycle in combination with nivolumab given IV every 2 weeks of each 4 week cycle. Participants may continue to receive study drug until discontinuation criteria are met.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (HCC) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Galunisertib given orally BID for the first 14 days of each 4 week cycle in combination with nivolumab given IV every 2 weeks of each 4 week cycle. Participants may continue to receive study drug until discontinuation criteria are met.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (Glioblastoma) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Galunisertib given orally BID for the first 14 days of each 4 week cycle in combination with nivolumab given IV every 2 weeks of each 4 week cycle. Participants may continue to receive study drug until discontinuation criteria are met.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Galunisertib</intervention_name>
    <description>Administered orally</description>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (Phase 1b)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (NSCLC) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (HCC) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (Glioblastoma) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>LY2157299</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Administered IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (Phase 1b)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (NSCLC) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (HCC) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Galunisertib + Nivolumab (Glioblastoma) (Phase 2)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  For Phase 1b, must have advanced refractory solid tumors in any line of therapy. In
             the Phase 2 if fewer than 3 NSCLC, HCC or glioblastoma participants are not included
             in the Phase 1b, then a safety run-in must occur for any of the cohorts that have
             fewer than 3 participants in Phase 1.

          -  For Phase 2, must have one of the following tumor types: recurrent or refractory
             NSCLC (any histology), HCC with elevated alpha-fetoprotein (AFP) ≥200
             nanogram/milliliter (ng/mL), or glioblastoma (primary).

          -  For Phase 2 only, have had disease progression or be refractory or intolerant to 1
             prior line of therapy (first line therapy) for recurrent or refractory for NSCLC, HCC
             or glioblastoma and have refused currently approved second-line therapy. First line
             therapy is defined as therapy used to treat advanced disease. This may include
             multiple chemotherapeutic, targeted or immunotherapeutic agents with or without
             radiation therapy and/or surgery. Each subsequent line of therapy is preceded by
             disease progression. A switch of an agent within the same drug class (eg, cisplatinum
             to carboplatinum) within a regimen in order to manage toxicity does not define the
             start of a new line of therapy.

          -  For NSCLC:

               -  Prior lines of therapy must include a platinum-based therapy. Investigational
                  agents used in combination with standard therapies are allowed. Participants who
                  received platinum-based neoadjuvant or adjuvant therapy and subsequently
                  received platinum-based therapy as first-line therapy are eligible.

               -  Participants who have completed neo-adjuvant or adjuvant therapy with a platinum
                  doublet and have experienced disease recurrence within 6 months of completing
                  the platinum doublet are eligible.

               -  Tumors with driver mutations (epidermal growth factor receptor mutation positive
                  or anaplastic lymphoma kinase fusion oncogene positive) treated with a tyrosine
                  kinase inhibitor or crizotinib are eligible. For participants who have
                  progressed on a tyrosine kinase inhibitor or crizotinib or are intolerant to
                  this targeted therapy, that participant must receive platinum-based therapy
                  prior to enrollment in this study. Documentation of such mutations must be
                  available and entered into the electronic case report form (eCRF).

               -  Maintenance or switch maintenance therapy after first-line chemotherapy will be
                  considered part of the first-line regimen and is acceptable.

        Participants who completed and progressed on a platinum-containing regimen as adjuvant,
        neoadjuvant, or part of a course of chemoradiation therapy given from locally advanced
        disease and developed recurrent (local or metastatic) disease within the 6 months before
        screening would be counted as having received 1 prior platinum-containing regimen and
        therefore would not require re-treatment with a platinum-containing regimen for Stage
        IIIB, IV, or recurrent disease and are eligible. However, participants must have received
        at least 2 cycles of a platinum doublet based chemotherapy before discontinuation for
        toxicity. If participants received only one cycle of a platinum doublet and discontinue
        due to clear progression, that regimen should be counted as a prior line of therapy.

          -  For HCC:

               -  One prior line of therapy which must include sorafenib or participant must have
                  progressed or been intolerant to sorafenib for participants not eligible for
                  transarterial chemoembolization. Participants who had sorafenib for locally
                  advanced disease or are intolerant to sorafenib are eligible. Participants may
                  have had clinical progression only following sorafenib or local therapy.

               -  Must have Child-Pugh A only. Participants may have any viral status (hepatitis
                  B, hepatitis C, or none).

               -  Have a viral load &lt;100 international units/milliliter (IU/mL).

               -  For hepatitis B participants, must be on a nucleoside analog reverse
                  transcriptase inhibitor (lamivudine, telbivudine, adefovir, tenofovir, or
                  entecavir).

          -  For Glioblastoma (GB): Previous first line of therapy with at least radiotherapy and
             temozolomide except for participants with O6-methylguanine-DNA methyltransferase
             (MGMT) unmethylated newly diagnosed GB. Participants with MGMT unmethylated newly
             diagnosed GB may have received radiation therapy only.

          -  Have adequate organ function.

          -  Have a performance status of 0 or 1 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG)
             scale.

          -  Use an approved contraceptive method.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Have moderate or severe cardiovascular disease:

               -  Have the presence of cardiac disease, including a myocardial infarction within 6
                  months prior to study entry, unstable angina pectoris, New York Heart
                  Association Class III/IV congestive heart failure, or uncontrolled hypertension.

               -  Have documented major electrocardiogram (ECG) abnormalities which are clinically
                  significant at the investigator's discretion (for example, symptomatic or
                  sustained atrial or ventricular arrhythmias, second- or third-degree
                  atrioventricular block, bundle-branch blocks, ventricular hypertrophy, or recent
                  myocardial infarction).

               -  Have major abnormalities documented by Echocardiogram with Doppler (for example,
                  moderate or severe heart valve function defect and/or left ventricular ejection
                  fraction &lt;50%, evaluation based on the institutional lower limit of normal).

               -  Have predisposing conditions that are consistent with development of aneurysms
                  of the ascending aorta or aortic stress (for example, personal history of
                  aneurysm in any location, family history of aneurysms in any location,
                  Marfan-Syndrome, bicuspid aortic valve, evidence of damage to the large vessels
                  of the heart documented by computed tomography [CT] scan/magnetic resonance
                  imaging [MRI] with contrast).

          -  Have evidence of interstitial lung disease that is symptomatic or may interfere with
             the detection or management of suspected drug-related pulmonary toxicity or active,
             noninfectious pneumonitis.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Call 1-877-CTLILLY (1-877-285-4559) or 1-317-615-4559 Mon - Fri 9 AM - 5 PM Eastern time (UTC/GMT - 5 hours, EST)</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>There may be multiple sites in this clinical trial. 1-877-CTLILLY (1-877-285-4559) or</last_name>
    <phone>1-317-615-4559</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>404-272-7222</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mansoor Saleh</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California - San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Jolla</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92037-0845</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>858-534-3804</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sandip Patel</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H Lee Moffitt Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612-9497</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>813-745-2677</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Scott Antonia</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>617-632-2166</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Reardon</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>919-681-4047</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gordana Vlahovic</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>713-563-5844</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Hong</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>For additional information regarding investigative sites for this trial, contact 1-877-CTLILLY (1-877-285-4559, 1-317-615-4559) Mon - Fri from 9 AM to 5 PM Eastern Time (UTC/GMT - 5 hours, EST), or speak with your personal physician.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Eli Lilly and Company</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.lillytrialguide.com/EN/studies/cancer/jbef</url>
    <description>Click here for more information about this study: A Study of Galunisertib (LY2157299) in Combination With Nivolumab in Advanced Refractory Solid Tumors and in Recurrent or Refractory NSCLC, Hepatocellular Carcinoma, or Glioblastoma</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 26, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 17, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
