<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="357">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02117440</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GRU CC-13-24C</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02117440</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Functional Image and Molecular Markers to Predict Treatment Outcomes in Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>GRU CC-13-24C: Using Functional Image and Circulating Molecular Markers to Predict Tumor Response and Lung Toxicity in Treatment of Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Georgia Regents University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Georgia Regents University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to apply functional imaging, Fluorodeoxyglucose_Positron Emission
      Tomography (FDG-PET) and Ventilation/Perfusion Single Photon Emission Computerized
      Tomography (V/Q SPECT), before treatment and then again during treatment to see if it
      predicts how well the treatment works for your cancer and how well your lungs function
      during treatment. A Computerized Tomography (CT) will also be performed along with both of
      these procedures to help the researchers see clearly where your cancer or your healthy lung
      is located. The researchers also perform blood tests in this study to look for markers in
      your blood to see if it helps them determine your risk of developing side effects from
      radiation to the lungs. The researchers hope that this study will help them in the future to
      design radiation treatment plans that provide the best treatment for each individual
      patient.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Lung cancer is the leading cause of cancer deaths in the United States. Although surgery
      provides the best chance of cure, the majority of lung cancers require radiation for
      treatment. The current radiation recommendation, using modern techniques and a uniform dose
      of prescription, generates an overall cure rate of less than 10-15%, and moderate toxicity
      in 10-30% of treated patients. Who can be cured and who will develop side effects? Computed
      tomography (CT) is a useful monitoring tool, but has limited power to predict both tumor
      control and lung toxicity. Using [18F] fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography
      (FDG-PET) and ventilation/perfusion single photon emission computed tomography (V/Q SPECT),
      we have recently shown heterogeneous changes in tumor activity and regional lung function
      during the course of radiation, which may be associated with long-term outcome. Data have
      also shown that radiation up-regulates the expression of cytokines, such as transforming
      growth factor beta 1 (TGFß1) and interleukin-6 (IL-6). We hypothesize that radiation-induced
      functional changes and plasma cytokines are associated with long-term tumor control and
      radiation lung damage. The general strategy of this protocol is to perform functional
      imaging and blood testing during the course of radiation and correlate the results with
      long-term outcomes.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Observational Model: Case-Only, Time Perspective: Prospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Investigate predictive models for long-term tumor control and late treatment lung toxicity by using FDG-PET-CT, V/Q SPECT-CT and blood test during the course of radiation therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 5 years after radiation completion</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Investigate predictive models for long-term tumor control and late treatment lung toxicity by using FDG-PET-CT, V/Q SPECT-CT and blood test during the course of radiation therapy. As secondary analysis, demographic and baseline clinical variables will be added to the model to determine if they add predictive value.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after completing radiation therapy</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Neoplasms</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      buffy coat, plasma and serum samples
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Lung cancer patients
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologically confirmed lung cancer, or clinically diagnosed lung cancer plus
             positive FDG-PET

          -  AJCC Stage I to IV lung cancer requiring radiation therapy (3D conformal or
             stereotactic) with or without chemotherapy, palliative radiation needing dose up to
             36 to 50 Gy, with or without surgery. Stage IV disease is eligible only if the
             patient has a solitary distant metastasis or lung nodules on the other lobes.

          -  Patients with a locoregional tumor recurrence following surgery will be eligible
             provided they meet other eligibility criteria.

          -  Patients must be 18 years of age or older. Female patients with reproductive
             capability must be willing to use effective contraception

          -  Patients must be willing and able to be compliant with all procedures and visits
             required for this protocol (pre-treatment, during RT, and throughout follow up
             period).

          -  Patients must sign an informed consent form for study.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Malignant pleural or pericardial effusion.

          -  Pregnancy

          -  Lactation

          -  Patients with diabetes mellitus, with uncontrolled fasting blood glucose level (above
             200 mg/dl)

          -  Inability to lie flat for the duration of PET-CT and V/Q SPECT-CT (approximately 45
             minutes for each study)

          -  Prisoners are excluded from this study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Feng-Ming Kong, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Georgia Regents University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mary Ann Moores, RN</last_name>
    <phone>706-721-1206</phone>
    <email>mmoores@gru.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Georgia Regents University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Augusta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30912</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mary Ann Moores, RN</last_name>
      <phone>706-721-1206</phone>
      <email>mmoores@gru.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Feng-Ming Kong, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>July 26, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 16, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Georgia Regents University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Feng-Ming Kong</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor and Chair of Department of Radiology Oncology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Neoplasms</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
