<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="250">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02637531</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IPI-549-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02637531</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Dose-Escalation Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics of IPI-549</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1/1b First-In-Human, Dose-Escalation Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics of IPI-549 Monotherapy and in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Subjects With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Infinity Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Infinity Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This dose-escalation study will evaluate the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and
      pharmacodynamics of IPI-549 monotherapy and IPI-549 in combination with pembrolizumab in
      subjects with advanced solid tumors.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study IPI-549-01 is a first-in-human multicenter, open-label, up to five-part Phase 1/1b
      dose-escalation study designed to evaluate safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics (PK), and
      pharmacodynamics (PD) of IPI-549 monotherapy and IPI-549 in combination with pembrolizumab
      in subjects with advanced solid tumors.

      Approximately 150 subjects will receive IPI-549, either as a monotherapy or in combination
      with pembrolizumab. Subjects will receive IPI-549 until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is
      achieved or until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.

      Part A (QD dosing) (and Part B (BID dosing) if necessary) a dose escalation part of the
      study will evaluate the safety and tolerability, PK, and PD of IPI-549 as a single agent in
      subjects with advanced solid tumors. Part A/B will determine the recommended phase 2 dose
      (RP2D) for IPI-549 single agent that is going to be administered in Part D as a single agent
      and Part C in combination with pembrolizumab.

      Part C a dose-escalation part of the study will evaluate the safety and tolerability, PK,
      and PD of IPI-549 when administered in combination with IV pembrolizumab 2 mg/kg every 3
      weeks (Q3wk) in subjects with advanced solid tumors. Part C will determine the RP2D for the
      combination of IPI-549 and pembrolizumab (combination RP2D).

      Part D will evaluate the safety, tolerability, PK, PD, and preliminary clinical activity of
      IPI-549 administered as a single agent in a cohort of subjects with advanced solid tumors.
      Part D, Cycle 2 will also include a pilot food (a high-fat meal) effect evaluation that will
      have 8 subjects out of the entire cohort of subjects participating in the Part D.

      Part E will evaluate the safety, tolerability, PK, PD, and preliminary clinical activity of
      IPI-549 in combination with intravenous (IV) pembrolizumab 2 mg/kg Q3wk in a cohort of
      subjects with non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) and a cohort of subjects with melanoma. One
      or more cohorts of subjects with additional tumor types may be enrolled if supported by data
      generated in dose escalation or earlier expansion cohorts. To be eligible for enrollment in
      Part E, subjects must have received an anti-PD1/PD-L1 as their most recent treatment prior
      to study entry. The dose level to be administered in Part E will be the combination RP2D as
      determined in Part C.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A/B/C: Dose Limiting Toxicities (DLT)</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of initial dose until up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part D/E: Adverse Events (AE) and safety laboratory values</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of patients with Clinically significant abnormal laboratory values and adverse events that are related to treatment from date of initial dose until 30 days after last dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A/B: Adverse Events (AE) and safety laboratory values</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of patients with Clinically significant abnormal laboratory values and adverse events that are related to treatment assessed during every visit for duration of study participation which is estimated to be 24 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A/B: Plasma concentrations of IPI-549 (metabolites, as appropriate)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during Days 1- 22 of Cycles 1 and 2, Assessed During Day 1 of Cycles 3 and 4</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A/B: Overall response rate (ORR), complete response/remission (CR) or partial response/remission (PR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A/B: Duration of response (DoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C: Adverse Events (AE) and safety laboratory values</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of patients with Clinically significant abnormal laboratory values and adverse events that are related to treatment assessed during every visit for duration of study participation which is estimated to be 24 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C: Plasma concentrations of IPI-549 (metabolites as appropriate)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during Days 1- 2 of Cycles 1 and 2</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C: Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C: Duration of Response (DoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part D: Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part D: Duration of Response (DoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part D: Progression-Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part D: Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Estimated to be 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part D: Plasma concentrations of IPI-549 (and metabolites, as appropriate)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during Days 1- 15 of Cycles 1 and 2, Assessed During Day 1 of Cycles 3 and 4</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part E:Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part E: Duration of Response (DoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part E: Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Responses Assessed in Cycle 3 and every odd cycle through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part E: Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Estimated to be 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part E: Plasma concentrations of IPI-549 (and metabolites, as appropriate)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during Days 1- 2 of Cycles 1 and 2</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Tumors (Part A/B/C/D)</condition>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) and Melanoma (Part E)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part A/B: IPI-549 Dose Escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive IPI-549 orally (PO) once a day (QD) for Part A and twice a day (BID) in Part B until disease progression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part C: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive IPI-549 (dose determined from Part A/B) orally in combination with pembrolizumab IV infusion (2 mg/kg) every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part D: IPI-549 Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive IPI-549 (dose determined from Part A/B) orally until disease progression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part D Annex: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive IPI-549 (dose determined from Part A/B/C) orally in combination with pembrolizumab IV infusion (2 mg/kg) every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part E: NSCLC: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with NSCLC receive IPI-549 (dose determined from Part A/B/C) orally in combination with pembrolizumab IV infusion (2 mg/kg) every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part E: Melanoma: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with melanoma receive IPI-549 (dose determined from Part A/B/C) orally in combination with pembrolizumab IV infusion (2 mg/kg) every 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IPI-549</intervention_name>
    <description>IPI-549 daily dose administered orally in 28-day cycles (Part A/B/D) and 21-day cycles (Part C/E).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part A/B: IPI-549 Dose Escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part C: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part D: IPI-549 Monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part D Annex: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part E: NSCLC: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part E: Melanoma: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Pembrolizumab (2 mg/kg, Q3wk) administered intravenously (IV) in 21-day cycles (Part C/D-Annex/E).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part C: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part D Annex: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part E: NSCLC: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part E: Melanoma: IPI-549 and pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>KEYTRUDA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        All subjects must meet the following criteria for inclusion:

          -  ≥ 18 years of age

          -  Life expectancy of ≥ 3 months

          -  Histological or cytological evidence of advanced and/or metastatic carcinoma or
             melanoma

          -  At least 1 measurable disease lesion as defined by RECIST 1.1

          -  Estimated creatinine clearance ≥60mL/min and Serum creatinine ≤ 2.0 x the upper limit
             of normal (ULN)

          -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (unless elevated due to Gilbert's syndrome)

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST/SGOT) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT/SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x
             ULN (&lt;5x ULN if liver metastasis)

          -  Adequate hematological function, defined as absolute neutrophil count ≥1.5 x 109/L,
             hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL, and platelet count ≥ 100 x 109/L

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤ 2 (corresponds to
             Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) ≥ 60%)

        Subjects entering Part A, B, C, or D must also meet the following additional criterion:

        • Failure to respond to standard therapy, or for whom no appropriate therapies are
        available (based on the judgement of the Investigator)

        Subjects entering Part D or E must also meet the following additional criterion:

        • Willing to undergo 1 pre-treatment and 1 on-treatment tumor biopsy

        Subjects entering Part E must also meet the following additional criteria:

          -  Histological or cytological evidence of NSCLC, or melanoma, or another tumor type to
             be determined

          -  Failure to respond to standard therapy, or for whom no appropriate therapies are
             available (based on the judgment of the Investigator The most recent treatment prior
             to study entry must be an anti-PD-1 or anti-PD-L1 antibody given as either
             monotherapy or in combination

        Subjects with NSCLC: must have received at least one line of therapy. Subjects whose
        tumors harbor an exon 19 deletion or exon 21 L858R EGFR mutation must have progressed on
        or had intolerance to an Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) tyrosine kinase inhibitor
        (e.g., erlotinib, afatinib or gefitinib). Subjects whose tumors harbor an anaplastic
        lymphoma kinase (ALK) translocation must have progressed on or had intolerance to
        crizotinib.

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Subjects are to be excluded from the study if they meet any of the following criteria:

          -  Severe allergic or anaphylactic reaction to any monoclonal antibody therapy, murine
             protein, or known hypersensitivity to any excipient in the study drugs

          -  Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to Screening

          -  Subjects who have been treated with chemotherapy, biologic therapy, or other
             investigational agent within &lt; 5 times the half-life of the agent or &lt; 28 days
             (whichever is shorter) of starting study drug

        NOTE: Subjects whose immediate prior treatment was with pembrolizumab may start study drug
        3 weeks after the last dose of pembrolizumab

          -  Symptomatic or untreated brain metastases

          -  Primary central nervous system (CNS) malignancy

          -  Infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B, or hepatitis C virus

          -  Ongoing treatment with chronic immunosuppressants (eg, cyclosporine) or systemic
             steroids

          -  Ongoing systemic bacterial, fungal, or viral infections at Screening

        NOTE: Subjects on antimicrobial, antifungal, or antiviral prophylaxis are not specifically
        excluded if all other inclusion/exclusion criteria are met

          -  Administration of a live vaccine within 6 weeks of first dose of study drug

          -  Administration of any of the following within 1 week prior to the administration of
             study drug:

               -  Strong inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4, including grapefruit products and
                  herbal supplements

               -  P-glycoprotein (P-gp) inhibitors

               -  Warfarin, phenytoin, or other substrates of CYP2C8 or CYP2C9 with a narrow
                  therapeutic range

               -  Medications associated with QTc interval prolongation or Torsades de Pointes

          -  Baseline QT interval corrected with Fridericia's method (QTcF) &gt; 480 ms (average of
             triplicate readings) NOTE: criterion does not apply to subjects with a right or left
             bundle branch block

          -  Prior surgery or gastrointestinal dysfunction that may affect drug absorption (eg,
             gastric bypass surgery, gastrectomy)

          -  Concurrent active malignancy other than non-melanoma skin cancer, carcinoma in situ
             of the cervix, or prostate intraepithelial neoplasia

          -  Past medical history of interstitial lung disease, drug-induced interstitial lung
             disease, radiation pneumonitis which required steroid treatment, or any evidence of
             clinically active interstitial lung disease

          -  History of peptic ulcer and/or gastrointestinal bleed

          -  History of stroke, unstable angina, myocardial infarction, or ventricular arrhythmia
             requiring medication or mechanical control within the last 6 months prior to
             Screening

          -  Unstable or severe uncontrolled medical condition (eg, unstable cardiac function,
             unstable pulmonary condition including pneumonitis and/or interstitial lung disease,
             uncontrolled diabetes) or any important medical illness or abnormal laboratory
             finding that would, in the Investigator's judgment, increase the risk to the subject
             associated with his or her participation in the study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joseph Pearlberg, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Infinity Pharmaceutical, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elizabeth Hnitecki</last_name>
    <phone>617-453-1000</phone>
    <email>IPI-549-01@infi.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 20, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 16, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>IPI-549</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced Solid Tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Melanoma</keyword>
  <keyword>PI3K</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
