<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="549">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01588821</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12-091</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01588821</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cabozantinib in Advanced Solid Malignancies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Cabozantinib (XL184) in Patients With Advanced Solid (Non-breast, Non-prostate) Malignancies and Bony Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study is a Phase II clinical trial. Phase II clinical trials test the
      effectiveness of an investigational drug to learn whether the drug works in treating a
      specific cancer. &quot;Investigational&quot; means that the drug is still being studied and that
      research doctors are trying to find out more about it-such as the safest dose to use, the
      side effects it may cause, and if the drug is effective for treating different types of
      cancer. It also means that the FDA has not approved the drug for this type of cancer, or for
      any use outside of research studies.

      When cancer spreads from the primary tumor, one of the most commons sites it spreads to is
      bone. When cancer spreads to bone there can be significant symptoms such as pain.

      Cabozantinib works by blocking signaling that leads to cancer growth as well as blocking the
      growth of new blood vessels (angiogenesis) that help to feed a tumor. Cabozantinib has been
      studied or is being studied in research studies as a possible treatment for various types of
      cancer, including prostate cancer, brain cancer, thyroid cancer, lung cancer and kidney
      cancer.

      Previous clinical research studies indicate that cabozantinib may also have activity against
      cancer once it has spread to the bones.

      The purpose of this study is to find out if cabozantinib is effective in treating cancer
      that has spread to the bone.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cabozantinib is a tablet that the subject will take by mouth. The subject will take it once
      per day. The study treatment with cabozantinib will be divided into 28 day cycles. A member
      of the study staff will give the subject a drug diary and explain to the subject how to use
      it to record doses of cabozantinib. This diary will also contain specific instructions about
      how the subject take cabozantinib.

      Every 28 days the subject will undergo the following procedures: Physical examination,
      questions about any side effects the subject may have, blood samples for routine laboratory
      tests and research tests, urine sample, electrocardiogram (EKG), and questionnaires to
      measure quality of life and level of pain. Every two months the subject will undergo a CT
      scan or MRI to evaluate the subjects disease.

      The investigators would like the subject to return to the study clinic for follow-up
      procedures about 4-5 weeks after the last dose of cabozantinib.

      The subject can continue to receive the study drug for as long as their disease does not
      worsen and the subject do not experience unacceptable side effects.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2012</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of Cabozantinib on Bone Biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Effect of cabozantinib on bone biomarkers of osteoblast and osteoclast acitivity (urinary NTx, serum NTx, serum CTx, among others)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of skeletal-related event (SRE)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Rate of SRE in patients treated with cabozantinib (SRE defined as pathologic fracture, cord compression, radiation or surgery to bone, hypercalcemia)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Quality of life as measured by pain and analgesic scores and the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - General (FACT-G)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Tumor Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overall tumor response rate by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) if patient has RECIST evaluable disase</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MET amplification in tumor sample</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Response will be correlated with specific tumor genotype (MET amplification).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response to Cabozantinib in Bone Metastatic Disease</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Response to cabozantinib in bone metastatic disease as measured by bone scan or PET-CT scan</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to SRE</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time to SRE in patients treated with cabozantinib (SRE defined as pathologic fracture, cord compression, radiation or surgery to bone, hypercalcemia)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">29</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Solid Tumor (Not Breast or Prostate Cancers)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cabozantinib</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cabozantinib</intervention_name>
    <description>60 mg daily by mouth</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>XL184</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologic or cytologic diagnosis of a solid tumor (not breast or prostate) that is
             metastatic and refractory to or progressed following standard therapies

          -  Has bony metastases

          -  Agree to use medically accepted methods of contraception

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding

          -  Received cytotoxic chemotherapy (including investigational cytotoxic chemotherapy) or
             biologic agents within 3 weeks of study entry(6 weeks for nitrosoureas/mitomycin C)

          -  Received radiation to the thoracic cavity/GI tract (within 3 months of study entry),
             to bone or brain metastasis (within 14 days) or to any other site within 28 days

          -  Received prior treatment with small molecule kinase inhibitor or hormonal therapy
             within 14 days/5 half-lives

          -  Received therapy with another investigational agent within past 28 days

          -  Has not recovered from toxicities due to prior therapies

          -  Primary brain tumor

          -  Active brain metastases or epidural disease

          -  Uncontrolled significant intercurrent or recent illness

          -  Allergy or hypersensitivity to components of the study treatment formulation
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rebecca Heist, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MGH</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rebecca Heist, MD</last_name>
    <phone>617-724-4000</phone>
    <email>rheist@partners.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rebecca Heist, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rebecca Heist, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 28, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 26, 2012</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rebecca Suk Heist, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Metastatic</keyword>
  <keyword>Refractory</keyword>
  <keyword>Relapsed</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
