<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="89">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02393209</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MLN1117-1501</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2014-004281-25</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1160-1736</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02393209</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Docetaxel With or Without MLN1117 in Participants With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b/Adaptive Phase 2 Study of Docetaxel With or Without MLN1117 in Patients With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>Canada: Health Canada</authority>
    <authority>Italy: The Italian Medicines Agency</authority>
    <authority>Netherlands: The Central Committee on Research Involving Human Subjects (CCMO)</authority>
    <authority>United Kingdom: Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency</authority>
    <authority>Spain: Spanish Agency of Medicines and Health Products</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of MLN1117
      when administered in combination with docetaxel in patients with non-small cell lung cancer
      (NSCLC) and to evaluate efficacy, safety, and tolerability of MLN1117 administered alone and
      in combination with docetaxel at the RP2D in patients with locally advanced or metastatic
      non-small cell lung cancer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The drug being evaluated in this study is called MLN1117. MLN1117 is tested in combination
      with docetaxel versus docetaxel alone for the treatment of non-small cell lung cancer
      (NSCLC).

      This study consists of 2 phases:

        -  Phase 1b - dose escalation phase

        -  Phase 2 - expansion phase.

      Approximately 15 patients with NSCLC who have been treated with multiple prior lines of
      therapies will be enrolled for Phase 1b. The participants will receive docetaxel (36 mg/m2)
      intravenous (IV) and MLN1117 tablets, orally administered, once daily in 21-day dosing
      cycles. The MLN117 dose will be escalated until recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) is
      determined.

      Up to 140 adults with locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC refractory or resistant to 1
      prior line platinum-based, non-docetaxel containing systemic chemotherapy or have previously
      failed 1 second line therapy with an immune-checkpoint inhibitor will be enrolled for Phase
      2 (dose expansion). Phase 2 expansion study uses a sequential, multistage Bayesian adaptive
      design and will consist of up to 3 parts evaluating the following patient populations:

        -  Part 1: NSCLC (inclusive of both squamous and nonsquamous histology and all PIK3CA
           genotypes)

        -  Part 2: Histology-specific NSCLC (either squamous or nonsquamous)

        -  Part 3: Histology- and genotype-specific NSCLC (PIK3CA MUT/AMP positive squamous NSCLC
           if squamous histology is selected in Part 2)

      Each part of the adaptive Phase 2 portion of the study is designed as a stand-alone,
      randomized study evaluating PFS as the primary efficacy measure in a total of 60 patients
      between the 2 treatment arms: MLN1117 plus docetaxel versus docetaxel alone. An event-driven
      analysis of PFS will be performed after each part of Phase 2. On the basis of the PFS
      analysis of the preceding part of the study, the study may be stopped for efficacy or
      futility, or proceed to the next part.

      Study drug will be administered in 21-day dosing cycles. During each phase of the study,
      patients will be treated with a maximum of 9 cycles of either docetaxel alone or docetaxel
      plus MLN1117. Subsequently, pPatients treated with docetaxel plus MLN1117 may continue to
      receive MLN1117 monotherapy until progression of disease, occurrence of unacceptable
      toxicities or death.

      The maximum duration of treatment for patients will be 12 months unless it is determined
      that a patient would derive benefit from continued treatment beyond 12 months. Patients will
      continue to be followed after discontinuation of study drug to collect PFS and OS data.
      Patients may withdraw from therapy at any time.

      This multicenter trial will be conducted in North America and in Europe. The overall time to
      participate in this study is up to 24 months.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants experiencing Dose-Limiting Toxicities (DLT) in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 9 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Toxicity will be evaluated according to the NCI CTCAE version 4.03. DLT will be defined as any of the events specified in the protocol that are considered by the investigator to be at least possibly related to therapy with MLN1117 plus docetaxel.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 9 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The MTD is defined as the highest dose level of MLN1117 when administered with weekly docetaxel at which no more than 1 of the 6 patients experiences a DLT during the first cycle (21 days) of therapy in Phase 1b.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recommended Phase 2 Dose in Phase 1b (RP2D)</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 9 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The RP2D of MLN1117 plus docetaxel will be determined in Phase 1b based on safety, tolerability, PK and other observations in both Cycle 1 and Cycle 2 and beyond. The RP2D will not exceed the MTD.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free Survival (PFS) in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 6 months after last dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Progression-free survival is defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of first documentation of progression of disease (PD) or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Vital sign measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days from the last dose date</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Clinically significant change from baseline in vital sign measures will be assessed. Vital sign measurements will include measurements of diastolic and systolic blood pressure, heart rate, and temperature.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in physical examination findings</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days from the last dose date</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>The percentage of participants with clinically significant changes from baseline will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) findings</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to end of treatment visit</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Clinically significant changes from baseline in ECGs will be tabulated by time point including any unscheduled measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in clinical laboratory test results</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days from the last dose date</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Shift tables summarizing the number of patients with each baseline NCI CTCAE grade and changes to the worst NCI CTCAE grade will be produced for selected laboratory parameters.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From signing of informed consent up to 30 days after last dose date</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Treatment-emergent AEs that occur after administration of the first dose of study drug and through 30 days after the last dose of study drug will be tabulated.
An Adverse Event (AE) is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical investigation participant administered a drug; it does not necessarily have to have a causal relationship with this treatment. An AE can therefore be any unfavorable and unintended sign (eg, a clinically significant abnormal laboratory finding), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a drug, whether or not it is considered related to the drug.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants experiecing serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From signing of informed consent up to 30 days after last dose date</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>A serious adverse event (SAE) is any untoward medical occurrence or effect that at any dose results in death, is life-threatening, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability / incapacity, is a congenital anomaly / birth defect or is medically important due to other reasons than the above mentioned criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately 12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Response rate was defined as complete response + partial response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>: From at the end of the Cycle 2 , 4, and 6, and then every 3 cycles thereafter until the patient discontinues study drug due to disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, or death (approximately 12 months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Disease control rate is defined as complete response [CR] + partial response [PR] +stable disease [SD]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of first documented response up to the first documentation of progression of disease (approximately 12 months)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The duration of response is defined as the time from the date of first documentation of a response to the date of first documentation of progression of disease.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Progression</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of randomization to the date of first documentation of progressive disease (approximately 24 months).</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time to progression is defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of first documentation of progression of disease.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS) in Phase 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 3 months from the last dose of the study drug for up to one year following last dose of study drug.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overall survival is defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax: Single dose maximum (peak) plasma concentration in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 pre-dose and up to 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Maximum observed plasma concentration (Cmax) is the peak plasma concentration of a drug after administration, obtained directly from the plasma concentration-time curve.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tmax: single-dose first time of occurrence of maximum (peak) concentration in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 pre-dose and up to 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Tmax is defined as time to reach the maximum plasma concentration (Cmax).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUCtau: Area under the concentration time curve from time 0 to the next dose ) in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 pre-dose and up to 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>AUCtau is defined as area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from zero to next dose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC(last): Area Under the Plasma Concentration-Time Curve From Time 0 to the Time of the Last Quantifiable Concentration in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 pre-dose and up to 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>AUC(last) is defined as area under the plasma concentration versus time curve from zero to the time of the last quantifiable concentration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CL/F: Apparent total body clearance in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 pre-dose and up to 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>CL/F is apparent clearance of the drug after extravascular administration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>T1/2: Terminal disposition half-life in Phase 1b</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 Day 1 pre-dose and up to 24 hours post-dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>T1/2 is the time required for half of the drug to be eliminated from the plasma.to be eliminated from the plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MLN1117 plasma concentrations when administered 1 day after docetaxel</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day post docetaxel dose</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The plasma concentration of MLN1117 is evaluated 1 day following docetaxel dosing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">155</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1b: MLN1117 + Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>During a 21-day cycle of treatment, docetaxel (36 mg/m2) intravenously (IV) will be administered on Days 1 and 8, and MLN1117 tablets (planned doses of 300, 600, and 900 mg) will be administered orally (PO) on a 3 days per week schedule (for example: Days 2, 3, 4, 9, 10, 11, 16, 17, and 18). If the MLN1117 maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) is not achieved by 900 mg, higher MLN1117 dose levels at 300 mg increments may be evaluated. Additionally, the daily MLN1117 daily dose may be reduced, or the number of treatment days per week may be reduced, based on observed safety and tolerability data.
If frequent docetaxel dose modifications are necessary when administered in combination with MLN1117, the fixed dose of docetaxel may be decreased (eg, -1 dose level) based on discussion and agreement between investigators and the Millennium project clinician.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2 ,Arm A- MLN1117 + Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Docetaxel 36 mg/m^2 IV on Days 1 and 8 of a 21-day cycle plus MLN1117 tablets (at the dose determined in the dose escalation phase) on Days 2, 3, 4, 9, 10, 11, 16, 17, and 18 of a 21-day cycle (An alternative combination dosing regimen may be used based on the RP2D decision in Phase 1b)..</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2, Arm B- Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Docetaxel 75mg/m^2 IV once every 3 weeks (per approved prescribing information) with dosing on Day 1 of each 21-day cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Docetaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>Docetaxel IV.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1b: MLN1117 + Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2 ,Arm A- MLN1117 + Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2, Arm B- Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MLN1117</intervention_name>
    <description>MLN1117 orally.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 1b: MLN1117 + Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase 2 ,Arm A- MLN1117 + Docetaxel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria

          -  Has a histologically and/or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of NSCLC (squamous or
             nonsquamous).

             - For Phase 2 of the study:, has a diagnosis of mixed squamous and nonsquamous (or
             adenosquamous) NSLC.

          -  Has locally advanced or metastatic disease (Stage IIIb or Stage IV) with
             radiographically or clinically evaluable lesions.

          -  Has experienced failure of at least 1 prior chemotherapy regimen:

               -  For Phase 2 of the study:

               -  Participants must have received 1 prior platinum-based chemotherapy regimen
                  (excluding a docetaxel-containing regimen) for advanced or metastatic (Stage
                  IIIb or Stage IV) disease followed by documented PD.

               -  A drug provided as maintenance therapy following cytotoxic chemotherapy will be
                  considered to be part of that regimen.

               -  Participants who received prior therapy with paclitaxel as a part of the
                  platinum-based doublet front-line regimen without PD on therapy.

               -  Participants who, after the front-line, platinum-based, non-docetaxelcontaining
                  chemotherapy, have been treated with 1 line of nivolumab or other
                  immune-checkpoint inhibitors but progressed on or after the therapy.

               -  For Phase 1b of the study: Participants who have experienced failure of multiple
                  lines of prior chemotherapy are eligible.

               -  For Phase 2, has archived or fresh tumor biopsy samples (obtained during
                  screening) sufficient for genotyping.

          -  Has adequate organ function, before the first dose of study drug.

          -  Has Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 or 1.

          -  Female participants who are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening
             visit or are surgically sterile, or are of childbearing potential, agree to practice
             1 highly effective method and 1 additional effective (barrier) method of
             contraception, at the same time, from the time of signing the informed consent
             through 30 days (or longer, as mandated by local labeling) after the last dose of
             study drug, or agree to practice true abstinence.

          -  Female participants must agree to not donate eggs (ova) during the course of this
             study and for 30 days after receiving their last dose of MLN1117 and, for docetaxel,
             for as long as is mandated by local labeling.

          -  Male participants agree to practice highly effective barrier contraception during the
             entire study treatment period and through 120 days after the last dose of MLN1117
             and, for docetaxel, for as long as is mandated by local labeling, or agree to
             practice true abstinence.

          -  Male participants must agree to not donate sperm during the course of the study and
             for 120 days after receiving their last dose of MLN1117 and, for docetaxel, for as
             long as is mandated by local labeling.

          -  Has suitable venous access for the study-required blood sampling.

          -  Has recovered (ie, &lt;= Grade 1 toxicity or eligibility per this protocol is met) from
             the reversible effects of prior anticancer therapy.

          -  In the opinion of the investigator, the patient or legal guardian is capable of
             understanding and complying with protocol requirements for the duration of the study.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Previous treatment with a PI3K or AKT inhibitor.

          -  Prior cancer therapy or other investigational therapy within 2 weeks before the first
             administration of study drug or failed to recover from the reversible effects of
             prior anticancer therapies. For prior therapies with a half-life longer than 3 days,
             the interval must be at least 28 days before the first administration of study drug,
             and the patient must have documented progressive disease.

          -  Has poorly controlled diabetes mellitus defined as HbA1c &gt; 6.5%.

          -  Has taken strong inhibitors or strong inducers of CYP3A4 within 14 days before the
             first dose of study drug.

          -  Has taken histamine-H2 receptor antagonists and/or neutralizing antacids within 24
             hours before the first administration of study drug.

          -  Has taken proton pump inhibitors within 7 days before the first administration of
             study drug.

          -  Has a condition that requires the concomitant use of any of the protocol-excluded
             medications, supplements, or food products during the course of the study .

          -  Has any clinically significant co-morbidities.

          -  Has acute myocardial infarction within 6 months before starting study drug, current
             or history of New York Heart Association Class III or IV heart failure; evidence of
             current uncontrolled cardiovascular conditions including cardiac arrhythmias, angina,
             pulmonary hypertension, or ECG evidence of acute ischemia or active conduction system
             abnormalities; Fridericia's corrected QT interval &gt; 475 milliseconds (msec) (males)
             or &gt; 450 msec (females) on a 12-lead ECG during the Screening period;, or
             abnormalities on 12-lead ECG including, but not limited to, changes in rhythm and
             intervals that in the opinion of the investigator are considered to be clinically
             significant.

          -  Has known, previously diagnosed human immunodeficiency virus infection or active
             chronic hepatitis B or C.

          -  Has brain metastasis, unless has completed definitive therapy, is not on steroids,
             has a stable neurologic status for at least 2 weeks after completion of the
             definitive therapy and steroids, and does not have neurologic dysfunction that would
             confound the evaluation of neurologic and other adverse events.

          -  Has active secondary malignancy that requires treatment.

          -  Has any serious medical or psychiatric illness, including drug or alcohol abuse.

          -  Male participants who intend to donate sperm during the course of this study or 120
             days after receiving their last dose of MLN1117 and, for docetaxel, for as long as is
             mandated by local labeling.

          -  Female participants who are lactating and breastfeeding or have a positive serum
             pregnancy test during the Screening period or a positive urine pregnancy test on Day
             1 before administration of the first dose of study drug.

          -  Is unwilling or unable to abide by the requirements of the study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director Clinical Science</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Study Registration Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>+1-877-825-3327</phone>
    <email>medicalinformation@tpna.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Farmington Hills</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Chattanooga</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Hoofddorp</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Maastricht</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 12, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 15, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug therapy</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Motilin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
