<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="538">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02414269</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15-007</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02414269</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Malignant Pleural Disease Treated With Autologous T Cells Genetically Engineered to Target the Cancer-Cell Surface Antigen Mesothelin</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Clinical Trial of Malignant Pleural Disease Treated With Autologous T Cells Genetically Engineered to Target the Cancer-Cell Surface Antigen Mesothelin</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this Phase I study is to test the safety of different doses of specially
      prepared immune cells (called &quot;T cells&quot;) collected from blood. The Investigators want to
      find a safe dose of these modified T cells for patients who have malignant pleural disease.
      They want to find out what effects these T cells have on the patient and the cancer (MPD).
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, dose-escalating, non randomized, single-center, phase I study of
      mesothelin-targeted T cells administered intrapleurally as a single infusion in patients
      with a diagnosis (histologically or cytologically documented) of MPD from mesothelioma, lung
      cancer, or breast cancer. The total number of patients studied will depend on the number of
      dose levels tested, up to a maximum dose of 3×10^6 mesothelin-targeted T cells/kg or until
      the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is reached.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2015</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite measure of severity and number of adverse events (AEs); changes in clinical laboratory test findings (hematologic and chemistry); and physical examination.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>All AEs and laboratory toxicities will be graded using version 4 of the CTCAE.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in serum levels of the biomarker soluble mesothelin related peptide (SMRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days (+/-5 days) after treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Mesothelin is an immunogenic cell surface antigen, that is expressed at high levels in MPD and mesothelioma pleural fluid will be drained from the chest by thoracentesis or through a pleural catheter and will be preserved for analysis .</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Pleural Disease</condition>
  <condition>Mesothelioma</condition>
  <condition>Metastases</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>modified T cells alone (without chemotherapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Following enrollment, leukapheresis product will be obtained in the blood donor facility at MSKCC and cryopreserved in the CTCEF. Before protocol treatment, leukapheresis product will be thawed, and T cell isolation, transduction, and expansion of iCasp928z T cells will be performed in the MSKCC Cell Therapy and Cell Engineering Facility. It is estimated that it will take approximately 3 to 6 weeks to generate T cells for treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>modified T cells with cyclophosphamide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive cyclophosphamide intravenously (at 1.5 g/m^2) , 2 - 7 (Day (-7) -(-2) days before T cell infusion. On Day 1 , patients will be admitted to the MSKCC Thoracic Surgery Inpatient Service (if not already inpatients) for intravenous hydration, clinical monitoring, and blood work for immune monitoring. Standard MSKCC antiemetic therapy will be administered prior to chemotherapy to prevent nausea/vomiting. Administration of corticosteroids will be avoided as steroids may impede the efficacy of CAR T cells.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>iCasp9M28z T cell infusions</intervention_name>
    <description>On day 0 patients will be treated with genetically modified T cells. Thirty to 60 minutes before T cell infusion, patients will be given 650 mg of acetaminophen orally and 50 mg of diphenhydramine orally or intravenously, to prevent infusion-related reactions. The genetically modified T cells will be infused for at least 15 minutes and no more than 2 hours through the indwelling pleural catheter depending on the volume of the T cells. A physician will be available during the infusion. Please note, during formulation of iCasp9M28z T cells, under or over estimation of CAR modified T-Cells may occur. Patient may receive an altered fractionation of the total dose or up to 35% over or under total cell dose with approval of PI.</description>
    <arm_group_label>modified T cells alone (without chemotherapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>modified T cells with cyclophosphamide</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cyclophosphamide</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive cyclophosphamide intravenously (at 1.5 g/m^2)</description>
    <arm_group_label>modified T cells with cyclophosphamide</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with MPD aged ≥18 years

          -  Karnofsky performance status ≥70%

          -  Patients with malignant pleural disease (MPD), pathologically confirmed at MSKCC, and
             defined as one of the following:

               1. Malignant pleural mesothelioma - previously treated with at least one prior
                  treatment regimen.

               2. Non-small cell lung cancer metastatic to the pleura—previously treated with at
                  least one prior treatment regimen (chemotherapy or targeted agent) and
                  documented progression of disease. Patients with disease outside of the pleura
                  will be discussed among study PI and Co-PIs prior to considered eligible for the
                  study. Disease outside of the pleura must not require any immediate therapy.

               3. Breast cancer metastatic to the pleura— previously treated with at least one
                  prior treatment regimen (chemotherapy or targeted agent) and documented
                  progression of disease. Patients with disease outside of the pleura will be
                  discussed among study PI and Co-PIs prior to considered eligible for the study.
                  Disease outside of the pleura must not require any immediate therapy.

          -  Expression of mesothelin must be confirmed by meeting one of the following criteria.

               1. Mesothelin expression (&gt;10% of the tumor expressing mesothelin) by
                  immunohistochemical (IHC) analysis

               2. Elevated serum SMRP levels (&gt;0.4 nM/L). Patients must have a free flowing
                  pleural effusion requiring management by placement of a pleural catheter.
                  Patients with a functional pleural catheter already in place are eligible for
                  the study, as long as there are no clinical concerns of infection.

          -  Chemotherapy, targeted therapy (such as a tyrosine kinase inhibitor) or radiotherapy
             must have been completed at least 28 days prior to administration of T-cells.
             Continuation of hormonal therapy (ie for breast cancer) is acceptable. Prior
             immunotherapy with checkpoint blockade (i.e. PD1 inhibitor, PDL1 inhibitor or
             CTL4-antagonist or similar agent) must have been completed more than 6 months prior
             to the T cell infusion.

          -  Any major thoracic (thoracotomy with lung or esophageal resection) or abdominal
             (laparotomy with organ resection) operation must have occurred at least 28 days
             before study enrollment. Patients who have undergone diagnostic VATS or laparoscopy
             can be included in the study.

          -  All acute toxic effects of any previous radiotherapy, chemotherapy, or surgical
             procedures must have resolved to grade I or lower according to CTCAE (version 4.0).

          -  Lab requirements (hematology)

          -  White blood cell (WBC) count ≥3000 cells/mm3

          -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥1500 neutrophils/mm3

          -  Platelet count ≥100,000 platelets/mm3 Lab requirements (serum chemistry)

          -  Bilirubin &lt;1.5x upper limit of normal (ULN)

          -  Serum alanine aminotransferase/serum aspartate aminotransferase (ALT/AST) &lt;2.5x ULN

          -  Serum creatinine &lt;1.5x ULN or Cr &gt; 1.5x ULN, but calculated clearances of &gt;60

          -  Negative screen for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B virus (HBV)
             antigen, and hepatitis C virus (HCV). If testing was performed during the previous 3
             months, there is no need to repeat testing, as long as documentation of results is
             provided to the study site. Subjects must receive counseling and sign a separate
             informed consent form for HIV testing.

          -  Subjects and their partners with reproductive potential must agree to use an
             effective form of contraception during the period of drug administration and for 4
             weeks after completion of the last administration of the study drug. An effective
             form of contraception is defined as oral contraceptives plus 1 form of barrier or
             double-barrier method contraception (condom with spermicide or condom with
             diaphragm).

          -  Subjects must be able to understand the potential risks and benefits of the study and
             must be able to read and provide written, informed consent for the study

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Any prior history of brain metastases

          -  Non-small cell lung cancer metastatic to the pleura that extends outside of the
             pleura requiring immediate therapy

          -  Breast cancer metastatic to the pleura that extends outside of the pleura requiring
             immediate therapy

          -  Prior history of seizure disorder

          -  Patients currently receiving treatment for concurrent active malignancy

          -  Autoimmune or antibody-mediated disease, including but not limited to systemic lupus
             erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, ulcerative colitis, Crohn's disease, and
             temporal arteritis (Patients with a history of hypothyroidism will not be excluded)

          -  Clinically significant cardiac disease (New York Heart Association class III/IV) or
             severe debilitating pulmonary disease

          -  Pregnant or lactating women

          -  An infection requiring antibiotic treatment within 7 days before the start of
             treatment (day 0)

          -  A requirement for daily systemic corticosteroids for any reason or a requirement for
             other immunosuppressive or immunomodulatory agents. Topical, nasal, and inhaled
             steroids are permitted.

          -  Administration of live, attenuated vaccine within 8 weeks before the start of
             treatment (day 0) and throughout the study

          -  Any other medical condition that, in the opinion of the PI, may interfere with a
             subject's participation in or compliance with the study

          -  Participation in a therapeutic research study or receipt of an investigational drug
             within 30 days before the screening visit
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Prasad Adusumilli, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Prasad Adusumilli, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-639-8093</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Prasad Adusumilli, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-639-8093</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mskcc.org/</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 7, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 2, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>modified T cells</keyword>
  <keyword>cyclophosphamide</keyword>
  <keyword>CAR T cells</keyword>
  <keyword>15-007</keyword>
  <keyword>CAR</keyword>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pleural Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Cyclophosphamide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
