<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="71">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02520778</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2015-01270</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2015-01270</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>9903</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>9903</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA006516</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1CA186709</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02520778</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EGFR Inhibitor AZD9291 and Navitoclax in Treating Patients With EGFR-Positive Previously Treated Advanced or Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1B Study of AZD9291 in Combination With Navitoclax in EGFR-Mutant Non-small Cell Lung Cancer Following Resistance to Initial EGFR Kinase Inhibitor</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase Ib trial studies the side effects and best dose of epidermal growth factor
      receptor (EGFR) inhibitor AZD9291 and navitoclax when given together and to see how well
      they work in treating patients with previously treated EGFR-positive non-small cell lung
      cancer that has spread to other places in the body or has not responded to previous
      treatment with initial EGFR kinase inhibitor. EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 and navitoclax may stop
      the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Giving
      with EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 together with navitoclax may work better in treating
      EGFR-positive non-small cell lung cancer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To determine the safety and tolerability of AZD9291 (EGFR inhibitor AZD9291) in
      combination with navitoclax in patients with EGFR-mutant non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)
      following resistance to prior EGFR-tyrosine kinase inhibitor (EGFR TKI).

      II. To evaluate the feasibility of treatment with AZD9291 plus navitoclax for patients with
      T790M-mediated acquired resistance to EGFR TKI.

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To study the pharmacokinetic profile of the combination of AZD9291 plus navitoclax.

      II. To observe and record anti-tumor activity.

      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To study plasma genotype levels as a response biomarker in patients with EGFR-mutant lung
      cancer.

      II. To explore tissue biomarkers of apoptosis and their association with treatment response.

      OUTLINE: This is a phase Ib, dose-escalation study followed by a dose-expansion study.

      Patients receive navitoclax orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1-28 and EGFR inhibitor
      AZD9291 PO QD on days 4-28 (days 1-28 during dose-expansion). Courses repeat every 28 days
      in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2016</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the combination therapy in T790M+ lung cancer, measured as at least 50% of patients achieving the expected dose duration and intensity (Dose expansion)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 weeks (3 courses of treatment)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The proportion of patients completing 3 courses of therapy with &gt; 75% of total dose of each drug will be quantified. The combination dosing will be considered potentially feasible if at least 50% of patients achieve the expected dose duration and intensity (95% confidence interval 30%-70%).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of toxicity, graded according to the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 4.03 (Dose escalation)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarkers of apoptosis such as BCL2-like 1 (BCL-XL) and BCL2-like 11 (apoptosis facilitator) (BIM) levels in tumor tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Biomarkers of apoptosis such as BCL-XL and BIM levels will be measured in tumor tissue and correlated with response in an exploratory fashion, under the hypothesis that navitoclax will have greater activity in cancers with high BCL-XL levels and inadequate apoptotic response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in plasma concentration of EGFR T790M and other EGFR mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Change in plasma concentration of EGFR T790M and other EGFR mutations will be studied in an exploratory fashion and compared to tumor response on imaging.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate by RECIST</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 30 days after completion of study drug</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Calculated in the 20 patient expansion cohort and compared to the expected response rate of 61% in T790M+ lung cancer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics parameters (maximum observed plasma drug concentration, area-under-the concentration-time-curve, Trough drug concentration at steady state, and half-life) of EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 in combination with navitoclax</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, 1, 2, 4, 6, and 8 hours after navitoclax administration (day 1 of courses 1 and 2)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Pharmacokinetic calculations will incorporate consideration of the dosing change in navitoclax between the two measurement days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Recurrent Non-Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (navitoclax, EGFR inhibitor AZD9291)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive navitoclax PO QD on days 1-28 and EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 PO QD on days 4-28 (days 1-28 during dose-expansion). Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (navitoclax, EGFR inhibitor AZD9291)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Navitoclax</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (navitoclax, EGFR inhibitor AZD9291)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>A-855071.0</other_name>
    <other_name>ABT-263</other_name>
    <other_name>BcI-2 Family Protein Inhibitor ABT-263</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Osimertinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (navitoclax, EGFR inhibitor AZD9291)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AZD-9291</other_name>
    <other_name>AZD9291</other_name>
    <other_name>Mereletinib</other_name>
    <other_name>Tagrisso</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pharmacological Study</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (navitoclax, EGFR inhibitor AZD9291)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologically confirmed non-squamous NSCLC

          -  Incurable advanced or metastatic disease

          -  Prior genotyping positive for an EGFR activating mutation (L858R, exon 19 deletion,
             G719X, L861Q)

          -  Progression after prior treatment with an EGFR TKI; any additional prior lines of
             therapy are allowed; prior treatment with a third-generation EGFR TKI is allowed for
             the dose escalation phase, but is not permitted for the expansion cohort

          -  Adequate archival tissue from a biopsy performed after progression of disease on
             previous EGFR TKI; or willing to undergo a new tumor biopsy prior to registration;
             for the expansion cohort, this biopsy must have been performed after developing
             resistance to the most recent systemic therapy and must be positive for EGFR T790M

          -  Measurable disease per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST 1.1)

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 1 (Karnofsky &gt;= 70%)

          -  Life expectancy of greater than 3 months

          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL

          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL

          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 8.0 g/dL

          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL

          -  Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT), prothrombin time (PT) =&lt; 1.2 × upper
             limit of normal (ULN)

          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 × ULN (patients with Gilbert's syndrome may have serum
             bilirubin &gt; 1.5 × ULN)

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])
             =&lt; 3.0 × institutional ULN

          -  Creatinine =&lt; 2.0 mg/dL

          -  Creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 mL/min

          -  Women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception
             using one of the methods listed below prior to study entry, for the duration of study
             participation, and up to 90 days following completion of therapy:

               -  Total abstinence from sexual intercourse (minimum one complete menstrual cycle
                  prior to study drug administration)

               -  Vasectomized male subject or vasectomized partner of female subjects

               -  Hormonal contraceptives (oral, parenteral, transdermal or vaginal ring) for at
                  least 3 months prior to study drug administration; if the subject is currently
                  using a hormonal contraceptive, she should also use a barrier method during this
                  study and for 1 month after study completion

               -  Intrauterine device (IUD)

               -  Double-barrier method: male condom plus diaphragm or vaginal cap with spermicide
                  (contraceptive sponge, jellies or creams)

               -  Additionally, male subjects (including those who are vasectomized) whose
                  partners are pregnant or might be pregnant must agree to use condoms for the
                  duration of the study and for 90 days following completion of therapy

          -  Women of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test within 7
             days prior to initiation of treatment; women will be considered not of childbearing
             potential if they are surgically sterile (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy)
             and/or post-menopausal (amenorrheic for at least 12 months)

          -  Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her partner is
             participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately;
             men treated or enrolled on this protocol must also agree to use adequate
             contraception prior to the study, for the duration of study participation, and 4
             months after completion of study drug administration

          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients who have had chemotherapy within 3 weeks prior to entering the study or
             radiotherapy within 2 weeks prior to entering the study

          -  Patients with persistent treatment-related toxicities which have not resolved to &lt;
             grade 2 with the exception of alopecia and sensory neuropathy =&lt; grade 2

          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents

          -  Patients with active, symptomatic, untreated brain metastases are excluded from this
             clinical trial; patients with treated stable brain metastases are eligible provided
             they are not requiring chronic corticosteroid therapy

          -  History of allergic reactions or interstitial pneumonitis attributed to compounds of
             similar chemical or biologic composition to AZD9291 or navitoclax; patients with a
             history of radiation pneumonitis are eligible for this study provided they do not
             require steroids and symptoms are stable

          -  Patients currently receiving (or unable to stop use at least 1 week prior to
             receiving the 1st dose of AZD9291) medications or herbal supplements known to be
             potent inhibitors of cytochrome P450, family 2, subfamily C, polypeptide 8 (CYP2C8)
             and potent inhibitors or inducers of cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A,
             polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) are ineligible; patients are eligible if they stop use of
             these compounds at least 1 week prior to receiving any treatment on this protocol

          -  Patients receiving anticoagulation or anti-platelet therapy are excluded; excluded
             agents include heparin or low molecular weight heparin, warfarin, clopidogrel,
             ibuprofen and other nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAIDS), tirofiban, and
             other anticoagulants, drugs, or herbal supplements that affect platelet function;
             administration of heparin to keep subject's infusion lines patent is allowed;
             low-dose anticoagulation medications that are used to maintain the patency of a
             central intravenous catheter are allowed; aspirin will not be allowed within 7 days
             prior to the first dose of navitoclax or during navitoclax administration; however,
             subjects who have previously received aspirin therapy for thrombosis prevention, may
             resume a low dose (i.e., maximum 100 mg QD) of aspirin if platelet counts are stable
             (&gt;= 50,000/mm3) through 6 weeks of navitoclax administration; all decisions regarding
             treatment with aspirin therapy will be determined by the investigator in conjunction
             with the medical monitor

          -  Patients with an underlying condition predisposing them to bleeding or currently
             exhibiting signs of clinically significant bleeding

          -  Patients with a recent history of non-chemotherapy-induced
             thrombocytopenic-associated bleeding within 1 year prior to the first dose of study
             drug

          -  Patients with a significant history of cardiovascular disease (e.g., myocardial
             infarction [MI], thrombotic or thromboembolic event in the last 6 months)

          -  Patients with active malignancies other than NSCLC or prior curatively treated
             malignancy at high risk of relapse during the study period with the exception of
             localized squamous or basal cell skin cancers

          -  Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to,
             ongoing or active infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina
             pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, gastrointestinal disease limiting absorption of AZD9291
             such as a malabsorption syndrome or inflammatory bowel disease or psychiatric
             illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study requirements

          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study; breastfeeding should be discontinued if
             the mother is treated with AZD9291 and navitoclax

          -  Patients with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) on antiretroviral therapy are
             ineligible
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Geoffrey Oxnard</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Cancer Center - Anschutz Cancer Pavilion</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David R. Camidge</last_name>
      <phone>720-848-0650</phone>
      <email>ross.camidge@ucdenver.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David R. Camidge</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Geoffrey R. Oxnard</last_name>
      <phone>617-632-5786</phone>
      <email>goxnard@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffrey R. Oxnard</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber/Harvard Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Geoffrey R. Oxnard</last_name>
      <phone>877-442-3324</phone>
      <email>goxnard@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffrey R. Oxnard</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 9, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 10, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Navitoclax</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osimertinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
