<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="460">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02710396</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AAAQ5450</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02710396</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Genetic Predictors of Benefit to Pembrolizumab</brief_title>
  <official_title>Identifying Genetic Predictors of Durable Clinical Benefit to Pembrolizumab in Advanced or Recurrent Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Columbia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Columbia University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objectives are to determine if tumor genetics (non-synonymous mutation burden &gt;
      200 mutations and mutational smoking signature [transversion high]) can predict durable
      clinical benefit (DCB) to pembrolizumab. The secondary objective is to determine if a
      combined genetic and immune (PD-L1, immune signature) analysis can predict durable clinic
      benefit better than either test alone. Our exploratory objectives are to identify and
      validate candidate neoantigens in vitro; and explore mechanisms of resistance to
      pembrolizumab.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The adaptive immune response mechanism can be co-opted by tumor cells leading to immune
      resistance and tumor growth. Recent success of anti-PD-1 antibodies (anti-PD-1) across a
      broad range of tumors suggests that this immune resistance can be reversed. Although
      responses have been observed to anti-PD-1, it is a subset of patients who have durable
      benefit. Biomarker analysis to date has focused on co-inhibitory molecule and T cell subsets
      in the tumor microenvironment leading to a useful classification ranging from highly
      immunogenic to immunologically ignorant tumors that can define to some degree sensitivity
      and resistance to anti-PD-1. This approach has been relatively successful however it does
      not define the specific antigenic targets that exist. A growing body of literature would
      suggest tumor specific neoantigens underlie sensitivity to anti-PD-1 and mutation burden
      stochastically increases the likelihood of neoantigen formation. Although responses are
      higher in more genetically damaged tumors, there are many paths to inducing DNA damage
      leading to adaptive immune resistance (viral mediated, DNA repair defects, carcinogen
      induced). In published work to date in non-small cell lung cancer, the non-synonymous
      mutation burden and mutational smoking signature is highly predictive of durable clinical
      benefit (DCB) to pembrolizumab (defined as objective complete or partial response or stable
      disease for at least 6 months). In this biomarker trial, we will explore the relationship
      between the genetic landscape of smoking carcinogen induced tumors and DCB to pembrolizumab.
      A systematic prospective analysis in smoking carcinogen induced tumors (NSCLC, HPV negative
      head and neck, esophageal and bladder cancers) will be performed to elucidate the underlying
      biology of sensitivity and resistance.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Diagnostic</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with non small-cell lung cancer who receive durable clinical benefit to pembrolizumab.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Objective response to pembrolizumab will be assessed by RECIST 1.1 by a study radiologist. Partial and complete responses will be confirmed by a repeat imaging occurring at least 4 weeks after the initial identification of response; unconfirmed responses will be considered stable or progressive disease dependent on results of the second CT scan. Durable clinical benefit (DCB) will be defined as stable disease or response (complete or partial) lasting longer than 6 months. No durable benefit (NDB) will be defined as progression of disease ≤ 6 months of beginning therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with other smoking related cancers (HPV negative head and neck, esophageal and bladder cancers) who receive durable clinical benefit to pembrolizumab.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Objective response to pembrolizumab will be assessed by RECIST 1.1 by a study radiologist. Partial and complete responses will be confirmed by a repeat imaging occurring at least 4 weeks after the initial identification of response; unconfirmed responses will be considered stable or progressive disease dependent on results of the second CT scan. Durable clinical benefit (DCB) will be defined as stable disease or response (complete or partial) lasting longer than 6 months. No durable benefit (NDB) will be defined as progression of disease ≤ 6 months of beginning therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</condition>
  <condition>Cancer of the Head and Neck</condition>
  <condition>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Esophageal Squamous Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with advanced or recurrent cancers receiving Pembrolizumab every 3 weeks for up to 2 years.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Pembrolizumab is a potent and highly selective humanized monoclonal antibody (mAb) of the immunoglobulin G4 (IgG4)/kappa isotype designed to directly block the interaction between PD-1 and its ligands, PD-L1 and PD-L2.
Pembrolizumab 200 mg will be administered as a 30 minute IV infusion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
    <other_name>MK-3475</other_name>
    <other_name>Lambrolizumab</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Be willing and able to provide written informed consent/assent for the trial.

          -  Advanced or recurrent non-small cell lung cancer, HPV negative head and neck cancer,
             transitional cell bladder cancer or squamous esophageal cancer.

          -  NSCLC patients may be chemotherapy naïve or pre-treated. For NSCLC patients with lung
             adenocarcinoma, tumors must be epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) and Alkaline
             phosphatase (ALK) wild-type; if a Kirsten rat sarcoma (KRAS) mutation is detected,
             EGFR and ALK testing is not required.

          -  HPV negative head and neck cancer, transitional cell bladder cancer and squamous
             esophageal cancer patients must have received at least one prior line of therapy for
             their disease; treatment may include surgery, radiation, chemotherapy and/or a
             biologic agent.

          -  Diagnosis must be documented by histology or cytology from brushings, washings, or
             needle aspiration of a defined lesion but not from sputum cytology.

          -  Be ≥ 18 years of age on day of signing informed consent.

          -  Have measurable disease based on RECIST 1.1.

          -  Be willing to undergo tumor biopsies pre-treatment and at Cycle 2 Day 8 (C2D8) (+/- 7
             days). For patients who progress after DCB, also repeat biopsy at progression.

          -  Have a performance status of 0 or 1 on the Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG)
             Performance Scale.

          -  Female subject of childbearing potential should have a negative urine or serum
             pregnancy within 72 hours prior to receiving the first dose of study medication. If
             the urine test is positive or cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy test
             will be required.

          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential should be willing to use 2 methods of birth
             control or be surgically sterile, or abstain from heterosexual activity for the
             course of the study through 120 days after the last dose of study medication (Section
             8.4.4). Subjects of childbearing potential are those who have not been surgically
             sterilized or have not been free from menses for &gt; 1 year.

          -  Male subjects should agree to use an adequate method of contraception starting with
             the first dose of study therapy through 120 days after the last dose of study
             therapy.

          -  Demonstrate adequate organ function as defined below, all screening labs should be
             performed within 10 days of treatment initiation.

        Hematological

          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC): ≥1,500 /mcL

          -  Platelets: ≥100,000 / mcL

          -  Hemoglobin: ≥9 g/dL or ≥5.6 mmol/L

        Renal

          -  Serum creatinine OR Measured or calculated creatinine clearance (GFR can also be used
             in place of creatinine or CrCl): ≤1.5 X upper limit of normal (ULN) OR ≥60 mL/min for
             subject with creatinine levels &gt; 1.5 X institutional ULN

        Hepatic

          -  Serum total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 X ULN OR Direct bilirubin ≤ ULN for subjects with total
             bilirubin levels &gt; 1.5 ULN

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (SGOT) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (SGPT) ≤
             2.5 X ULN OR ≤ 5 X ULN for subjects with liver metastases

        Coagulation

          -  International Normalized Ratio (INR) or Prothrombin Time (PT): ≤1.5 X ULN unless
             subject is receiving anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or PTT is within therapeutic
             range of intended use of anticoagulants

          -  Activated Partial Thromboplastin Time (aPTT) ≤1.5 X ULN unless subject is receiving
             anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or PTT is within therapeutic range of intended
             use of anticoagulants

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Is currently participating in or has participated in a study of an investigational
             agent or using an investigational device within 4 weeks of the first dose of
             treatment.

          -  Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving systemic steroid therapy or any
             other form of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of
             trial treatment.

          -  Has had a prior monoclonal antibody within 4 weeks prior to study Day 1 or who has
             not recovered (i.e., ≤ Grade 1 or at baseline) from adverse events due to agents
             administered more than 4 weeks earlier.

          -  Has had prior chemotherapy, targeted small molecule therapy, or radiation therapy
             within 2 weeks prior to study Day 1 or who has not recovered (i.e., ≤ Grade 1 or at
             baseline) from adverse events due to a previously administered agent. Note: Subjects
             with ≤ Grade 2 neuropathy are an exception to this criterion and may qualify for the
             study. Note: If subject received major surgery, they must have recovered adequately
             from the toxicity and/or complications from the intervention prior to starting
             therapy.

          -  Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or requires active treatment.
             Exceptions include basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the
             skin, or in situ cervical cancer that has undergone potentially curative therapy.

          -  Has known active central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous
             meningitis. Subjects with previously treated brain metastases may participate
             provided they are stable (without evidence of progression by imaging for at least
             four weeks prior to the first dose of trial treatment and any neurologic symptoms
             have returned to baseline), have no evidence of new or enlarging brain metastases,
             and are not using steroids for at least 7 days prior to trial treatment.

          -  Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2
             years (i.e. with use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or
             immunosuppressive drugs). Replacement therapy (eg., thyroxine, insulin, or
             physiologic corticosteroid replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary
             insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a form of systemic treatment.

          -  Has evidence of interstitial lung disease or active, non-infectious pneumonitis.Has
             an active infection requiring systemic therapy.

          -  Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory
             abnormality that might confound the results of the trial, interfere with the
             subject's participation for the full duration of the trial, or is not in the best
             interest of the subject to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator.

          -  Has known psychiatric or substance abuse disorders that would interfere with
             cooperation with the requirements of the trial.

          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the
             projected duration of the trial, starting with the pre-screening or screening visit
             through 120 days after the last dose of trial treatment.

          -  Has received prior therapy with an anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, anti-PD-L2, anti-CD137, or
             anti-Cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-associated antigen-4 (CTLA-4) antibody (including
             ipilimumab or any other antibody or drug specifically targeting T-cell co-stimulation
             or checkpoint pathways).

          -  Has a known history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) (HIV 1/2 antibodies).

          -  Has known active Hepatitis B (e.g., HBsAg reactive) or Hepatitis C (e.g., HCV RNA
             [qualitative] is detected).

          -  Has a known history of active TB (Bacillus Tuberculosis)

          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of trial
             treatment.

          -  History of allergy or hypersensitivity to any component of the treatment.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Naiyer Rizvi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Columbia University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anu Sadhu, BA</last_name>
    <phone>(212) 342-3747</phone>
    <email>as5055@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sara Marcus, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>212 304-5579</phone>
    <email>sm4100@columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Roy Herbst, MD</last_name>
      <phone>203-785-6879</phone>
      <email>roy.herbst@yale.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Roy Herbst, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Sidney Kimmel Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21231</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julie Brahmer, MD</last_name>
      <phone>410-502-7159</phone>
      <email>brahmju@jhmi.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Julie Brahmer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Justin Ganor, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>617-724-4000</phone>
      <email>jgainor@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Beow Yeap, ScD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Justin Ganor, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anurita Sadhu, BA</last_name>
      <phone>212-342-3747</phone>
      <email>as5055@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sara Marcus, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>(212) 304-5579</phone>
      <email>sm4100@columbia.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Catherine Shu, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Stoopler, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Naiyer Rizvi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matthew Hellman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-4863</phone>
      <email>hellmanm@mskcc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matthew Hellman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brahmer JR, Drake CG, Wollner I, Powderly JD, Picus J, Sharfman WH, Stankevich E, Pons A, Salay TM, McMiller TL, Gilson MM, Wang C, Selby M, Taube JM, Anders R, Chen L, Korman AJ, Pardoll DM, Lowy I, Topalian SL. Phase I study of single-agent anti-programmed death-1 (MDX-1106) in refractory solid tumors: safety, clinical activity, pharmacodynamics, and immunologic correlates. J Clin Oncol. 2010 Jul 1;28(19):3167-75. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2009.26.7609. Epub 2010 Jun 1.</citation>
    <PMID>20516446</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brahmer, J.R., et al., Clinical activity and safety of anti-PD1 (BMS-936558, MDX-1106) in patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC). J Clin Oncol, 2012(30): p. suppl; abstr 7509</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Topalian SL, Hodi FS, Brahmer JR, Gettinger SN, Smith DC, McDermott DF, Powderly JD, Carvajal RD, Sosman JA, Atkins MB, Leming PD, Spigel DR, Antonia SJ, Horn L, Drake CG, Pardoll DM, Chen L, Sharfman WH, Anders RA, Taube JM, McMiller TL, Xu H, Korman AJ, Jure-Kunkel M, Agrawal S, McDonald D, Kollia GD, Gupta A, Wigginton JM, Sznol M. Safety, activity, and immune correlates of anti-PD-1 antibody in cancer. N Engl J Med. 2012 Jun 28;366(26):2443-54. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1200690. Epub 2012 Jun 2.</citation>
    <PMID>22658127</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brahmer JR. Harnessing the immune system for the treatment of non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2013 Mar 10;31(8):1021-8. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2012.45.8703. Epub 2013 Feb 11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23401435</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Taube JM, Anders RA, Young GD, Xu H, Sharma R, McMiller TL, Chen S, Klein AP, Pardoll DM, Topalian SL, Chen L. Colocalization of inflammatory response with B7-h1 expression in human melanocytic lesions supports an adaptive resistance mechanism of immune escape. Sci Transl Med. 2012 Mar 28;4(127):127ra37. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.3003689.</citation>
    <PMID>22461641</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Matsushita H, Vesely MD, Koboldt DC, Rickert CG, Uppaluri R, Magrini VJ, Arthur CD, White JM, Chen YS, Shea LK, Hundal J, Wendl MC, Demeter R, Wylie T, Allison JP, Smyth MJ, Old LJ, Mardis ER, Schreiber RD. Cancer exome analysis reveals a T-cell-dependent mechanism of cancer immunoediting. Nature. 2012 Feb 8;482(7385):400-4. doi: 10.1038/nature10755.</citation>
    <PMID>22318521</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>DuPage M, Cheung AF, Mazumdar C, Winslow MM, Bronson R, Schmidt LM, Crowley D, Chen J, Jacks T. Endogenous T cell responses to antigens expressed in lung adenocarcinomas delay malignant tumor progression. Cancer Cell. 2011 Jan 18;19(1):72-85. doi: 10.1016/j.ccr.2010.11.011.</citation>
    <PMID>21251614</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>DuPage M, Mazumdar C, Schmidt LM, Cheung AF, Jacks T. Expression of tumour-specific antigens underlies cancer immunoediting. Nature. 2012 Feb 8;482(7385):405-9. doi: 10.1038/nature10803.</citation>
    <PMID>22318517</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Castle JC, Kreiter S, Diekmann J, Löwer M, van de Roemer N, de Graaf J, Selmi A, Diken M, Boegel S, Paret C, Koslowski M, Kuhn AN, Britten CM, Huber C, Türeci O, Sahin U. Exploiting the mutanome for tumor vaccination. Cancer Res. 2012 Mar 1;72(5):1081-91. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-11-3722. Epub 2012 Jan 11.</citation>
    <PMID>22237626</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schumacher TN, Schreiber RD. Neoantigens in cancer immunotherapy. Science. 2015 Apr 3;348(6230):69-74. doi: 10.1126/science.aaa4971. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25838375</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rizvi NA, Hellmann MD, Snyder A, Kvistborg P, Makarov V, Havel JJ, Lee W, Yuan J, Wong P, Ho TS, Miller ML, Rekhtman N, Moreira AL, Ibrahim F, Bruggeman C, Gasmi B, Zappasodi R, Maeda Y, Sander C, Garon EB, Merghoub T, Wolchok JD, Schumacher TN, Chan TA. Cancer immunology. Mutational landscape determines sensitivity to PD-1 blockade in non-small cell lung cancer. Science. 2015 Apr 3;348(6230):124-8. doi: 10.1126/science.aaa1348. Epub 2015 Mar 12.</citation>
    <PMID>25765070</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 15, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 11, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Columbia University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Naiyer Rizvi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine at the Columbia University Medical Center, Dept of Med Hematology &amp; Onc</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-Small-Cell Lung Carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Nonsmall Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer of Neck</keyword>
  <keyword>Neoplasms, Head and Neck</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer of the Head</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer of the Head and Neck</keyword>
  <keyword>Head, Neck Neoplasms</keyword>
  <keyword>Bladder Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Bladder Neoplasms</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant Tumor of Urinary Bladder</keyword>
  <keyword>Urinary Bladder Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Esophageal Squamous Cell Carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
