<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="411">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02498613</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2015-01097</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2015-01097</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>TBD</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>9881</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>9881</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA016359</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1CA186689</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02498613</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 2 Study of Cediranib in Combination With Olaparib in Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Study of Cediranib in Combination With Olaparib in Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies cediranib maleate in combination with olaparib in treating
      patients with solid tumors that have spread to other parts of the body or cannot be removed
      by surgery, including breast cancer, non-small cell lung cancer, small cell lung cancer, and
      pancreatic cancer. Cediranib maleate and olaparib may stop the growth of tumor cells by
      blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Cediranib maleate may also block the
      flow of oxygen to the tumor, and may help make the tumor more sensitive to olaparib.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To determine the objective response rate (ORR) of cediranib (cediranib maleate) plus
      olaparib in combination in patients with advanced or metastatic solid tumors of the
      following tumor types: non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), germline breast cancer, early
      onset 1/2 (BRCA1/2) wild type (wt) triple negative breast cancer (TNBC), pancreatic ductal
      adenocarcinoma (PDAC), and small cell lung cancer (SCLC). The responses will be assessed by
      the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1.

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To assess the safety and tolerability of oral administration of cediranib in combination
      with olaparib in patients with select advanced solid tumors.

      II. To determine progression free survival (PFS) in each tumor cohort.

      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. In the NSCLC cohort of the study, to determine changes in tumor hypoxia on cediranib
      treatment compared to baseline by positron emission tomography (PET) imaging using [F-18]
      fluoromisonidazole (F-MISO) as a tracer.

      II. To correlate ORR with hypoxia levels at baseline and changes from baseline. III. To
      determine in tumor tissue, if the BRCA1 gene is repressed or silenced by cediranib treatment
      and correlate with ORR.

      IV. To determine changes in other markers of hypoxia in tumor tissue, correlate with BRCA1
      expression and ORR.

      V. To correlate hypoxia levels determined by PET imaging with BRCA1 gene expression and
      hypoxia markers.

      VI. To determine baseline levels and changes in angiogenesis markers in plasma, including
      plasma vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and correlate with ORR and other
      correlative markers in patients where tissue is available as well as hypoxia levels measured
      by PET imaging.

      VII. To determine changes in microribonucleic acids (miRNAs) related to hypoxia and
      correlate with ORR and other correlative markers in patients where tissue is available as
      well as hypoxia levels determined by PET imaging.

      VIII. To assess gene variants and mutations in tumors (NSCLC and breast cancer [BC] cohorts)
      using the BROCA panel to explore, if any variants in genes involved in deoxyribonucleic acid
      (DNA) damage repair or hypoxia pathways predict ORR and explore correlation with any of the
      other biomarkers measured in the study.

      OUTLINE:

      Patients receive cediranib maleate orally (PO) once daily (QD) for 3-4 days and then undergo
      biopsy. After biopsy, patients continue to receive cediranib maleate PO QD and begin
      olaparib PO twice daily (BID) beginning on the day after the post-dose biopsy (days 4-7) or
      by day 8 of course 1 (biopsy cohorts-NSCLC and TNBC) or day 4 of course 1 (non-biopsy
      cohorts-PDAC and SCLC). Courses repeat every 28 days (35 days for course 1) in the absence
      of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 4 weeks.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2016</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR, measured by RECIST v 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 weeks after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The exact two-sided 95% confidence interval for the ORR will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of toxicity, graded according to NCI CTCAE version 4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 weeks after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Adverse medical events will be tabulated. NCI toxicity grade 3 and grade 4 laboratory abnormalities will be listed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS</measure>
    <time_frame>The duration of time from start of treatment to time of progression or death, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 4 weeks after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method with the 95% confidence intervals (CIs). The Rothman CI, CI based on the Greenwoods variance, Thomas and Grunkemeier CI and the simultaneous confidence bands by Nair and Hall and Wellner will be reported. The possible risk factors will be compared for survival with log-rank test. For multivariate analysis, the proportional hazards Cox model will be applied to investigate potential prognostic factors, such as age and stage of disease on the survival data. The adjusted p-values of the hazard ratios and the adjusted 95% confidence interval will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarker data</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 weeks after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The biomarker data analysis including miRNAs data will be completed using the Lasso based elastic net method. The penalty parameter that controls the shrinkage of fixed terms and the variable selection will be determined by k-fold cross validation. Due to the limited sample size, the biomarker data analysis is for the exploratory research only.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>PET imaging data</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to day 4</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The general non-linear and generalized non-liner model will be used to analyze PET imaging data.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">121</enrollment>
  <condition>Estrogen Receptor Negative</condition>
  <condition>HER2/Neu Negative</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Progesterone Receptor Negative</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Breast Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Non-Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Pancreatic Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage III Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Triple-Negative Breast Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (cediranib maleate, olaparib)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive cediranib maleate PO QD for 3-4 days and then undergo biopsy. After biopsy, patients continue to receive cediranib maleate PO QD and begin olaparib PO BID on the day after the post-dose biopsy (day 4-7) or by day 8 of course 1 (biopsy cohorts-NSCLC and TNBC) or day 4 of course 1 (non-biopsy cohorts-PDAC and SCLC). Courses repeat every 28 days (35 days for course 1) in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>18F-Fluoromisonidazole</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (cediranib maleate, olaparib)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>18F-MISO</other_name>
    <other_name>18F-Misonidazole</other_name>
    <other_name>FMISO</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cediranib Maleate</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (cediranib maleate, olaparib)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AZD2171</other_name>
    <other_name>AZD2171 Maleate</other_name>
    <other_name>Recentin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (cediranib maleate, olaparib)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olaparib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (cediranib maleate, olaparib)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AZD2281</other_name>
    <other_name>KU-0059436</other_name>
    <other_name>Lynparza</other_name>
    <other_name>PARP Inhibitor AZD2281</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Positron Emission Tomography</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (cediranib maleate, olaparib)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Medical Imaging, Positron Emission Tomography</other_name>
    <other_name>PET</other_name>
    <other_name>PET SCAN</other_name>
    <other_name>Positron Emission Tomography Scan</other_name>
    <other_name>Positron-Emission Tomography</other_name>
    <other_name>proton magnetic resonance spectroscopic imaging</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients must have histologically confirmed, metastatic or unresectable malignancy of
             the following types: (a) non-squamous, non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), (b)
             triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) without germline BRCA mutation, (c) pancreatic
             adenocarcinoma (PDAC), or (d) small cell lung cancer (SCLC)

          -  For NSCLC patients only:

               -  Must be willing to undergo paired FMISO PET scans

               -  Must be willing to undergo paired biopsies

               -  Must have had prior chemotherapy including platinum-based regimen and epidermal
                  growth factor receptor (EGFR) tyrosine kinase inhibitor(s) (TKI[s]) or
                  anaplastic lymphoma receptor tyrosine kinase (ALK) inhibitors if sensitizing
                  mutations are present

          -  For TNBC patients only

               -  Must be known germline BRCA wild-type; BRCA mutation carriers are excluded; if
                  unknown, then BRCA testing must be performed in a clinical Clinical Laboratory
                  Improvement Amendments (CLIA) certified lab

               -  Must have tumor amenable for, and be willing to undergo, baseline and
                  on-treatment biopsies

               -  Must have received at least 1 prior chemotherapy regimen in the metastatic
                  setting

          -  For PDAC patients only

               -  Must have received at least one standard chemotherapy either with or without
                  radiation therapy

          -  For SCLC patients only

               -  Must have had a standard platinum-based regimen for limited or extensive stage
                  disease

          -  FOR ALL PATIENTS

          -  Patients must have measurable disease by RECIST v1.1

          -  Toxicities of prior therapy (except alopecia) should be resolved to =&lt; grade 1 as per
             National Cancer Institute (NCI)-Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events
             (CTCAE) version (v)4.0; patients with long-standing stable grade 2 neuropathy may be
             considered after discussion with the study Principal Investigator (PI)

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or 1 (Karnofsky &gt;=
             70%)

          -  Life expectancy of &gt;= 4 months

          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL

          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL

          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL

          -  Hemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL

          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x the institutional upper limit of normal (ULN)

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])
             =&lt; 2.5 x institutional ULN

          -  Creatinine within normal institutional limits OR creatinine clearance &gt;= 60
             mL/min/1.73 m^2 for patients with creatinine levels above institutional normal

          -  Proteinuria less than or equal to 1+ proteinuria on two consecutive dipsticks taken
             no less than week apart, or &lt; 1 g protein on 24-hour urine collection or a urine
             protein:creatinine ratio of &lt; 1

          -  Troponin T or I within normal institutional limits

          -  International normalized ration (INR) within 1.25 x ULN institutional limits, except
             where a lupus anti-coagulant has been confirmed

          -  Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) within 1.25 x ULN institutional limits,
             except where a lupus anti-coagulant has been confirmed

          -  Patients must be able to tolerate oral medications and not have gastrointestinal
             illnesses that would preclude absorption of cediranib or olaparib

          -  Adequately controlled thyroid function, with no symptoms of thyroid dysfunction and
             thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) within normal limits

          -  Adequately controlled blood pressure (BP) &lt; 140 mmHg (systolic) and &lt; 90 mmHg
             (diastolic) taken in the clinic setting by a medical professional within 2 weeks
             prior to starting study; patients with hypertension may be managed with up to a
             maximum of 3 antihypertensive medications; patients who are on 3 antihypertensive
             medications are highly recommended to be followed by a cardiologist or blood pressure
             specialist for management of BP while on protocol

          -  Patients who have the following risk factors are considered to be at increased risk
             for cardiac toxicities, and must have documented left ventricular ejection fraction
             (LVEF) by echocardiogram greater than institution's lower limit of normal (or 55% if
             threshold for normal not otherwise specified by institutional guidelines) obtained
             within 6 months

               -  Prior treatment with anthracyclines

               -  Prior treatment with trastuzumab

               -  A New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification of II controlled with
                  treatment

               -  Prior central thoracic radiation therapy (RT), including RT to the heart

               -  History of myocardial infarction within 12 months (patients with history of
                  myocardial infarction within 6 months are excluded from the study)

          -  Women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception
             (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and
             for the duration of study participation; should a woman become pregnant or suspect
             she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should
             inform her treating physician immediately; men treated or enrolled on this protocol
             must also agree to use adequate contraception prior to the study, for the duration of
             study participation, and for 4 months after completion of cediranib and olaparib
             administration

          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with known deleterious BRCA germline mutation by standard clinical testing
             are excluded; for TNBC patients, BRCA germline testing is required, if not performed
             previously; for the other cohorts, BRCA germline testing is not required

          -  Patients who have had chemotherapy or RT within 3 weeks prior to start of the study
             agents, or those who have not recovered from adverse events due to agents
             administered more than 3 weeks earlier

          -  Patients should not have received any other investigational agents within the past 4
             weeks

          -  Patients with untreated brain metastases, spinal cord compression, or evidence of
             symptomatic brain metastases or leptomeningeal disease as noted on computed
             tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans should be excluded from
             this clinical trial; screening imaging to rule out brain metastases is not required,
             but should be performed prior to study enrollment if clinically indicated; patients
             with treated brain metastases and resolution of any associated symptoms must
             demonstrate stable post-therapeutic imaging for at least 1 month following
             radiotherapy prior to starting study drug

          -  Patients who have received prior inhibitor of VEGF signaling and a poly (ADP-ribose)
             polymerases (PARP) inhibitor administered in combination; unless administered in
             combination, patients who received a prior PARP inhibitor or a prior VEGF-signaling
             inhibitor agent are allowed after discussing with the PI

          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic
             composition to cediranib or olaparib

          -  Participants receiving any medications or substances that are strong inhibitors or
             inducers of cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A, polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) are
             ineligible; dihydropyridine calcium-channel blockers are permitted for management of
             hypertension

          -  Current use of natural herbal products or other &quot;folk remedies;&quot; if using previously,
             patients must stop using natural herbal products while participating in this study

          -  Patients with concomitant or prior invasive malignancies within the past 3 years;
             subjects with treated limited stage basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin
             or carcinoma in situ of the breast or cervix are eligible

          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with
             study requirements

          -  Patients with corrected QT interval (QTc) (with Bazett's correction) prolongation &gt;
             470 msec or other significant electrocardiogram (ECG) abnormality noted within 14
             days of treatment

          -  History of myocardial infarction within 6 months

          -  History of stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months

          -  NYHA classification of III or IV

          -  Current condition requiring concurrent use of drugs or biologics with anti-arrhythmic
             or pro-arrhythmic potential

          -  History of hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy within 3 years

          -  Clinically significant peripheral vascular disease or vascular disease (abdominal
             aortic aneurysm (&gt; 5 cm) or aortic dissection)

          -  A major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or significant traumatic injury within 28
             days prior to starting cediranib (percutaneous/endobronchial biopsies are allowed)

          -  Patients may not have current signs and/or symptoms of bowel obstruction within 1
             month prior to starting study drugs, except if it was a temporary incident (improved
             within &lt; 24 hrs with medical management)

          -  History of hemoptysis within the last 1 month

          -  Presence of cavitation of central pulmonary lesion

          -  History of abdominal fistula, intra-abdominal abscess, or gastrointestinal
             perforation with the 3 months

          -  Patients may not have current dependency on intravenous (IV) hydration or total
             parenteral nutrition (TPN)

          -  Patients may not have evidence of coagulopathy or bleeding diathesis; therapeutic
             anticoagulation for prior thromboembolic events is permitted

          -  Patients may not have features suggestive of myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) or acute
             myelogenous leukemia (AML) on peripheral blood smear or bone marrow biopsy, if
             clinically indicated

          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study; breastfeeding should be discontinued if
             the mother is treated with cediranib and olaparib

          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-positive patients on combination antiretroviral
             therapy are ineligible
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joseph Kim</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University Cancer Center LAO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale University Cancer Center LAO</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06520</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joseph W. Kim</last_name>
      <phone>203-737-6467</phone>
      <email>joseph.w.kim@yale.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph W. Kim</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 10, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 14, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Cediranib</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Maleic acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Misonidazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
