<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="289">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01068210</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15-215</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01068210</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lung Cancer Exercise Training Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Lung Cancer Exercise Training Study: A Randomized Trial of Aerobic Training, Resistance Training, or Both in Postsurgical Lung Cancer Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the study is look at the effects of different modalities of exercise training
      and its effect on post-surgical lung cancer patients. Subjects will take part in a 16 week
      training intervention that can consist of aerobic, resistance, aerobic &amp; resistance, or a
      control group. Pre and Post testing will include stress tests, echos, blood, and urine
      samples.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes in VO2peak (on exercise capacity)</measure>
    <time_frame>17 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>by comparing the efficacy of different types of exercise training modalities in patients with resected non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) following the completion of primary adjuvant therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">82</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aerobic Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A customized and supervised endurance exercise training program that will last 4 months (16 weeks). The regimen will be tailored to the individual fitness level. The exercise program will consist of three supervised sessions per week. During each session, the participant will cycle on a stationary bicycle at moderate intensity for approximately 30-60 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Resistance Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A customized and supervised resistance exercise training program that will last 4 months (16 weeks). Resistance training will be performed on stationary weight machines. No free weights will be used. The participant will be trained to perform different resistance exercise, alternating between lower and upper body muscle groups. The exercise program will consist of three supervised sessions per week. Each session will last approximately 30-60 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Combined Aerobic and Resistance Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A customized and supervised endurance exercise training program that will last 4 months (16 weeks). The regimen will be tailored to the individual fitness level, and will be a combination of Arm A and Arm B, described above. At each session, the participant will complete aerobic training on a stationary bicycle and also resistance training using stationary weight machines. The exercise program will consist of three supervised sessions per week. Each session will last approximately 30-90 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Progressive Stretching Group (Attention-Control)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>A customized and supervised progressive stretching program that will last 4 months (16 weeks). The progressive stretching program will consist of a series of stretching exercises alternating between lower and upper body muscle groups/joints. This program will consist of three exercise sessions a week. Each session will last approximately 30-60 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise Training</intervention_name>
    <description>The overall goal for all the exercise training groups will be 3 supervised exercise sessions per week an intensity between 50 to 100% of the individually determined VO2peak for aerobic training and an intensity between 50% to 85% of 1-RM for resistance training. All the exercise interventions are designed such that participants begin exercising at a low intensity (~50%-60% VO2peak / 1RM) that is subsequently increased to more moderate to vigorous intensity (~70%-100% VO2peak / ~70-85% 1RM) when appropriate. All interventions will be individually tailored to each patient following the principles of aerobic or resistance training prescription guidelines for adults.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aerobic Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Resistance Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Combined Aerobic and Resistance Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Progressive Stretching</intervention_name>
    <description>Stretching will be performed on stretching mats (i.e., no machines). Patients will be progressively trained to perform stretching exercises alternating between muscle groups / joints. Stretches will consist of prolonged holds held (under the maximum range of passive motion) initially for 20 secs and increasing to ≥60 secs/stretch.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Progressive Stretching Group (Attention-Control)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Signed informed consent prior to initiation of study-related procedures

          -  Age ≥ 21 years MSKCC histologically confirmed postoperative non-small lung cancer

          -  An interval of at least one year following the completion of definitive adjuvant
             therapy (i.e., completion of definitive surgery and/or chemotherapy or radiation)

          -  An interval of no longer than ten years following completion of primary therapy

          -  Life expectancy ≥ 6 months

          -  Sedentary, as per the leisure score index (LSI) of the Godin Leisure-Time Exercise
             Questionnaire (GLTEQ) (Appendix B) (i.e., patients not performing regular exercise on
             at least 5 days a week, for at least 30 minutes each session, at a moderate or
             vigorous intensity for the past month)

          -  Exercise intolerance (i.e., patients must have a VO2peak below that predicted for
             sedentary age and sex-matched individuals)

          -  Willing to be randomized to one of the study arms

          -  Willing to commit to study program and comply with all related protocol procedures

          -  Ability to achieve and complete an acceptable baseline CPET as defined as follows:
             absence of remarkable ECG findings or results cleared by a cardiologist;
             hemodynamically appropriate responses to exercise as determined by attending exercise
             physiologist(s) and reviewing cardiologist; achieving peak or plateau in oxygen
             concurrent with increased power output; a respiratory exchange ratio ≥ 1.1;
             volitional exhaustion; and rating of perceived exertion ≥ 18.

          -  Ability to achieve and complete an acceptable baseline one-repetition maximum
             muscular strength test as defined by the effective execution of protocol-specific
             joint and muscle ranges of motion without remarkable signs or symptoms of pain,
             discomfort or distress.

          -  Primary attending approval

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Presence of a concurrent, actively treated other malignancy, or history of other
             malignancy treated within the past 3 years (other than non-melanoma skin cancer);

          -  Presence of metastatic disease;

          -  Any of the following absolute contraindications to cardiopulmonary exercise testing:

               -  Acute myocardial infarction (within 3-5 days of any planned study procedures);

               -  Unstable angina;

               -  Uncontrolled arrhythmia causing symptoms or hemodynamic compromise;

               -  Recurrent syncope;

               -  Active endocarditis;

               -  Acute myocarditis or pericarditis;

               -  Symptomatic severe aortic stenosis;

               -  Uncontrolled heart failure;

               -  Acute (within 3 months) pulmonary embolus or pulmonary infarction;

               -  Thrombosis of lower extremities;

               -  Suspected dissecting aneurysm;

               -  Uncontrolled asthma;

               -  Pulmonary edema;

               -  Room air desaturation at rest ≤ 85%;

               -  Respiratory failure;

               -  Acute non-cardiopulmonary disorders that may affect exercise performance or be
                  aggravated by exercise (i.e., infection, renal failure, thyrotoxicosis); or

               -  Mental impairment leading to inability to cooperate.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lee Jones, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lee Jones, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>646-888-8103</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Valerie Rusch, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-639-5873</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lee Jones, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>646-888-8103</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Valerie Rusch, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-639-5873</phone>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lee Jones, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mskcc.org/</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 6, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>February 11, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Exercise Intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>15-215</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
