<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="497">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01233687</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10-058</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01233687</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>AMG 102 and Erlotinib for Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II Trial of AMG 102 and Erlotinib in Previously Treated Patients With Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ahmad Tarhini</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Amgen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pittsburgh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase I/II study of erlotinib and AMG 102 in previously treated subjects with
      advanced NSCLC. Subjects will be enrolled with recurrent or progressive advanced stage NSCLC
      that has been treated with at least one and a maximum of two prior chemotherapy regimens.
      The Phase I part of the study will enroll 8-16 subjects with the Phase II part enrolling
      21-45 subjects.

      The Phase I part of the study is designed to determine how safest the combination of AMG 102
      and erlotinib is and the recommended dose for the Phase II part. The Phase II part is to
      determine whether the combination of AMG102 and erlotinib works enough to warrant further
      interest in this combination.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of a safe dose of AMG 102 when combined with erlotinib for the treatment of patients with advanced, previously-treated NSCLC (phase I part).</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing from the start of the study.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>The recommended phase II dose is determined in part by the dose of AMG 102 that, in combination with erlotinib, is associated with a maximum 25% rate of dose limiting toxicity (DLT). Dose de-escalation will proceed according to a Narayana k-in-a-row design and the selected dose will be estimated by isotonic regression. For this trial k is set to 3.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination whether the efficacy (disease-control rate) of the combination of AMG102 and erlotinib is high enough to warrant further interest in this combination (phase II part).</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>In the absence of dose de-escalation, the phase II starting dose will be 15 mg.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">61</enrollment>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AMG 102 and erlotinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Combination of AMG 102 and erlotinib</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AMG 102 and erlotinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose Level -2 Dose level -1 Dose Level 0 AMG 102 5 mg/kg 7.5 mg/kg 15 mg/kg Erlotinib 150 mg 150 mg 150 mg
The first cohort of patients in the phase I portion will start at dose level 0 of AMG102.</description>
    <arm_group_label>AMG 102 and erlotinib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rilotumumab</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Patients must have baseline evaluations performed prior to the first dose of study drug
        and must meet all inclusion and exclusion criteria. Results of all baseline evaluations,
        which assure that all inclusion and exclusion criteria have been satisfied, must be
        reviewed by a Physician Investigator prior to enrollment of that patient. In addition, the
        patient must be thoroughly informed about all aspects of the study, including the study
        visit schedule and required evaluations and all regulatory requirements for informed
        consent. The written informed consent must be obtained from the patient prior to
        enrollment. The following criteria apply to all patients enrolled onto the study unless
        otherwise specified.

        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with recurrent or progressive advanced stage Non-small cell lung cancer
             (NSCLC,no SCLC component) who have been treated with at least one and a maximum of
             two prior chemotherapy regimens for advanced NSCLC. Chemotherapy as part of initial
             potentially curative therapy (given as part of adjuvant or concomitant
             chemoradiotherapy) that was completed &lt;1 year counts as 1 prior regimen. Prior
             erlotinib, other epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) TKIs or monoclonal
             antibodies targeting EGFR are not allowed.

        NOTE: Chemotherapy as part of initial potentially curative therapy (given as part of
        adjuvant or concomitant chemoradiotherapy) that was completed one or more years prior to
        screening for this study does not count as a prior regimen.

        If the tumor is refractory (progressed) after a prior chemotherapy regimen, then that
        regimen would count. If a prior chemotherapy regimen has been changed due to other reasons
        than disease progression (e.g. poor tolerance, allergic reaction), then it would not count
        as a separate prior regimen. A chemotherapy drug added for &quot;maintenance&quot; following disease
        stabilization or response to a chemotherapy regimen (in the absence of prior disease
        progression) does not count as a separate prior regimen.

        NOTE: Pathology reports documenting the diagnosis of NSCLC are required to be reviewed by
        the screening physician investigator.

          -  Measurable disease (RECIST version 1.1) (for phase II part only).

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of ≤ 2 and life
             expectancy of ≥ 3 months.

        NOTE: For the phase I part of the study, patients with ECOG Performance Status 2 will be
        excluded.

          -  Age ≥ 18 years old and ability to provide written informed consent obtained prior to
             participation in the study and any related procedures being performed.

          -  Patients must meet the following laboratory criteria (within 14 days prior to study
             registration):

        oHematology: Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1500/mm³ Platelets ≥ 100,000/mm³ Hemoglobin
        ≥ 9 g/dL International normalized ratio (INR) ≤ 1.5 or prothrombin time (PT)/partial
        thromboplastin time (PTT) within normal limits (WNL) of the institution oBiochemistry:
        Total Bilirubin within normal institutional limits. AST/SGOT and ALT/SGPT ≤ 2.5 x upper
        limit of normal (ULN), except if there is known hepatic metastasis, wherein transaminases
        may be ≤ 5 x institutional ULN.

        Creatinine clearance 45 ml/min or higher calculated using the Cockcroft-Gault formula.
        Multiply the number by 0.85 if the patient is female.

          -  Patients must have fully recovered from the effects of any prior surgery,
             chemotherapy or radiation therapy. In the case of residual effects, these must be
             clinically stable, grade 1 or less in severity and do not meet other protocol
             exclusion criteria. A minimum time period of 3 weeks should elapse between the
             completion of radiation therapy for recurrent/metastatic disease and enrollment in
             the study. A minimum of 4 weeks should elapse between the completion of chemotherapy
             or any experimental therapy and enrollment in the study. A minimum of 4 weeks should
             elapse between prior major surgery (such as open biopsy or significant traumatic
             injury) and enrollment in the study. A minimum of 2 weeks should elapse between prior
             minor surgical procedures (such as chemotherapy infusion port placement or core
             visceral organ biopsy) and enrollment in the study.

          -  If patient has history of brain metastases, brain lesions should have been treated
             with surgery and/or radiation and be stable on repeat imaging and patients should be
             neurologically stable on a stable or tapering dose of corticosteroids.

          -  No history of prior malignancy, with the exception of curatively treated squamous
             cell or basal carcinoma of the skin or in situ cervical cancer, unless there is a
             3-year disease-free interval.

          -  Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy
             test within 7 days of the first administration of study treatment and must be willing
             to use two methods of contraception one of them being a barrier method or abstain
             from sexual activity during the study and for 6 months after last study drug
             administration. Sexually active males and their female partners must agree to use two
             methods of accepted and effective method of contraception (hormonal or barrier
             methods, abstinence) prior to study entry and for the duration of the study.

          -  All patients must have given signed, informed consent prior to registration on study.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with known positivity for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or hepatitis C;
             baseline testing for HIV and hepatitis C is not required. This is due to the unknown
             effects of AMG102.

          -  Patients with any significant history of non-compliance to medical regimens or with
             inability to grant a reliable informed consent.

          -  Patients who have mixed tumors with small-cell elements are ineligible.

          -  Pregnancy or lactation. All females of child-bearing potential must have negative
             serum or urine pregnancy tests within 7 days prior to starting study treatment.

          -  Prior treatment of NSCLC with EGFR TKIs or monoclonal antibodies targeting EGFR.

          -  A serious active infection (&gt;grade 2) within 7 days of enrollment.

          -  A serious underlying medical condition that would impair the ability of the patient
             to receive protocol treatment.

          -  Untreated brain metastases.

          -  A major surgical procedure or significant traumatic injury within 28 days of
             beginning treatment, or anticipation of the need for major surgery during the course
             of the study per inclusion criterion 3.1. In addition, if a patient has not yet
             recovered from prior minor surgery (such as central venous access device or fine
             needle aspiration biopsy).

          -  Thrombosis or vascular ischemic events within the last twelve months, such as deep
             venous thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, transient ischemic attack, cerebral
             infarction, or myocardial infarction

          -  Concurrent or prior (within 7 days of enrollment) anticoagulation therapy, except for
             the use of low dose coumarin-type anticoagulants or low molecular weight heparin for
             prophylaxis against central venous catheter thrombosis

          -  Presence of peripheral edema &gt; Grade 2 (CTCAE version 4).
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmad Tarhini, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ahmad Tarhini, MD, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>412-648-6507</phone>
    <email>tarhiniaa@upmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kelli Davis, RN, MSN</last_name>
    <phone>412-235-1316</phone>
    <email>skoviraka@upmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ahmad Tarhini, MD, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>412-648-6507</phone>
      <email>tarhiniaa@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>April 14, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>November 2, 2010</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmad Tarhini</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recurrent</keyword>
  <keyword>progressive</keyword>
  <keyword>advanced</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
