<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="443">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02409108</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>G130154</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2014-089</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02409108</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Perfusion-Induced Hyperthermia in Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Early Feasibility Study Of Perfusion-Induced Hyperthermia For Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jeremiah Martin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Exatherm, Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Kentucky</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to gather information on how safe the hyperthermia treatment
      delivered via the Exatherm-TBH (the device that will heat your blood and deliver it back to
      you), added to the best supportive care is to patients who have advanced persistent or
      recurrent, unresectable Non Small Cell Lung Cancer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety as measured by adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Incidence of adverse events as assessed by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version (v.) 4.0. Adverse event data and corresponding toxicity grades during treatment will be summarized in the form of tables. Incidence tables will be generated to summarize incidence of patients reporting at least one episode of each specific adverse event, incidence of adverse events causing withdrawal and incidence of serious adverse event. The total number of episodes for each event reported (Frequency Table), the severity and attribution to study therapy of each episode reported (Severity Table and Attribution Table) will also be displayed. Safety data will be summarized for the overall treated group and the overall concurrent control group. Reversibility of the adverse events and toxicities will also be summarized.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exatherm-TBH device functionality</measure>
    <time_frame>Time frame: day 1</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Device functionality will be documented and summarized using descriptive statistics and presented in the form of tables</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety as measured by serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Incidence of serious adverse events associated with hyperthermic treatment as graded by the NCI CTCAE v. 4.0. Summarized in the form of tables. Listings of adverse events by patients will include the time to onset, the duration of each event, the severity of each event, and the relationship of the event to study therapy, whether it was a serious event, and whether it caused withdrawal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and up to 1 year after treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Assess changes in quality of life as documented by the EQ-DL-3L. QOL and neurocognitive testing will be summarized using descriptive statistics including mean, median and variation levels of QOL score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Complication rates associated with hyperthermic treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 weeks post-treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Complication rates will be documented and summarized using descriptive statistics and presented in the form of tables</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Assess clinical benefit rate as documented by CR+PR+SD.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to treatment failure</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Documentation of disease progression presented with Kaplan Meier curve.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Progression free survival following hyperthermic therapy presented with Kaplan Meier curve</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Death</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Documentation of time of death presented with Kaplan Meier curve</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Non-Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Exatherm-TBH system</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>One treatment of Total Body Hyperthermia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exatherm-TBH system</intervention_name>
    <description>One treatment of Total Body Hyperthermia</description>
    <arm_group_label>Exatherm-TBH system</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of Stage IIIB
             or Stage IV of non-small cell lung cancer and have received at least two lines of
             FDA-approved or National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) accepted systemic
             therapy and progressed through, or not tolerated, such therapy.

               -  Subjects whose tumors harbor an exon 19 deletion or exon 21L858R EGFR mutation
                  must have progressed on or had intolerance to EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor.

               -  Subjects whose tumors harbor an AKL translocation must have progressed on or had
                  intolerance to crizotinib (or any FDA approved ALK inhibitor).

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤2

          -  Life expectancy of greater than 3 months.

          -  Age ≥18 years.

          -  There is no restriction on the number of prior therapies allowed for this disease and
             prior radiation and chemotherapy is allowed, provided the subject has recovered from
             all grade 2 or greater toxicity prior to enrollment.

          -  Patient understands the nature of the procedure, is willing to comply with associated
             follow-up evaluations, and provide written informed consent prior to the procedure

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients who have had chemotherapy or radiotherapy within 4 weeks (6 weeks for
             nitrosoureas or mitomycin C, or monoclonal antibodies such as bevacizumab, cetuximab
             or panitumumab) prior to entering the study or those who have not recovered to &lt;
             grade 2 adverse events due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier.

          -  Patients with stroke or TIA within 90 days prior to enrollment; or peripheral
             vascular disease requiring intervention within the 90 days prior to enrollment; or
             any known hemodynamically significant lesion or embolic plaque.

          -  Patients must have normal organ and marrow function as defined below:

               -  leukocytes ≥3,000/mcL

               -  absolute neutrophil count ≥1,500/mcL

               -  total Bilirubin, AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT) ≤2.5 × institutional upper limit of normal

               -  glomerular filtration rate (GFR)&gt; 60 as defined by the Modification of Diet in
                  Renal Disease (MDRD) formula

               -  Thromboplastin Time (PTT) &lt; 35 sec)

          -  Patients with uncontrolled seizure disorder, spinal cord compression or carcinomatous
             meningitis.

          -  Patients with a mental disorder, psychiatric illness/social or concussion which would
             inhibit their ability to provide informed consent or prevent compliance with
             follow-up.

          -  Patients with high risk of cardiovascular event such as severe uncontrolled
             hypertension (&gt;170/110 systemic blood pressure on therapy), or pulmonary hypertension
             (greater than .5 systolic blood pressure

          -  ST elevation myocardial infarction within 30 days prior to enrollment; unstable
             angina or significant, untreated arrhythmias within 30 days prior to enrollment.

          -  Patients with moderate to severe heart failure, New York Heart Association (NYHA)
             class III or IV, liver dysfunction with total bilirubin &gt;2. 5 upper limit of normal,
             or serum creatinine &gt;2.5 mg/dL or any form of dialysis; within 30 days prior to
             enrollment.

          -  Patients with a major surgical procedure or other investigational agents within 30
             days before study enrollment.

          -  Patients with known, untreated or progressive brain metastases will be excluded from
             this clinical trial because of their poor prognosis and because they often develop
             progressive neurologic dysfunction that would confound the evaluation of neurologic
             and other adverse events.

          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study

          -  Prior malignancy except for adequately-treated basal cell (or squamous cell) skin
             cancer, in situ cervical cancer, or other cancer for which the patient has been
             disease-free for three years.

          -  Patients with documented contraindication to anticoagulation therapy such as heparin
             induced thrombocytopenia or a documented coagulopathy or hematologic disorder that
             would contraindicated undergoing treatment and use of the associated anticoagulant
             agents required during treatment.

          -  Patients with documented active bacterial, viral or fungal infection, untreated
             systematic peptic ulcer disease, uncontrolled diabetes mellitus or serious concurrent
             medical disease that could limit survival to less than 3 months.

          -  HIV-positive patients on combination antiretroviral therapy are ineligible because of
             the potential for harm when exposed to hyperthermia, as well as negative interactions
             of these medications with hyperthermia.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeremiah Martin, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Lucille P. Markey Cancer Center at University of Kentucky</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jeremiah Martin, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>859-323-6494</phone>
    <email>j.martin@uky.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kevin W Hatton, MD</last_name>
    <email>kevin.hatton@uky.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kentucky, Markey Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lexington</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40536</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jeremiah Martin, MB BCh FRCSI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>November 30, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 17, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Kentucky</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jeremiah Martin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
