<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="112">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02496663</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2015-01053</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2015-01053</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PHI-77</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PhI-77</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>9898</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA033572</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UM1CA186717</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02496663</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EGFR Inhibitor AZD9291 and Necitumumab in Treating Patients With EGFR-Positive Stage IV or Recurrent Non-small Cell Lung Cancer Who Have Progressed on a Previous EGFR Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Trial of AZD9291 and Necitumumab in EGFR-Mutant Non-small Cell Lung Cancer After Progression on a Previous EGFR Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial studies the side effects and best dose of necitumumab when given together
      with epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) inhibitor AZD9291 (osimertinib) in treating
      patients with EGFR-positive non-small cell lung cancer that is stage IV or has come back
      (recurrent) and who have progressed on a previous EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor. Monoclonal
      antibodies, such as necitumumab, may block tumor growth in different ways by targeting
      certain cells. EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 may stop the growth of tumor cells by blocking some of
      the enzymes needed for cell growth. Giving necitumumab with EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 may be a
      better treatment for EGFR-mutant non-small cell lung cancer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To determine the safety and tolerability of AZD9291 (EGFR inhibitor AZD9291) in
      combination with necitumumab in patients with EGFR-mutant non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)
      and resistance to previous EGFR-tyrosine kinase inhibitor (EGFR-TKI) therapy.

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To observe and record anti-tumor activity in these NSCLC patients with EGFR-activating
      mutations and progressive disease on previous EGFR-TKI with a focus on an EGFR T790M
      negative expansion cohort.

      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To characterize the pharmacokinetics of AZD9291 in combination with necitumumab.

      II. To explore biomarkers of response and resistance to previous EGFR-TKIs and with the
      combination by studying biopsied tumor tissue at baseline and at progression, as well as
      serial plasma deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) specimens.

      III. To create patient derived xenograft (PDX) models of patients with EGFR-mutant NSCLC
      both prior to study initiation and at acquired resistance to treatment.

      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of necitumumab.

      Patients receive EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1-21 and
      necitumumab intravenously (IV) over 50 minutes on days 1 and 8. Courses repeat every 21 days
      in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 4 weeks, every 12 weeks for
      1 year, and annually thereafter.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2016</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of toxicity, graded according to the NCI CTCAE version 4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Grade and attribution will be summarized by dose level, cycle, organ system and type.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose of necitumumab combined with EGFR inhibitor AZD9291</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Defined as the highest dose tested in which only 0 or 1 out of 6 evaluable patients experience a dose limiting toxicity, as graded by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.0. The recommended phase II dose will be the MTD, pending review of other safety/tolerability considerations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate (DCR) with combination EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 and necitumumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>DCR will be the proportion of patients in the expansion cohort whose best confirmed response is CR, PR, or stable disease (SD). Point estimates and associated 90% confidence intervals will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) in patients treated at the recommended phase II dose, graded according to RECIST version 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>ORR will be calculated as the percent of patients in the expansion cohort whose best confirmed response is complete response (CR) or partial response (PR). Point estimates and associated 90% confidence intervals will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of treatment to time of progression or death, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Kaplan-Meier plots will be used to summarize the progression-free survival. Medians and associated 95% confidence intervals will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetic parameters of EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 in combination with necitumumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to dosing on day 1 of course 2, then again, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours after dosing in cycle</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The PK analyses will be descriptive and will permit comparison of the plasma levels of AZD9291 and its metabolites in the presence of Necitumumab (in this trial) with levels in other studies where AZD9291 is given alone or combined with other drugs. We will estimate mean PK parameters as well as the between-patient variability. Results will be listed and plotted, by dose as well as by objective response, qualitative patterns will be described, and means and standard deviations will be calculated for use in planning follow-up studies.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of biomarkers of response and resistance to previous EGFR-TKIs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Recurrent Non-Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EGFR inhibitor AZD9291, necitumumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive EGFR inhibitor AZD9291 PO QD on days 1-21 and necitumumab IV over 50 minutes on days 1 and 8. Courses repeat every 21 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EGFR inhibitor AZD9291, necitumumab)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Necitumumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EGFR inhibitor AZD9291, necitumumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Anti-Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Monoclonal Antibody IMC-11F8</other_name>
    <other_name>IMC-11F8</other_name>
    <other_name>Portrazza</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Osimertinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EGFR inhibitor AZD9291, necitumumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AZD-9291</other_name>
    <other_name>AZD9291</other_name>
    <other_name>Mereletinib</other_name>
    <other_name>Tagrisso</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pharmacological Study</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (EGFR inhibitor AZD9291, necitumumab)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with stage IV or recurrent/metastatic histologically confirmed non-squamous
             NSCLC

          -  NSCLC must harbor an EGFR activating mutation (Exon 21 L858R, Exon 19 deletion, Exon
             18 G719X, Exon 21 L861Q).

          -  Progressive disease on at least one prior EGFR-TKI (previous treatment with 3rd
             generation EGFR-TKI including AZD9291 allowed for dose escalation only)

          -  Adequate archival tissue from a biopsy performed after progression of disease on
             previous EGFR-TKI or willing to consent for a fresh tumor biopsy (mandatory for dose
             expansion cohort only; optional for dose escalation)

          -  For the dose expansion portion ONLY, patient must: 1) have progression of disease
             with erlotinib, gefitinib or afatinib as last previous systemic treatment, 2) tumors
             must be EGFR-T790M negative confirmed by central testing prior to treatment (If
             EGFR-T790M status is unknown patients may consent for trial for biopsy and testing
             for EGFR T790M will be performed as part of initial biopsy for trial; patients who
             test positive for EGFR T790M by central testing will be ineligible for the dose
             expansion), 3) be treatment naïve to 3rd generation EGFR-TKI (EGFR inhibitor CO-1686
             [CO-1686] and AZD9291) and EGFR monoclonal antibodies

          -  Patients must have measurable disease by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors
             (RECIST) 1.1, defined as at least one lesion that can be accurately measured in at
             least one dimension &gt;= 10 mm (&gt;= 1 cm) by computed tomography (CT) imaging or
             magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) within 42 days prior to registration; the CT from a
             combined positron emission tomography (PET)/CT may be used only if it is of
             diagnostic; laboratory parameters are not acceptable as the only evidence of disease

          -  Any number of prior therapies is allowed

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 2

          -  Life expectancy of greater 3 months

          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL

          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL

          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL

          -  Total bilirubin within normal institutional limits

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])
             =&lt; 2.5 × institutional upper limit of normal

          -  Creatinine within normal institutional limits OR

          -  Creatinine clearance &gt;= 50 mL/min/1.73 m^2 for patients with creatinine levels above
             institutional normal

          -  Women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception
             using one of the methods listed below prior to study entry, for the duration of study
             participation, and for 3 months for women and 6 months for men following the date of
             the last dose of AZD9291 and/or necitumumab:

               -  Total abstinence from sexual intercourse (minimum one complete menstrual cycle
                  prior to study drug administration)

               -  Vasectomized male subject or vasectomized partner of female subjects

               -  Hormonal contraceptives (oral, parenteral, transdermal or vaginal ring) prior to
                  study drug administration; if the subject is currently using a hormonal
                  contraceptive, she should also use a barrier method during this study and for 3
                  months after study completion

               -  Intrauterine device (IUD)

               -  Double-barrier method: male condom plus diaphragm or vaginal cap with spermicide
                  (contraceptive sponge, jellies or creams)

               -  Additionally, male subjects (including those who are vasectomized) whose
                  partners are pregnant or might be pregnant must agree to use condoms for the
                  duration of the study and for 6 months following completion of therapy

          -  Women of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test within 7
             days prior to initiation of treatment; women will be considered not of childbearing
             potential if they are surgically sterile (bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy)
             and/or post menopausal (amenorrheic for at least 12 months); should a woman become
             pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this
             study, she should inform her treating physician immediately

          -  Patients with a prior history of brain metastases are eligible provided:

               -  The brain metastases have been treated

               -  The patient is asymptomatic from the brain metastases

               -  Corticosteroids prescribed for the management of brain metastases have been
                  discontinued at least 7 days prior to registration

               -  The brain metastases are stable on pre-registration imaging

          -  Patients must have completed last chemotherapy &gt;= 3 weeks or radiotherapy &gt;= 2 weeks
             prior to receiving study drugs

          -  Patients must have recovered from adverse events attributable to previous treatment
             to =&lt; grade 1, except for alopecia and sensory neuropathy =&lt; grade 2

          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Major surgery within 21 days of starting protocol treatment

          -  Patients must discontinue previous EGFR-TKI at least 7 days prior to study enrollment

          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents

          -  Past medical history of interstitial lung disease, drug-induced interstitial lung
             disease, radiation pneumonitis requiring steroid treatment, or any evidence of
             clinically active interstitial lung disease

          -  Patients currently receiving (or unable to stop use prior to receiving the first dose
             of study treatment) medications or herbal supplements known to be potent inhibitors
             of cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A, polypeptide 4 (CYP3A4) (at least 1 week
             prior) and potent inducers of CYP3A4 (at least 3 weeks prior); all patients must try
             to avoid concomitant use of any medications, herbal supplements and/or ingestion of
             foods with known inducer/inhibitory effects of CYP3A4

          -  Patients with active malignancies other than NSCLC or prior curatively treated
             malignancy at high risk of relapse during the study period with the exception of
             localized squamous or basal cell skin cancers

          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac
             arrhythmia, gastrointestinal disease limiting absorption of AZD9291 such as a
             malabsorption syndrome or inflammatory bowel disease or psychiatric illness/social
             situations that would limit compliance with study requirements

          -  Mean resting corrected QT interval (QTc using Fridericia's formula [QTcF]) &gt; 470 msec

          -  Any clinically important abnormalities in rhythm, conduction or morphology of resting
             electrocardiography (ECG) (e.g., complete left bundle branch block, third degree
             heart block, second degree heart block)

          -  Congenital long QT syndrome or family history of long QT syndrome

          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study; breastfeeding should be discontinued if
             the mother is treated with AZD9291 and necitumumab

          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-positive patients on combination antiretroviral
             therapy are ineligible
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan Riess</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beckman Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope Comprehensive Cancer Center LAO</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan W. Riess</last_name>
      <phone>916-734-7946</phone>
      <email>jonathan.riess@ucdmc.ucdavis.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jonathan W. Riess</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan W. Riess</last_name>
      <phone>916-734-3772</phone>
      <email>jwriess@ucdavis.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jonathan W. Riess</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Davis Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95817</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan W. Riess</last_name>
      <phone>916-734-7946</phone>
      <email>jwriess@ucdavis.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jonathan W. Riess</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 6, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>July 9, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cetuximab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osimertinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
