<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="201">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02254512</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>090-13</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02254512</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>METformin With a Cargohydrate Restricted Diet in Combination With Platinum Based Chemotherapy in Stage IIIB/IV Non-squamous Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>METformin With a Carbohydrate Restricted Diet in Combination With Platinum Based Chemotherapy in Stage IIIB/IV Non-squamous Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NS-NSCLC) - METRO Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beth Israel Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beth Israel Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Subjects, who are eligible for the study, will be treated with four cycles of carboplatin
      AUC of 5 IV and pemetrexed 500mg/m2 IV every 21 days +/- 2 days as per the standard of care.
      Subjects who have not progressed after four cycles by radiological assessment (partial
      response or stable disease) will receive single agent pemetrexed 500mg/m2 IV q 21 days +/- 2
      days as maintenance therapy and as the standard of care until disease progression or subject
      cannot tolerate.

      Metformin will be given as 500 mg pills starting on day 1 of chemotherapy. Starting dose
      will 500mg po bid (1000mg/day). If tolerating (see below for dose reduction), the dose will
      be escalated to 1000mg po qam and 500mg po qpm (1500mg/day) from days 8 to 14. If still
      tolerating, the dose will be escalated to 2 500mg pills twice a day for a total dose of
      2000mg/day from days 15 until end of the study. This dose has been found to be safe in
      healthy controls and in subjects treated with chemotherapy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Metformin, an oral biguanide agent used for the treatment of non-insulin-dependent diabetes
      mellitus, is now prescribed to more than 120 million people worldwide. Its glucose lowering
      effects result from both inhibition of liver gluconeogenesis and increased insulin
      sensitivity in peripheral tissue[5]. Metformin has limited adverse effects with little or no
      risk of hypoglycemia in healthy, nondiabetic controls. In addition to its anti-diabetic
      properties, metformin has demonstrated both chemopreventative and therapeutic effects in
      both prostate and breast cancer.

      The role of metformin as a preventative and therapeutic agent in lung cancer is beginning to
      be assessed. A recent epidemiological study from Taiwan demonstrated a 39-45% decreased risk
      of lung cancer in diabetic patients being treated with antidiabetic drugs including
      metformin versus those not taking these agents[12]. These studies have triggered preclinical
      and clinical observational trials that further support metformin's potential as an
      antineoplastic agent. Two observational studies in humans have reinforced metformin's
      potential role as a therapeutic agent in lung cancer. In the first, Mezzone et al. showed
      that diabetic patients with lung cancer previously treated with metformin or
      thiazolidinediones had a lower incidence of metastatic disease at the time of diagnosis and
      a reduced risk of death compared to those who did not receive the same treatment[15]. More
      recently, a retrospective study performed by Tan et al. evaluated the outcomes of three
      groups of diabetic patients with NSCLC treated with first line chemotherapy and receiving
      various diabetic drugs. In this study, patients treated with chemotherapy with metformin had
      superior outcomes compared to those patients treated with chemotherapy with insulin or with
      drugs other than metformin (OS, 20 months vs. 13.1 months vs 13.0 months, respectively,
      p=0.007)[16]. The remarkable activity of this agent in both preclinical and clinical lung
      cancer models as well as its low toxicity and tolerability in non- diabetic patients
      warrants further prospective studies evaluating the therapeutic efficacy with platinum based
      chemotherapy in NSCLC.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the safety and efficacy (progression free survival)</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months, up to March 2017 (anticipated)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>To determine the safety and efficacy (progression free survival) of metformin and a carbohydrate restricted diet in addition to standard platinum-pemetrexed based chemotherapy for advanced stage (IIIB/IV) non-squamous, non-small cell lung cancer subjects (NS-NSCLC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the overall survival of subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months, up to March 2017 (anticipated)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>To determine the overall survival of subjects treated with metformin and a carbohydrate restricted diet in addition to standard platinum-pemetrexed based chemotherapy for advanced stage IIIB/IV non-sqaumous cell lung cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate LKBI mutations as a potential biomarker</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months, up to March 2017 (anticipated)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>To evaluate LKBI mutations as a potential biomarker to predict subjects who will benefit most from metformin in combination with a carbohydrate restricted diet</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate tolerability in fasting serum glucose, insulin levels and subject BMI</measure>
    <time_frame>48 months, up to March 2017 (anticipated)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>To evaluate baseline and changes in fasting serum glucose, insulin levels and subject BMI during treatment as potential host makers to predict clinical outcomes from this intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Non-squamous Non-small-cell Lung</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin+Carboplatin+Pemetrexed</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Metformin total 1000mg/day on days 1-7, total 1500mg/day on days 8-14, and total 2000mg/day on day 15 until PD.
Carboplatin AUC of 5, IV day 1 of every 21 days times 4 cycles. Pemetrexed 500 mg/m2, IV day 1 of every 21 days until PD.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Metformin</intervention_name>
    <description>Metformin by mouth twice daily with meals</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin+Carboplatin+Pemetrexed</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Glucophage</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carboplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>Carboplatin AUC of 5, IV day 1 of every 21 days times 4 cycles</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin+Carboplatin+Pemetrexed</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pemetrexed</intervention_name>
    <description>Pemetrexed 500 mg/m2, IV day 1 of every 21 days until PD</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin+Carboplatin+Pemetrexed</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Alimta</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  • Able to provide written consent and is amenable to compliance with protocol
             schedules and testing

               -  Subject is &gt; 18 years of age

               -  Pathologically proven (either histologic or cytologic) diagnosis of Stage IIIB
                  or IV non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer

               -  No prior, palliative chemotherapy for stage IV lung cancer Subjects who have
                  received adjuvant chemotherapy post surgery for curative intent more than 12
                  months prior to development of stage IV disease are allowed.

               -  Measurable disease as RECIST criteria 1.1 (Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid
                  Tumors, Version 1.1)

               -  CT Scan of the chest/abdomen/pelvis or PET Scan within 30 days of study entry

               -  An MRI of the brain or Head CT Scan with contrast within 30 days of study entry
                  if clinically indicated

               -  ECOG Performance Status 0-2.

               -  CBC/differential obtained within 2 weeks prior to registration on study, with
                  adequate bone marrow function defined as follows:

                    -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;1,500 cells/ul

                    -  Platelets &gt; 100,000 cells/ul

                    -  Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 g/dl (Note: The use of transfusion or other intervention
                       to achieve Hgb &gt; g/dl is acceptable.)

               -  Serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 x ULN

               -  Total bilirubin &lt; 2.0 times the institutional Upper Limit of Normal (ULN)

               -  AST and ALT &lt; 3.0 x the ULN

               -  Women of childbearing potential must have:

                    -  A negative serum or urine pregnancy test (sensitivity &lt;/=25IU HCG/L) within
                       14 days prior to the start of study drug administration

                    -  Persons of reproductive potential must agree to use and utilize an adequate
                       method of contraception throughout treatment and for at least 90 days after
                       study drug is stopped prior to study enrollment, women of childbearing
                       potential must be advised of the importance of avoiding pregnancy during
                       trial participation and the potential risk factors for an unintentional
                       pregnancy.

               -  Ability to take oral medication

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  • The subject has a diagnosis of squamous cell carcinoma. Adenosquamous (mixed)
             histologies are allowed

               -  The subject has a history of type I or type II diabetes

               -  Weight of less than 80% of (IBW) ideal body weight

               -  Creatinine clearance less than 45 l/min as calculated by the Cockcroft-Gault
                  equation

               -  Known EGFR or ALK mutation in which targeted therapy with erlotinib or
                  crizotinib would be the standard of care. Those subjects whose tissue is not
                  tested or have insufficient material are eligible

               -  The subject is currently taking or has previously taken metformin in the past 6
                  months

               -  The subject has received previous chemotherapy for NSCLC except in instances of
                  adjuvant therapy post surgical resection more than 12 months prior to enrollment

               -  The subject has undergone major surgery within four weeks prior to
                  randomization.

               -  The subject has undergone palliative radiation (chest, brain) to tumor sites
                  within two weeks of randomization (except palliative radiation to the bone which
                  can be within one week

               -  Uncontrolled (untreated) brain metastasis.

               -  Subject who has NCI-CTCAE Version 4 Grade &gt; 2 diarrhea

               -  That subject has clinically relevant CAD or uncontrolled CHF

               -  The subject has ongoing or active infection (requiring antibiotics) that would
                  limit the administration of chemotherapy including active TB. HIV is allowed in
                  this study

               -  The subject has a history of neurological or psychological disorder that may
                  interfere with the compliance of the protocol

               -  Women who are unwilling or unable to use an acceptable method to avoid pregnancy
                  for the entire study period and for at least 4 weeks after cessation of study
                  drug, or have a positive pregnancy test at baseline, or are pregnant or
                  breastfeeding
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Benjamin Levy, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mount Sinai Beth Israel</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Benjamin Levy, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-604-6017</phone>
    <email>belevy@chpnet.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tiffany Xing</last_name>
    <phone>212-367-0190</phone>
    <email>txing@chpnet.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Beth Israel Phillips Ambulatory Care Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10003</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rotsen Rocha</last_name>
      <phone>212-844-8133</phone>
      <email>rrocha@chpnet.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Peter Kozuch, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Moun Sinai Beth Israel Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10011</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tiffany Xing</last_name>
      <phone>212-367-0190</phone>
      <email>txing@chpnet.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Zujun Li, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Roosevelt</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10019</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tahir Mirzoyev</last_name>
      <phone>212-523-7289</phone>
      <email>tmirzoye@chpnet.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 21, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>September 25, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>non-squamous</keyword>
  <keyword>non-small cell</keyword>
  <keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>metformin</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pemetrexed</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
