<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="603">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02734004</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D081KC00001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2015-004005-16</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02734004</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase I/II Study of MEDI4736 in Combination With Olaparib in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors.</brief_title>
  <acronym>MEDIOLA</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II Study of MEDI4736 (Anti-PD-L1 Antibody) in Combination With Olaparib (PARP Inhibitor) in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Quintiles, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AstraZeneca</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>United Kingdom: Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency</authority>
    <authority>France: National Agency for the Safety of Medicine &amp; Health Products</authority>
    <authority>Netherlands: Central Committee on Research Involving Human Subjects</authority>
    <authority>Switzerland: Swissmedic</authority>
    <authority>Israel: State of Israel Ministry of Health</authority>
    <authority>South Korea: Ministry of Food and Drug Safety</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to look at the effectiveness, safety, and antitumor activity of
      study drugs MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib. It will also examine what happens to the
      study drugs in the body and investigate how well the combination between MEDI4736 and
      olaparib is tolerated.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase I/II open-label, multicenter study to evaluate the safety, tolerability,
      pharmacokinetics (PK) and antitumor activity of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib in
      patients with advanced solid tumors, selected based on a rationale for response to olaparib.

      Patients will be poly (adenosine diphosphate-ribose) polymerase (PARP)-inhibitor and
      immunotherapy (IMT)-naïve (defined as no prior exposure to PARP inhibitors or IMT,
      including, but not limited to, other anti-cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-associated protein 4
      [CTLA-4], anti-programmed cell death 1 [PD-1], anti-programmed death-ligand 1 [PD-L1]
      monoclonal antibodies, or any other antibody or drug specifically targeting T-cell
      co-stimulation or checkpoint pathways).

      Initially, patients will be enrolled concurrently into 4 exploratory cohorts, which will
      include patients with relapsed Small cell lung cancer (SCLC), Germline mutated breast cancer
      susceptibility gene (gBRCAm) metastatic human epidermal growth factor receptor 2
      (HER2)-negative breast cancer, gBRCAm platinum-sensitive relapsed ovarian cancer, and Ataxia
      telangiectasia mutated (ATM)-negative gastric cancer. Additional tumor types may be added at
      a later date based on emerging data. The results from this study will form decision-making
      for future studies.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate (DCR) [Complete response + Partial response + Stable disease (CR+PR+SD)] based on modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 weeks, compared to Baseline</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessments will be performed using CT/MRI assessments of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The safety and tolerability of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib by assessment of the number and grade of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening up to 90 days after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Adverse events defined according to Common Terminology for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v4.03</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The safety and tolerability of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib by assessment of the number of participants with adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening up to 90 days after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Adverse events defined according to CTCAE v4.03</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The safety and tolerability of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib by assessment of the number and grade of immune-related adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening up to 90 days after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Adverse events defined according to CTCAE v4.03</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The safety and tolerability of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib by assessment of the number of participants with immune-related adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening up to 90 days after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Adverse events defined according to CTCAE v4.03</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The safety and tolerability of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib by assessment of physical examination</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening up to 30 days after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessments of general appearance, head, eyes, ears, nose and throat; and the respiratory, cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, breast, urogenital, musculoskeletal, neurological, dermatological, hematologic/lymphatic and endocrine systems will be performed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The safety and tolerability of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib by assessment of vital signs</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening up to 30 days after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessments of blood pressure, pulse, temperature, respiratory rate and electrocardiogram tests will be performed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The safety and tolerability of MEDI4736 in combination with olaparib by assessment of blood samples</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening up to 90 days after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Laboratory assessments of blood samples for hematology and coagulation variables, plus clinical chemistry parameters will be performed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PD-L1 expression in serum samples</measure>
    <time_frame>Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 15 of cycle 1; Day 1 of cycle 3; Day 1 of cycle 5; Day 1 of cycle 7; 3 month Follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Samples will be measured for the presence of sPD-L1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate (DCR) [Complete response + Partial response + Stable disease (CR+PR+SD)] based on modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>At 28 weeks, compared to Baseline</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessments will be performed using CT/MRI assessments of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to study treatment discontinuation (TDT)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Cycle 1, Day 1 up to 52 weeks.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time of study treatment discontinuation or death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From Cycle 1, Day 1 until death or up to 52 weeks.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time from start of Olaparib treatment until death due to any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage change from baseline in tumor size</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 weeks and 28 weeks compared to Baseline</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessments will be performed using CT/MRI assessments of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best percentage change from baseline in tumor size</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline, at 4 weeks and every 8 weeks thereafter up to 52 weeks.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Assessments will be performed using CT/MRI assessments of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum concentrations of anti-drug antibody (ADA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 15 of cycle 1; Day 1 of cycle 3; Day 1 of cycle 5; Day 1 of cycle 7; 3 month Follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Samples will be measured for the presence of MEDI4736 ADAs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Olaparib pharamacokinetic sample</measure>
    <time_frame>Olaparib Run-In treatment week 1 day 1; Olaparib Run-In treatment week 4 day 1; Day 15 of Cycle 1</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Samples will be collected for determination of Olaparib levels in plasma</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MEDI4736 pharmacokinetic sample</measure>
    <time_frame>Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 15 of cycle 1; Day 1 of cycle 3; Day 1 of cycle 5; Day 1 of cycle 7; 3 month Follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Samples will be collected for determination of MEDI4736 levels in plasma</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (Complete response+Partial response) based on modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline, at 4 weeks and every 8 weeks thereafter up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response based on modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline, at 4 weeks and every 8 weeks thereafter up to 52 weeks.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS based on modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>From Baseline, at 4 weeks and every 8 weeks thereafter up to 52 weeks.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor genetics</measure>
    <time_frame>At Screening</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>To determine presence of homologous recombination repair (BRCA1, BRCA2) ATM and overall mutation burden</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamics: Paired tumor biopsies</measure>
    <time_frame>Olaparib Run-In Treatment week 1 day1. Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 1 of Cycle 2</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Tumor samples will be analyzed for biomarkers including CD8 expressing T cells, PD-L1 expression, measures of T-cell repertoire, gene expression and markers associated with immunogenic cell death</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamics: whole blood for gene expression (PAXgene-RNA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Olaparib Run-In Treatment week 1 day 1. Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 1 of Cycle 2; Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamics: circulating soluble factors in the plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Olaparib Run-In Treatment week 1 day 1. Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 1 of Cycle 2; Day 1 of Cycle 3; Day 1 of Cycle 6</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The concentrations of a panel of cytokines and chemokines will be assessed.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamics: whole blood for immunophenotyping</measure>
    <time_frame>Screening. Olaparib Run-In Treatment week 1 day 1. Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 15 of Cycle 1; Day 1 of Cycle 2; Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Whole blood samples will be collected for flow cytometry-based immunophenotyping of circulating lymphocytes</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamics: peripheral blood mononuclear cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Olaparib Run-In treatment week 1 day 1. Olaparib Run-In treatment week 3 day 1. Each cycle = 28 days in combination of treatment. Day 1 of cycle 1; Day 15 of Cycle 1; Day 1 of Cycle 2; Day 1 of Cycle 3</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Whole blood samples will be collected for preparation of PBMCs and storage for potential downstream analyses.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacogenetics</measure>
    <time_frame>Olaparib Run-In treatment week 1 day 1</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Optional: patient consent required to collect and store DNA from blood (according to each country's local and ethical procedures) for future exploratory research into genes/genetic variation that may influence response (ie, distribution, safety, tolerability and efficacy) to study treatments and or susceptibility to disease (optional)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">141</enrollment>
  <condition>Ovarian</condition>
  <condition>Breast</condition>
  <condition>SCLC</condition>
  <condition>Gastric Cancers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1: Olaparib / MEDI4736</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Olaparib PO 300mg BID starting on week 1 day 1 / MEDI4736 IV 1.5g every 4 weeks starting on week 5 day 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olaparib</intervention_name>
    <description>Olaparib</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1: Olaparib / MEDI4736</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MEDI4736</intervention_name>
    <description>MEDI4736 starting 4 weeks after Olaparib</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1: Olaparib / MEDI4736</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed progressive advanced or
        metastatic solid tumor of one of the following:

          -  Relapsed gBRCAm ovarian cancer

          -  gBRCAm HER2-negative metastatic breast cancer

          -  Relapsed small cell lung cancer

          -  Advanced ATM-negative gastric cancer At least one measureable lesion

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Patients may not enter the study if any of the following exclusion criteria are met. To
        perform Breast cancer susceptibility gene (BRCA) testing, investigator judgment of
        patient's potential eligibility to the study should be assessed and by reviewing the
        exclusion criteria listed immediately below.

          -  Prior chemotherapy or other systemic anticancer therapy within 4 weeks prior to start
             of olaparib treatment, 6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin.

          -  Radiation therapy within 4 weeks prior to start of olaparib or radionuclide treatment
             within 6 weeks.

          -  Receipt of live attenuated vaccination within 30 days of treatment with MEDI4736.

          -  Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 14 days before first dose
             of MEDI4736.

          -  Current dependency on total parenteral nutrition or IV fluid hydration.

          -  Concurrent use of any medications or substances that are strong inhibitors of
             cytochrome P450.

          -  Concomitant therapy with any other anticancer therapy or chronic use of systemic
             corticosteroids.

          -  Patients requiring long-acting narcotic analgesics, unless on stable regiment with
             adequate pain control for at least 14 days prior to olaparib run-in treatment.

          -  Previous allogenic bone marrow transplant or double umbilical cord blood
             transplantation.

          -  Whole blood transfusions within 120 days.

          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds similar to MEDI4736 or
             olaparib.

          -  Persistent toxicities (CTCAE grade ≥2) caused by previous cancer therapy, excluding
             alopecia.

          -  Other malignancy within last 5 years except treated non-melanoma skin cancer, in situ
             cancer of cervix, ductal carcinoma in situ, Stage/grade 1 endometrial carcinoma,
             other solid tumors.

          -  History of leptomeningeal carcinomatosis.

          -  Known brain metastases or spinal cord compression.

          -  Patient being considered poor medical risk due to serious, uncontrolled medical
             disorder, non-malignant systemic disease or active, uncontrolled seizures or active
             uncontrolled infection.

          -  Known drug or alcohol abuse.

          -  Any psychiatric disorder that prohibits informed consent.

          -  Major surgery or significant traumatic injury within 2 weeks of run-in.

          -  Immunocompromised patients.

          -  Hepatitis B Virus or Hepatitis C virus-positivity.

          -  Active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disorders within 3 years
             (excluding vitiligo, alopecia and hypothyroidism).

          -  Known history of anaphylaxis, angioedema, laryngeal edema, serum sickness, or
             uncontrolled asthma.

          -  QTc prolongation &gt;470msec or other significant ECG abnormality within 14 days.

          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding women.

          -  Involvement in planning or conduct of study.

          -  Previous enrolment.

          -  Participation in a clinical study within 28 days or 5 half-lives, whichever is
             longer.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>130 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan Domcheck, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Abramson Cancer Center, University of Pennsylvania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>AstraZeneca Clinical Study Information Center</last_name>
    <phone>1-877-240-9479</phone>
    <email>information.center@astrazeneca.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Angela Sawyer</last_name>
    <phone>44 7775 820899</phone>
    <email>angela.sawyer@astrazeneca.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newnan</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Novi</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>St Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille Cedex</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>MARSEILLE Cedex 5</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pierre Benite Cedex</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse Cedex 9</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif Cedex</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ramat Gan</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tel Aviv</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seongnam-si</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maastricht</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chur</city>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lausanne</city>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sutton</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 31, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 17, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>MEDIOLA</keyword>
  <keyword>Olaparib</keyword>
  <keyword>MEDI4736</keyword>
  <keyword>Ovarian cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastric Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase I/II, Adults</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olaparib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
