<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="124">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02635009</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NRG-CC003</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2015-01548</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NRG-CC003</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NRG-CC003</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UG1CA189867</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02635009</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Whole-Brain Radiation Therapy With or Without Hippocampal Avoidance in Treating Patients With Limited Stage or Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Phase II/III Trial of Prophylactic Cranial Irradiation With or Without Hippocampal Avoidance for Small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NRG Oncology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Radiation Therapy Oncology Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NRG Oncology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This randomized phase II/III trial studies how well whole-brain radiation therapy works and
      compares it with or without hippocampal avoidance in treating patients with small cell lung
      cancer that is found in one lung, the tissues between the lungs, and nearby lymph nodes only
      (limited stage) or has spread outside of the lung in which it began or to other parts of the
      body (extensive stage). Radiation therapy uses high energy x-rays to kill tumor cells and
      shrink tumors. The hippocampus is part of the brain that is important for memory. Avoiding
      the hippocampus during whole-brain radiation could decrease the chance of side effects on
      memory and thinking. It is not yet known whether giving whole-brain radiation therapy is
      more effective with or without hippocampal avoidance in treating patients with small cell
      lung cancer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Determine whether the 12-month intracranial relapse rate following hippocampal avoidance
      (HA)-prophylactic cranial irradiation (PCI) is non-inferior compared to the rate following
      PCI for patients with small cell lung cancer (SCLC). (Randomized Phase II Component
      [Non-Inferiority]) II. Determine whether HA-PCI reduces the likelihood of 6-month
      deterioration from baseline in Hopkins Verbal Learning Test (HVLT)-Revised (R) delayed
      recall compared to PCI for patients with SCLC. (Phase III Component [Efficacy])

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Compare time to cognitive failure, as measured by a battery of tests (HVLT-R, Controlled
      Oral Word Association [COWA] test, and Trail Making Test [TMT] parts A and B), after PCI
      versus HA-PCI in SCLC.

      II. Compare time to cognitive failure as separately measured by each test (HVLT-R for Total
      Recall and Delayed Recognition, COWA test, and TMT parts A and B), after PCI versus HA-PCI
      for SCLC.

      III. Compare patient-reported cognitive functioning and other quality of life domains
      (assessed by the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer [EORTC] Quality
      of Life Questionnaire [QLQ]-Core [C]30 and BN20) between PCI versus HA-PCI for patients with
      SCLC.

      IV. Compare overall survival after PCI versus HA-PCI for patients with SCLC. V. Compare
      12-month intracranial relapse rate (at completion of phase III) and time to intracranial
      relapse after PCI versus HA-PCI for patients with SCLC.

      VI. Evaluate adverse events according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events
      (CTCAE) criteria.

      VII. Correlate changes in health-related quality of life (HRQOL) domains with changes in
      cognitive testing outcomes following PCI versus HA-PCI for patients with SCLC.

      VIII. Assess cost-effectiveness of HA-PCI (intensity modulated radiation therapy [IMRT]) and
      PCI (3-dimensional conformal radiation therapy [3DCRT]) using the EuroQual (EQ)-5-Dimensions
      (5D)-5L.

      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Collect serum, whole blood, and urine for future translational research analyses.

      II. Evaluate baseline magnetic resonance (MR) imaging biomarkers of white matter injury and
      hippocampal volumetry as potential predictors of cognitive decline and differential benefit
      from HAPCI as compared to PCI.

      OUTLINE: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 treatment arms.

      ARM I: Patients undergo PCI using 3DCRT daily for 2 weeks.

      ARM II: Patients undergo PCI with HA using IMRT daily for 2 weeks.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed every 3 months for 1 year, then
      every 6 months until 3 years and then annually until death.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2015</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HVLT-R delayed recall deterioration status, defined using the Reliable Change Index (RCI) (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months from start of treatment</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Compared using Fisher's exact test at a significance level of 0.05.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracranial relapse rate (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>It will be compared between arms using a binomial test of difference in proportions at a significance level of 0.1. If the rate of relapse in the HA-PCI arm is significantly greater than that of the PCI only arm, this study will not continue to the phase III portion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost-effectiveness as measured by the EQ-5D (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Quality-adjusted life years (QALY's) will be assessed as the area under the preference-weighted survival curve. Cost will be assessed using a societal perspective. The primary cost-effectiveness outcome will be the pooled incremental cost-per QALY ratio for HA-PCI versus standard PCI. The incremental cost per QALY ratio will be calculated as the total cost of the HA-PCI minus total cost of standard PCI which will be divided by the quality adjusted survival of the patients treated with HA-PCI minus the quality adjusted survival of patients receiving standard PCI.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events (AEs), as measured by the CTCAE v.4 (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Counts of all AEs by grade will be provided by treatment arm. Counts and frequencies will be provided for the worst grade AE experienced by the patient by treatment arm.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracranial relapse rate (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The occurrence of intracranial relapse will be defined as appearance of brain metastasis in brain. Cumulative incidence approach will be used to estimate the median time to intracranial relapse to account for the competing risk of death. Gray's test will be used to test for statistically significant difference in the distribution of intracranial relapse times. Cause-specific Cox proportional hazards regression model will be used to evaluate effect of stratification variables (age, stage, and planned concurrent memantine use) and other baseline characteristics, on time to intracranial relapse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of randomization to the date of death, or, otherwise, the last follow-up date on which the patient was reported alive, assessed up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method and differences between treatment arms will be tested using the log rank test. The Cox proportional hazard model will be performed with the stratification variables and other baseline characteristics as fixed variables to assess the treatment effect while adjusting for patient-specific risk factors.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported HRQOL, as measured by the EORTC QLQ-C30 and BN20 (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Correlation of changes in HRQOL domains measured by the EORTC QLQ-C30 and BN20 with changes in cognitive function will be assessed. Additionally cognitive function decline at 3, 6, 12, 18 and 24 months will also be assessed and compared using Fisher's exact test. Decline from baseline to each time point (3, 6, 12, 18, and 24 months from the start of treatment) in the following subscales will also be assessed and compared using Fisher's exact test: global QOL, physical functioning, role functioning, emotional functioning, and social functioning domains along with fatigue and pain items.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preservation of neurocognitive function, as measured by neurocognitive decline for HVLT-R, COWA test, TMT Parts A and B, and Clinical Trial Battery Composite (CTB COMP) score (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Standardized scores that adjust for age, education, and gender when necessary will be analyzed. For discrete time point analyses, the change from baseline to each follow-up time point (3, 6, 12, 18, and 24 months from the start of treatment) will be calculated and compared between treatment arms using a t-test or Wilcoxon-Mann- Whitney test, depending on the normality of the data. Neurocognitive decline using the RCI for the HVLT-R, COWA, and TMT also will be compared between treatment arms at each follow-up time point using Fisher's exact test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to neurocognitive failure, where a failure is defined using the RCI criteria, as measured by HVLT-R, COWA test, and TMT Parts A and B (Phase III)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The cumulative incidence approach will be used to estimate the median time to neurocognitive failure to account for the competing risk of death. Gray's test will be used to test for statistically significant difference in the distribution of neurocognitive failure times. The cause-specific Cox proportional hazards regression model will be used to evaluate the effect of stratification variables (age, stage, and planned concurrent memantine use) and other baseline characteristics, on time to neurocognitive decline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>White matter injury and hippocampal volume on neurocognitive function</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The change from baseline to 6 months will be compared between arms using the t-test (or Wilcoxon test if not normally distributed) in the total score and the two subscale scores (agency and pathway). These scores will be correlated with the EORTC- QLQ-C30 total score using a Pearson correlation coefficient. A general linear model will be used to assess hopefulness, performed separately for the AHS total score and subscale scores, between treatment arms while adjusting for depression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">304</enrollment>
  <condition>Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Limited Stage Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (PCI using 3DCRT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo PCI using 3DCRT daily for 2 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (PCI with HA using IMRT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo PCI with HA using IMRT daily for 2 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>3-Dimensional Conformal Radiation Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo PCI using 3DCRT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (PCI using 3DCRT)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>3-dimensional radiation therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>3D-CRT</other_name>
    <other_name>Conformal Therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Radiation Conformal Therapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (PCI using 3DCRT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (PCI with HA using IMRT)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intensity-Modulated Radiation Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo PCI with HA using IMRT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (PCI with HA using IMRT)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>IMRT</other_name>
    <other_name>Intensity Modulated RT</other_name>
    <other_name>Intensity-Modulated Radiotherapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (PCI using 3DCRT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (PCI with HA using IMRT)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quality-of-Life Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (PCI using 3DCRT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (PCI with HA using IMRT)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Quality of Life Assessment</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  PRIOR TO STEP 1 REGISTRATION

          -  Histologic proof or unequivocal cytologic proof (fine needle aspiration, biopsy or
             two positive sputa) of SCLC within 250 days prior to Step 1 registration

          -  Patients must have a three-dimensional (3D), T1-weighted, spoiled gradient (SPGR),
             magnetization-prepared rapid gradient echo (MP-RAGE), or turbo field echo (TFE) MRI
             scan without and with gadolinium contrast-enhanced T1-weighted axial, coronal, and
             sagittal sequence acquisitions and standard T2-weighted axial and coronal fluid
             attenuation inversion recovery (FLAIR) sequence acquisitions within 28 days of Step 1
             registration; to yield acceptable image quality, the pre-contrast-enhanced should
             have a resolution of 1 x 1 x 1.2 mm and should follow the protocols established by
             the Alzheimer's Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (ADNI); performance of this sequence
             at a 3 Tesla field strength is recommended; sites may contact the Imaging Co-Chair,
             Dr. Tammie Benzinger, for further information or assistance if needed; to yield
             acceptable image quality, the gadolinium contrast-enhanced T1-weighted scan should
             use the smallest possible axial slice thickness not exceeding 1.5 mm; the associated
             coronal and sagittal sequences can be up to 2.5 mm in slice thickness; this imaging
             is considered standard of care

          -  Note: The MRI study as part of response assessment following chemotherapy can be used
             for this purpose, but the appropriate sequences must be obtained; this sequence
             cannot be obtained prior to chemotherapy and is mandatory irrespective of
             randomization to the experimental or control arm of this study

          -  Patients must sign a study-specific informed consent prior to study entry

          -  PRIOR TO STEP 2 REGISTRATION

          -  The following baseline neurocognitive assessments must be completed within 14 days
             prior to Step 2 registration: HVLT-R, TMT, and COWA; the neurocognitive assessments
             will be uploaded into the National Surgical Adjuvant Breast and Bowel Project,
             Radiation Therapy Oncology Group, and Gynecologic Oncology Group (NRG) Oncology RAVE
             system for evaluation by Dr. Wefel; once the upload is complete, a notification will
             be sent to the site to proceed to Step 2; note: completed baseline neurocognitive
             assessments can be uploaded at the time of Step 1 registration

          -  Patients must have a baseline raw score greater than 2 on the HVLT-R delayed recall

          -  Prior to chemotherapy or thoracic radiotherapy, patients must be defined as
             limited-stage or extensive-stage SCLC after clinical staging evaluation involving the
             following:

               -  History/physical examination;

               -  Computed tomography (CT) of the chest and abdomen with contrast (does not have
                  to be done if the patient has had a positron emission tomography (PET)/CT scan
                  within 8 weeks prior to initiating chemotherapy or thoracic radiotherapy)

               -  MRI of the brain

               -  For patients without evidence of extensive-stage SCLC on chest and abdomen CT
                  and brain MRI, a PET/CT or bone scan is required to confirm limited-stage SCLC

          -  Patients must be registered on study no earlier than 1 week and no later than 8 weeks
             after completing chemotherapy (+/- thoracic radiotherapy)

          -  After chemotherapy, patients must be restaged using the same diagnostic work-up as
             required pre-chemotherapy; repeat PET/CT or bone scan is not required; patients must
             have:

               -  No central nervous system (CNS) metastases

               -  Radiographic partial or complete response to chemotherapy in at least one
                  disease site using Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST)
                  criteria

               -  No progression in any site

          -  Zubrod performance status 0-2

          -  Women of childbearing potential and male participants must practice adequate
             contraception

          -  Women of childbearing potential must have a negative qualitative serum pregnancy test
             =&lt; 2 weeks prior to study entry

          -  Patients who are primary English or French speakers are eligible

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Prior radiotherapy to the head or neck (except for T1 glottic cancer), resulting in
             overlap of radiation fields

          -  Radiographic evidence of CNS metastases

          -  Radiographic evidence of hydrocephalus

          -  Planned concurrent chemotherapy or anti-tumor agent during PCI

          -  Concomitant invasive malignancy or invasive malignancy within the past five years
             other than non-melanomatous skin cancer; history of in situ carcinoma (e.g. ductal
             carcinoma in situ of breast, in situ carcinoma of the cervix, vulva or larynx) is
             permitted

          -  Contraindication to MR imaging, such as implanted metal devices or foreign bodies or
             severe claustrophobia

          -  Severe, active comorbidity, defined as follows:

               -  Unstable angina and/or congestive heart failure requiring hospitalization within
                  the last 6 months

               -  Transmural myocardial infarction within the last 6 months

               -  Acute bacterial or fungal infection requiring intravenous antibiotics at the
                  time of registration

               -  Hepatic insufficiency resulting in clinical jaundice and/or coagulation defects

               -  Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbation or other respiratory illness
                  requiring hospitalization or precluding study therapy at the time of
                  registration

               -  Uncontrolled, clinically significant cardiac arrhythmias

          -  Women of childbearing potential and male participants who are sexually active and not
             willing/able to use medically acceptable forms of contraception
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vinai Gondi</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NRG Oncology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cadence Cancer Center in Warrenville</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warrenville</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60555</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vinai Gondi</last_name>
      <phone>630-352-5350</phone>
      <email>vgondi@chicagocancer.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Vinai Gondi</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Minesh P. Mehta</last_name>
      <phone>410-328-6921</phone>
      <email>mmehta@umm.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Minesh P. Mehta</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Upper Chesapeake Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bel Air</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21014</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mark Mishra, MD</last_name>
      <phone>410-328-6080</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Mishra, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 16, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 16, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
