<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="60">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02013219</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WP29158</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2013-004382-13</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02013219</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 1b Study of Atezolizumab in Combination With Erlotinib or Alectinib in Participants With Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b Study of the Safety and Pharmacology of MPDL3280A Administered With Erlotinib or Alectinib in Patients With Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hoffmann-La Roche</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hoffmann-La Roche</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This open-label, multicenter study will assess the safety, tolerability, and
      pharmacokinetics of intravenous (IV) dosing of MPDL3280A (Atezolizumab) in combination with
      oral erlotinib or alectinib in participants with non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC).

      This study has two stages. In the erlotinib group, the combination treatment will be given
      to participants with epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) tyrosine kinase inhibitor
      (TKI)-treatment-naive, advanced (non-resectable) NSCLC in a safety-evaluation stage and to
      participants with previously untreated, EGFR mutation-positive, advanced NSCLC in an
      expansion stage (Stage 2). In the alectinib group, for both the safety-evaluation and
      expansion stages (Stages 1 and 2), the combination will be given to treatment-naive
      participants with anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK)-positive advanced NSCLC.

      In Stage 1, erlotinib will be given at a starting dose of 150 milligrams (mg) once daily
      (QD) and the starting dose of alectinib will be 600 mg twice daily (BID), for 28 consecutive
      days during Cycle 1 and for 21-day cycles thereafter. The starting dose of atezolizumab will
      be 1200 mg, administered every 3 weeks (q3W) starting on Day 8 of Cycle 1. If the starting
      regimen for a combination treatment is not tolerated, alternative doses and/or schedules of
      erlotinib and atezolizumab or alectinib and atezolizumab may be tested to determine
      potential recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) for that combination treatment. In Stage 2, a
      potential RP2D and schedule for each combination treatment will be investigated in an
      expansion cohort.

      For both stages, continuation of treatment beyond Cycle 1 will be at the discretion of the
      treating investigator. Study treatment will be discontinued in participants who experience
      disease progression or unacceptable toxicity, are not compliant with the study protocol, or,
      in their opinion or in the opinion of the investigator, are not benefiting from study
      treatment. However, in the absence of unacceptable toxicity, participants with second-line
      or greater NSCLC who are still receiving atezolizumab at the time of radiographic disease
      progression may be permitted to continue study treatment. Time on study is expected to be
      approximately 15 months.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Dose-Limiting Toxicities</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 8, Cycle 1 until Day 1, Cycle 2 (21 days from start of atezolizumab treatment)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Minimum Plasma Concentration (Cmin) of Alectinib and its Metabolites, as Appropriate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 15 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 15 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response, as Determined by the Investigator with RECIST v1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 15 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Atleast One Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Anti-Therapeutic Antibodies Against Atezolizumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Serum Concentration (Cmax) of Atezolizumab</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day 8</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Minimum Serum Concentration (Cmin) of Atezolizumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of Erlotinib</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Minimum Plasma Concentration (Cmin) of Erlotinib</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of Alectinib and its Metabolites, as Appropriate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">53</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 1: Alectinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Stage 1, starting dose of atezolizumab will be 1200 mg IV q3w, administered on Day 8 of Cycle 1 and on Day 1 (21-day cycle) of each cycle thereafter along with alectinib at a starting dose of 600 mg per oral (PO) BID for 28 consecutive days during Cycle 1 and on Days 1 to 21 of each cycle thereafter; until maximum tolerable dose (MTD). The combination will be given to treatment-naive participants with ALK-positive advanced NSCLC.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 1: Erlotinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Stage 1, starting dose of atezolizumab will be 1200 mg IV q3w, administered on Day 8 of Cycle 1 and on Day 1 (21-day cycle) of each cycle thereafter along with erlotinib at a starting dose of 150 mg PO QD, for 28 consecutive days during Cycle 1 and on Days 1 to 21 of each cycle thereafter; until MTD. The combination will be given to participants with EGFR TKI treatment naive, advanced (non-resectable) NSCLC.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 2: Alectinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Stage 2, participants received the RP2D on the basis of the MTD or maximum allowed dose (MAD) of the combination treatment established in Stage 1. Treatment-naive participants with ALK-positive advanced NSCLC will be included.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 2: Erlotinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Stage 2, participants received the RP2D on the basis of the MTD or MAD of the combination treatment established in Stage 1. Previously untreated (or with one prior treatment that was not an EGFR TKI), EGFR mutation positive, advanced (non-resectable) NSCLC participants will be included.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alectinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive 600 mg PO alectinib BID for 28 consecutive days during Cycle 1 and on Days 1-21 of each cycle thereafter in Stage 1 (21-day cycles from Cycle 2 onwards) and PO RP2D BID in Stage 2.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 1: Alectinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 2: Alectinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Atezolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive 1200 mg IV atezolizumab infusion q3w on Day 8 of Cycle 1 and on Day 1 of each cycle thereafter in Stage 1 and IV RP2D infusion q3w in Stage 2.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 1: Alectinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 1: Erlotinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 2: Alectinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 2: Erlotinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MPDL3280A</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Erlotinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive 150 mg PO erlotinib QD for 28 consecutive days during Cycle 1 and on Days 1-21 of each cycle thereafter in Stage 1 (21-day cycles from Cycle 2 onwards) and PO RP2D QD in Stage 2.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 1: Erlotinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stage 2: Erlotinib and Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Tarceva</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Age &gt;/= 18 years.

          -  Histologically or cytologically documented, locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC.

          -  Participants in Stage 1 (Safety Evaluation) receiving erlotinib: No limit to the
             number of prior therapies (except for EGFR TKIs).

          -  Participants in Stage 2 (Expansion) receiving erlotinib: i) sensitizing mutation in
             the EGFR gene and ii) consent to collection of tumor tissue samples before, during,
             and after treatment for biopsy and PD biomarker analyses.

          -  Participants receiving alectinib in either Stage 1 or Stage 2: must be ALK positive
             as assessed by Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved test and must not have
             received prior treatment for their advanced NSCLC.

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1.

          -  Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks.

          -  Measurable disease, as defined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors
             (RECIST) Version 1.1 (v1.1).

          -  Adequate hematologic and end-organ function.

          -  Use of highly effective contraception (as defined by protocol) until 3 months after
             the last dose of atezolizumab; participants must not be pregnant or breastfeeding.

          -  Archival tumor tissue specimen meeting protocol specifications or the participant
             will be offered the option of a pre-treatment biopsy to obtain adequate tissue
             sample.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  For participants receiving erlotinib group: prior treatment with any EGFR
             mutant-targeting TKI

          -  Any approved anticancer therapy, including chemotherapy, or hormonal therapy (except
             hormone-replacement therapy or oral contraceptives) within 3 weeks of first dose.

          -  Treatment with any other test drug or participation in another clinical trial within
             28 days of enrollment.

          -  Known symptomatic central nervous system (CNS) metastases. Participants with a
             history of treated or untreated asymptomatic CNS metastases may be eligible.

          -  Leptomeningeal disease.

          -  Uncontrolled tumor-related pain.

          -  Uncontrolled pleural effusion, pericardial effusion, or ascites requiring drainage at
             least once monthly.

          -  High levels of calcium requiring bisphosphonate therapy or denosumab.

          -  Malignancies other than NSCLC within 5 years prior to enrollment, with the exception
             of those with a negligible risk of metastasis or death (such as adequately treated
             carcinoma in-situ of the cervix, basal or squamous cell skin cancer, localized
             prostate cancer, or ductal carcinoma in situ).

          -  History of severe allergic, anaphylactic, or other reactions to chimeric or humanized
             antibodies or fusion proteins.

          -  Known hypersensitivity to biopharmaceuticals produced in Chinese hamster ovary cells
             or any component of the atezolizumab formulation.

          -  History of autoimmune disease.

          -  Participants with prior bone marrow or solid organ transplantation.

          -  History of lung inflammation or disease.

          -  Serum albumin less than (&lt;) 2.5 grams per deciliter (g/dL).

          -  Positive for Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV).

          -  Liver disease.

          -  Current or active tuberculosis, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C.

          -  Participants with past or resolved hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection are eligible;
             participants positive for hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody are eligible only if
             polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is negative for HCV Riboxy Nucleic Acid (RNA).

          -  Signs or symptoms of infection within 2 weeks prior to first dosing.

          -  Received therapeutic oral or IV antibiotics within 2 weeks prior to first dosing.

          -  Significant cardiovascular disease.

          -  Major surgical procedure other than for diagnosis within 28 days prior to first
             dosing or during the course of the study.

          -  Administration of a live, attenuated vaccine within 4 weeks before first dosing or
             during the study.

          -  Any other diseases, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding, or clinical
             laboratory finding that may reasonably prevent the participant from participating.

          -  Hypersensitivity to erlotinib or alectinib or to any of the excipients.

          -  Any significant ophthalmologic abnormality. The use of contact lenses is not
             recommended during the study.

          -  For participants receiving alectinib: baseline Fridericias corrected QT interval
             (QTcF) greater than (&gt;) 470 milliseconds (ms) or symptomatic bradycardia.

          -  Prior treatment with CD137 agonists or immune checkpoint blockade therapies.

          -  Treatment with systemic immunostimulatory agents within 6 weeks or five half-lives of
             the drug, whichever is shorter, prior to first dosing.

          -  Treatment with systemic immunosuppressive medications within 2 weeks prior to first
             dosing (inhaled corticosteroids and mineralocorticoids are allowed).

          -  Potent inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4 within 14 days prior to Cycle 1, Day 1.

          -  For participants receiving alectinib: administration of agents with potential
             QT-interval prolonging effects within 14 days prior to the first administration of
             study treatment and while on treatment.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hoffmann-La Roche</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Reference Study ID Number: WP29158 www.roche.com/about_roche/roche_worldwide.htm</last_name>
    <phone>888-662-6728 (U.S. and Canada)</phone>
    <email>global.rochegenentechtrials@roche.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Orlando</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32904</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Greenville</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29605</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif</city>
        <zip>94805</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Shatin</city>
        <zip>123456</zip>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>03080</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>05505</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28050</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46010</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>EC1M 6BQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 27, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>December 11, 2013</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Erlotinib Hydrochloride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
