<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="246">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02408861</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2015-00461</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2015-00461</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PAMC-095_R03PAPP01</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>AMC-095</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>AMC-095</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>U01CA121947</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02408861</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nivolumab and Ipilimumab in Treating Patients With Advanced HIV Associated Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study of Ipilimumab and Nivolumab in Advanced HIV Associated Solid Tumors With an Expansion Cohort in HIV Associated Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial studies the side effects and best dose of nivolumab when given with
      ipilimumab in treating patients with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) associated solid
      tumors that have spread to other places in the body and usually cannot be cured or
      controlled with treatment. Monoclonal antibodies, such as ipilimumab and nivolumab, may
      block tumor growth in different ways by targeting certain cells. Ipilimumab is an antibody
      that acts against a molecule called cytotoxic T-lymphocyte antigen 4 (CTLA-4). CTLA-4
      controls a part of your immune system by shutting it down. Nivolumab is a type of antibody
      that is specific for human programmed cell death 1 (PD-1), a protein that is responsible for
      destruction of immune cells. Giving ipilimumab with nivolumab may work better in treating
      patients with HIV associated solid tumors.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To demonstrate safety and feasibility of ipilimumab and nivolumab at the standard doses
      of drug in solid tumor participants with HIV infection given the possibility of increased
      toxicity based on immune activation, co-morbidity, or interference with highly active
      antiretroviral therapy (HAART) therapy. The purpose for this would be to provide appropriate
      experience and guidelines, if necessary, to allow patients with HIV infections to
      participate in ongoing trials. (Dose Escalation and Dose Expansion Cohorts)

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab and
      nivolumab, on immune function (HIV viral load in plasma using conventional assay, cluster of
      differentiation [CD]4+ and CD8+ cells). (Dose Escalation Cohort) II. To preliminarily assess
      objective response rates associated with treatment for commonly represented tumors. (Dose
      Expansion Cohort) III. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the
      combination of ipilimumab and nivolumab, on immune function (HIV viral load in plasma using
      conventional HIV assay, CD4 cells). (Dose Expansion Cohort)

      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Understand the immune response to agent in the context of antiretroviral therapy (ART),
      of altered immune function, and repertoire due to prior HIV infection.

      II. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab and
      nivolumab, on intratumor immune cells by immunohistochemistry (IHC) such as PD1, programmed
      cell death 1 ligand 1 (PDL-1), and others.

      III. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab
      and nivolumab on circulating cytokine markers by multiplex assay, such as: interleukin
      (IL)-2, IL-4, IL-6, IL-10, IL-8, interferon gamma-induced protein 10 (IP10), chemokine
      (C-X-C motif) ligand 13 (CXCL13), interferon (IFN)-gamma, tumor necrosis factor (TNF)-alpha,
      soluble IL-2 receptor (sIL2R)-alpha, sCD27, soluble TNF receptor (sTNFR)1, and sTNFR2.

      IV. To understand the response of human tumor viruses (human papillomavirus [HPV], Kaposi's
      sarcoma-associated herpesvirus [KSHV]) to agent.

      V. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab and
      nivolumab on herpesvirus loads (Epstein-Barr virus [EBV], Kaposi's sarcoma-associated
      herpesvirus [KSHV], cytomegalovirus [CMV]) in plasma.

      VI. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab and
      nivolumab on latent herpesvirus (Epstein-Barr virus [EBV], KSHV, cytomegalovirus [CMV]) in
      peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC).

      VII. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab
      and nivolumab on herpesvirus specific CD8 and CD4 T cells in PBMC.

      VIII. In cases of Kaposi sarcoma, to evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the
      combination of ipilimumab and nivolumab on viral transcription in tumor biopsies.

      IX. In cases of anal cancer, to evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the
      combination of ipilimumab and nivolumab on HPV types in anal swabs, when feasible.

      X. Understand the response of HIV to agent. XI. To evaluate the effects of single agent
      nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab and nivolumab on latent HIV loads in PBMC using
      outgrowth assay.

      XII. To evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab
      and nivolumab on HIV reactive T cells.

      OUTLINE: This is a dose escalation study of nivolumab.

      INDUCTION PERIOD: Patients receive nivolumab intravenously (IV) over 60 minutes on days 1,
      15, 29, and 43 (dose level -1 and 1) or days 1, 22, 43, and 64 (dose levels -2 and 2).
      Patients in dose levels -2 and 2 also receive ipilimumab IV over 90 minutes on days 1, 22,
      43, and 64. Patients with an overall response of immune-related stable disease (irSD),
      immune-related partial response (irPR), immune-related complete response (irCR), or
      unconfirmed immune-related progressive disease (irPD) at the end of the Induction Period
      will enter the Maintenance Period.

      MAINTENANCE PERIOD: Patients receive nivolumab IV over 60 minutes every 2 weeks for up to 42
      infusions.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 16 weeks or 112 days
      (based on 5 half lives).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2015</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose of nivolumab defined as the starting dose level at which 0/6 or 1/6 subjects experience dose limiting toxicity (DLT) with the next higher dose having at least 2/3 or 2/6 subjects encountering DLT</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Toxicity data will be presented by type and severity for each dose group and overall; the incidence of toxicity related dose reductions and treatment discontinuations will be summarized.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HIV viral load</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Change in HIV viral load from pre-study to the end of study will be examined using a nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in immune status</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Change in immune status from pre-study to the end of study will be examined using a nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune function</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated to evaluate the effects of single agent nivolumab, and the combination of ipilimumab and nivolumab, on immune function (HIV viral load, CD4 cells).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The proportion of patients achieving objective responses (by Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors 1.1 or Kaposi's sarcoma response criteria) and their corresponding 95% confidence intervals (calculated using exact binomial) will be reported using designated response criteria. Descriptive statistics will be reported for response based on Immune-Related Response Criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Circulating cytokine markers by multiplex assay</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Herpesvirus loads (EBV, KSHV, CMV) in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Herpesvirus specific CD8 and CD4 T cells in PBMC</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>HIV reactive T cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>HPV types in anal swabs (anal cancer cases)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Intratumor immune cells by IHC</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Latent herpesvirus (EBV, KSHV, CMV) in PBMC</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Latent HIV loads in PBMC using outgrowth assay</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Viral transcription in tumor biopsies (Kaposi sarcoma cases)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Descriptive statistics will be generated. Changes from pre-study to end of study will be explored using nonparametric Wilcoxon signed-rank test.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Anal Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>HIV Infection</condition>
  <condition>Kaposi Sarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Lung Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (nivolumab, ipilimumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>INDUCTION PERIOD: Patients receive nivolumab IV over 60 minutes on days 1, 15, 29, and 43 (dose level -1 and 1) or days 1, 22, 43, and 64 (dose levels -2 and 2). Patients in dose levels -2 and 2 also receive ipilimumab IV over 90 minutes on days 1, 22, 43, and 64. Patients with an overall response of irSD, irPR, irCR, or unconfirmed irPD at the end of the Induction Period will enter the Maintenance Period.
MAINTENANCE PERIOD: Patients receive nivolumab IV over 60 minutes every 2 weeks for up to 42 infusions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (nivolumab, ipilimumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Anti-Cytotoxic T-Lymphocyte-Associated Antigen-4 Monoclonal Antibody</other_name>
    <other_name>BMS-734016</other_name>
    <other_name>MDX-010</other_name>
    <other_name>MDX-CTLA4</other_name>
    <other_name>Yervoy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (nivolumab, ipilimumab)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (nivolumab, ipilimumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BMS-936558</other_name>
    <other_name>MDX-1106</other_name>
    <other_name>NIVO</other_name>
    <other_name>ONO-4538</other_name>
    <other_name>Opdivo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Participants must have histologically confirmed solid tumor malignancy that is
             metastatic or unresectable and for which standard curative or palliative measures do
             not exist or are no longer effective; participants with uncontrolled Kaposi sarcoma
             are permitted (KS must be increasing despite HAART and HIV suppression for greater
             than or equal to 2 months, or stable KS despite HAART for greater than or equal to 3
             months)

          -  HIV-1 infection, as documented by any federally approved, licensed HIV rapid test
             performed in conjunction with screening (or enzyme linked immunosorbent assay
             [ELISA], test kit, and confirmed by Western blot or other approved test);
             alternatively, this documentation may include a record demonstrating that another
             physician has documented the participant's HIV status based on either: 1) approved
             diagnostic tests, or 2) the referring physician's written record that HIV infection
             was documented, with supporting information on the participant's relevant medical
             history and/or current management of HIV infection

          -  Participants must have measurable disease, defined as at least one lesion that can be
             accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be recorded for
             non-nodal lesions and short axis for nodal lesions) as &gt;= 20 mm with conventional
             techniques or as &gt;= 10 mm with spiral computed tomography (CT) scan, magnetic
             resonance imaging (MRI), or calipers by clinical exam; scans must have been performed
             within 4 weeks prior to registration; Note: for participants with Kaposi sarcoma, the
             following apply: at least five measurable cutaneous KS lesions or any number of
             lesions with systemic unresectable disease with no previous local radiation,
             surgical, or intralesional cytotoxic therapy that would prevent response assessment

          -  Prior therapy for metastatic disease permitted; at least 4 weeks must have elapsed
             since prior chemotherapy or biological therapy, 6 weeks if the regimen included
             carmustine (BCNU) or mitomycin C; radiotherapy must be completed at least 4 weeks
             prior to registration

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 1 (Karnofsky &gt;= 70%)

          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 2,000/mm^3

          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,000/mm^3

          -  Platelets &gt;= 75,000/mm^3

          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) =&lt; 3 x ULN for
             subjects with Gilbert's disease or with atazanavir- or indinavir-induced unconjugated
             hyperbilirubinemia without aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine
             aminotransferase (ALT) elevation and must have a total bilirubin less than 3.0 mg/dL

          -  Serum lipase and amylase &lt; 1.5 x ULN

          -  AST (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase [SGOT])/ALT (serum glutamate pyruvate
             transaminase [SGPT]) =&lt; 3 X institutional upper limit of normal

          -  Creatinine &lt; 1.5 upper normal limit (UNL) or creatinine clearance (CrCl) &gt; 50 ml/min

          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL

          -  Serum albumin &gt;= 2.8 g/dL

          -  HIV plasma HIV-1 ribonucleic acid (RNA) below detected limit obtained by Food and
             Drug Administration (FDA)-approved assays (limit of detection: 75) within 4 weeks
             prior to registration

          -  CD4 counts:

               -  For Stratum 1: CD4+ cell count greater than 200 cells/mm^3 obtained within 2
                  weeks prior to enrollment at any U.S. laboratory that has a clinical laboratory
                  improvement amendments (CLIA) certification or its equivalent

               -  For Stratum 2: CD4 cell count between 100-200 cells/mm^3 obtained within 2 weeks
                  prior to enrollment at any U.S. laboratory that has a clinical laboratory
                  improvement amendments (CLIA) certification or its equivalent

               -  Expansion Cohort: CD4 cell count for this cohort will be specified once Stratum
                  1 and Stratum 2 have completed enrollment

          -  Participants must be purified protein derivative (PPD) negative; PPD positive
             participants are permitted if prophylaxis has been completed prior to enrollment

          -  Women of child-bearing potential (WOCBP) and men must agree to use adequate
             contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to
             study entry and for the duration of study participation; WOCBP should use an adequate
             method to avoid pregnancy for 6 months after the last dose of investigational drug;
             women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy test
             (minimum sensitivity 25 IU/L or equivalent units of human chorionic gonadotropic
             [HCG]) within 72 hours prior to the start of nivolumab; women must not be
             breastfeeding; men who are sexually active with WOCBP must use any contraceptive
             method with a failure rate of less than 1% per year; men receiving nivolumab and who
             are sexually active with WOCBP will be instructed to adhere to contraception for a
             period of 31 weeks after the last dose of investigational product; women who are not
             of childbearing potential (i.e., who are postmenopausal or surgically sterile as well
             as azoospermic men) do not require contraception; WOCBP receiving nivolumab will be
             instructed to adhere to contraception for a period of 6 months after the last dose of
             investigational product; men receiving nivolumab and who are sexually active with
             WOCBP will be instructed to adhere to contraception for a period of 31 weeks after
             the last dose of investigational product; should a woman become pregnant or suspect
             she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she (or the
             participating partner) should inform the treating physician immediately

          -  Participants MUST receive appropriate care and treatment for HIV infection, including
             antiretroviral medications when clinically indicated, and should be under the care of
             a physician experienced in HIV management; participants will be eligible regardless
             of antiretroviral medication (including no antiretroviral medication) provided there
             is no intention to initiate therapy or the regimen has been stable for at least 4
             weeks with no intention to change the regimen within 12 weeks following enrollment

          -  Participants who have hepatitis C (both reactive anti-hepatitis C virus [HCV]
             antibody and detectable HCV RNA) and hepatitis B (hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg]
             positive and anti-hepatitis B core [HBc]-total positive), may be enrolled, provided
             total bilirubin is =&lt; 1.5 x institutional ULN, and AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT) must be
             =&lt; 3 X institutional upper limit of normal, and hepatitis B virus (HBV)
             deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) &lt; 100 IU/mL (if hepatitis B positive) within 2 weeks
             prior to enrollment

          -  Ability to understand and to sign a written informed consent document

          -  Criteria for Solid Tumor Expansion Cohort:

               -  Inclusion and exclusion criteria for this cohort are the same as above, with the
                  following rule for CD4 count based on tolerability in Phase I; if, participants
                  with lymphocyte T CD4 count between 100-200/mm^3 (Stratum 2) are shown to
                  tolerate treatment in the Phase I dose escalation portion at the same dose level
                  as those with CD4 counts &gt; 200/mm^3 (Stratum 1), participants in the expansion
                  cohort with CD4 counts &gt;= 100/mm^3 are permitted; otherwise, only participants
                  with CD4 count &gt; 200/mm^3 will be enrolled in this cohort; the expansion is
                  limited to only participants with Kaposi sarcoma, lung cancer, and anal cancer

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Participants who have received any other investigational agents within the 4 weeks
             prior to enrollment; concurrent radiation therapy is not permitted, except palliative
             (limited-field) radiation therapy, if all of the following criteria are met:

               -  Repeat imaging demonstrates no new sites of bone metastases

               -  The lesion being considered for palliative radiation is not a target lesion

          -  Participants with known brain metastases or leptomeningeal metastases may be excluded
             because of poor prognosis and concerns regarding progressive neurologic dysfunction
             that would confound the evaluation of neurologic and other adverse events; however,
             participants with brain metastases are permitted if metastases have been treated and
             there is no magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) evidence of progression for at least 4
             weeks or more after treatment is complete and within 4 weeks prior to the first dose
             of nivolumab administration

          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic
             composition to ipilimumab, nivolumab, or other agents used in study, or history of
             severe hypersensitivity reaction to any monoclonal antibody

          -  Participants should be excluded if they have a condition requiring systemic treatment
             with either corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg daily prednisone equivalents) or other
             immunosuppressive medications within 2 weeks of study drug administration; inhaled or
             topical steroids and adrenal replacement doses =&lt; 10 mg daily prednisone equivalents
             are permitted in the absence of active autoimmune disease; participants are permitted
             to use topical, ocular, intra-articular, intranasal, and inhalational corticosteroids
             (with minimal systemic absorption); physiologic replacement doses of systemic
             corticosteroids are permitted, even if &gt;= 10 mg/day prednisone equivalents; a brief
             course of corticosteroids for prophylaxis (e.g., contrast dye allergy) or for
             treatment of non-autoimmune conditions (e.g., delayed-type hypersensitivity reaction
             caused by contact allergen) is permitted; these drugs may interfere with the activity
             of ipilimumab and nivolumab if administered at the time of the first ipilimumab dose;
             use of anabolic steroids is permitted

          -  Participants with clinical or radiographic evidence of pancreatitis are excluded

          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with
             study requirements

          -  Participants should be excluded if they have had prior treatment with an anti-PD-1,
             anti-programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1), anti-programmed cell death ligand 2
             (PD-L2), anti-CTLA-4 antibody, or any other antibody or drug specifically targeting
             T-cell co-stimulation or immune checkpoint pathways; prior immune modulating therapy
             including vaccines may be eligible; prior immune events must be evaluated and the
             risk for new events which may represent continued sub clinical disease or a new
             process at previously damaged site or immune potentiation (e.g. ipilimumab followed
             by IL2 causing bowel perforation, ipilimumab followed by indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase
             [IDO] inhibitor resulting in clinical hypophysitis); please keep in mind that
             inflammatory events may occur weeks to months following the last dose of ipilimumab
             and possibly nivolumab; assessment of potential effects of prior therapy should
             include:

               -  Immune status

               -  Organ damage

               -  Risk of autoimmunity

               -  Immunopotentiation

          -  The subject has not recovered to baseline or Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse
             Events (CTCAE) =&lt; grade 1 from toxicity due to all prior therapies except =&lt; grade 2
             alopecia, neuropathy, and other non-clinically significant adverse events (AEs)

          -  The subject has a primary brain tumor

          -  Participant has &gt;= grade 2 diarrhea (participants with grade 1 diarrhea are eligible
             provided stool for ova/parasites and stool cryptosporidium studies are negative)

          -  Opportunistic infection within the last 3 months

          -  Participants with active autoimmune disease or history of autoimmune disease that
             might recur, which may affect vital organ function or require immune suppressive
             treatment including systemic corticosteroids, should be excluded; these include but
             are not limited to patients with a history of immune related neurologic disease,
             multiple sclerosis, autoimmune (demyelinating) neuropathy, Guillain-Barré syndrome,
             myasthenia gravis; systemic autoimmune disease such as systemic lupus erythematosus
             (SLE), connective tissue diseases, scleroderma, inflammatory bowel disease (IBD),
             Crohn's, ulcerative colitis, hepatitis; and participants with a history of toxic
             epidermal necrolysis (TEN), Stevens-Johnson syndrome, or phospholipid syndrome should
             be excluded; participants with vitiligo, endocrine deficiencies including thyroiditis
             managed with replacement hormones including physiologic corticosteroids are eligible;
             participants with rheumatoid arthritis and other arthropathies, Sjögren's syndrome
             and psoriasis controlled with topical medication and participants with positive
             serology, such as antinuclear antibodies (ANA), anti-thyroid antibodies should be
             evaluated for the presence of target organ involvement and potential need for
             systemic treatment but should otherwise be eligible; participants are permitted to
             enroll if they have vitiligo, type I diabetes mellitus, residual hypothyroidism due
             to autoimmune condition only requiring hormone replacement, psoriasis not requiring
             systemic treatment, or conditions not expected to recur in the absence of an external
             trigger (precipitating event)

          -  Participants who have had evidence of Clostridium (C.) difficile infection, active or
             acute diverticulitis, intra-abdominal abscess, intra-abdominal abscess,
             gastrointestinal (GI) obstruction and abdominal carcinomatosis, which are known risk
             factors for bowel perforation, should be evaluated for the potential need for
             additional treatment before coming on study
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lakshmi Rajdev</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>AIDS Malignancy Consortium</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCLA Center for Clinical AIDS Research and Education</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90035</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>San Francisco General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chia-Ching (Jackie) Wang</last_name>
      <phone>415-476-4082</phone>
      <phone_ext>146</phone_ext>
      <email>chia-ching.wang@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chia-Ching (Jackie) Wang</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCSF Medical Center-Mount Zion</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chia-Ching (Jackie) Wang</last_name>
      <phone>415-476-4082</phone>
      <phone_ext>146</phone_ext>
      <email>chia-ching.wang@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chia-Ching (Jackie) Wang</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John H Stroger Jr Hospital of Cook County</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AIDS Malignancy Consortium</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rockville</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20850</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lee Ratner</last_name>
      <phone>800-600-3606</phone>
      <email>info@siteman.wustl.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lee Ratner</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Montefiore Medical Center-Einstein Campus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10461</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Montefiore Medical Center-Weiler Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10461</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Montefiore Medical Center - Moses Campus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10467-2490</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harborview Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Manoj Menon</last_name>
      <phone>800-422-6237</phone>
      <email>mmenon@fhcrc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Manoj Menon</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seattle Cancer Care Alliance</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Manoj Menon</last_name>
      <phone>800-422-6237</phone>
      <email>mmenon@fhcrc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Manoj Menon</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 13, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 3, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Anus Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma, Kaposi</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
