<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="331">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01829217</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>13-086</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01829217</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sunitinib in Never-Smokers With Lung Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Trial of Sunitinib in Never-smokers With Lung Adenocarcinoma: Identification of Oncogenic Alterations Underlying Sunitinib Sensitivity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study is a Phase II clinical trial, which tests the safety and effectiveness
      of an investigational drug to learn whether the drug works in treating a specific cancer.
      &quot;Investigational&quot; means that the drug is being studied. It also means that the FDA has not
      yet approved sunitinib for your type of cancer.

      Sunitinib has been approved by the FDA for treatment of gastrointestinal stromal tumors,
      advanced renal cell carcinoma and advanced pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. While most
      chemotherapies work by interfering with cancer cell replication, sunitinib works by blocking
      certain protein signals within the cell. Because sunitinib works differently from standard
      intravenous chemotherapies, we call it a &quot;targeted therapy.&quot; This drug has also been used in
      other research studies and information from those other research studies suggests that this
      agent may help to slow the growth of some NSCLC tumors.

      In this research study, we are looking to see if sunitinib may stop certain NSCLC tumors
      from growing. The study focuses on a type of NSCLC, adenocarcinoma, which has previously
      been found to be more sensitive to other kinds of oral targeted therapies. This study will
      focus specifically on (1) adenocarcinoma tumors that do not carry a mutation in a known
      cancer gene (EGFR, KRAS, or ALK) and occur in patients that never smoked (less than 100
      cigarettes in their lifetime) or (2) adenocarcinoma tumors that have a mutation in the RET
      gene.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      If you are willing to participate in this research study you will be asked to undergo some
      screening tests and procedures to confirm that you are eligible. Many of these tests and
      procedures are likely to be part of regular cancer care and may be done even if it turns out
      that you do not take part in the research study. If you have had some of these tests or
      procedures recently, they may or may not have to be repeated. These tests and procedures
      will include: a medical history, complete physical exam, performance status, assessment of
      your tumor, routine blood tests, urine pregnancy test, urine test, electrocardiogram, and an
      echocardiogram. In order to screen for and participate in this study, your tumor sample must
      have been tested for genetic alterations in EGFR, KRAS and ALK and been found to have
      negative results. Alternatively, you must have had testing that determined that your tumor
      sample has a RET mutation. You will not be eligible to screen on this study unless these
      testing requirements have already been met. In addition to the above requirements, before
      starting other screening for the study, it must be confirmed that there is adequate tumor
      tissue left from a previous surgery or biopsy for required study-related tests. This tumor
      specimen is stored in a pathology department in a paraffin block. If adequate tumor tissue
      isn't available, you may be able to have a new biopsy of our tumor to obtain this tissue. If
      the required tests and procedures show that you are eligible to participate in the research
      study, you will begin the study drug. If you do not meet all of the eligibility criteria,
      you will not be able to participate in this research study.

      If you take part in this research study, you will be given a study drug-dosing diary for
      each treatment cycle. Each treatment cycle lasts 42 days (6 weeks), during which time you
      will be taking the study drug daily (at home, by mouth) for 28 days (four weeks), followed
      by 2 weeks off sunitinib. On Day 1 of each cycle, you will be given a 28 days supply of
      study drug. The diary that you will be given on Day 1 of each cycle will also include
      special instructions for taking the sunitinib.

      There is a possibility that the following tests or procedures may need to be done at times
      other than those listed below. These may be done if your research doctor determines they are
      medically necessary to monitor your illness or any side effects you may be experiencing. It
      is important that you call your research doctor if at any time you are experiencing side
      effects you cannot tolerate.

      During Cycle 1, you will be seen every two weeks on Days 1, 15 and 29 and during Cycles 2-3,
      you will be seen on Days 1 and 29. Starting with Cycle 4, you will only have a clinic visit
      on Day 1 of every six-week cycle.

      During all cycles you will have a physical exam and you will be asked questions about your
      general health and specific questions about any problems that you might be having and any
      medications you may be taking. At different times throughout the study you will also undergo
      the following: side effect review, current medication review, weight, vital signs, physical
      exam, performance status, blood sample collection, review of drug diary and ECG.

      We will assess your tumor(s) by CT scans ever six weeks (at the end of each cycle). CT scans
      will also be repeated at the End of Study if they weren't done within the previous 30 days.

      During the study, your tumor sample will be tested and analyzed for genomic changes (changes
      in your tumor genes) that may be associated with the effectiveness of sunitinib. As a
      comparison, your blood will also be tested for changes in these genes. These genomic tests
      will be for research only and you will not be informed of their results. If you withdraw
      from the study and yuor tumor sample has already been tested, the remaining tumor material
      will be sent to the pathology department that first tested your tissue for cancer. However,
      the collected information related to your participation in this study and your genomic
      testing will remain part of the overall research data and used for the analysis.

      We would like to keep track of your medical condition for the rest of your life. We would
      like to do this by calling you on the telephone once a year to see how you are doing.
      Keeping in touch with you and checking your condition every year helps us look at the
      long-term effects of the research study.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Objective Response Rate to Sunitinib</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>To evaluate the objective response rate (ORR) to sunitinib in never-smokers with lung cancers that are wild-type for EGFR, KRAS, and ALK in a single-arm phase II trial</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identify Oncogenic Alterations</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>To identify oncogenic alterations underlying sensitivity to sunitinib through performing next-generation sequencing (NGS) of lung cancers treated with sunitinib</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Explore Activity of Sunitinib in Lung Cancers with RET Rearrangement</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>To explore the activity of sunitinib in lung cancers known to harbor a RET rearrangement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sunitinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>42 day cycle, taken orally every day for the first 28 days followed by 14 days off</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sunitinib</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Sunitinib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced (stage IV or recurrent) non-small
             cell lung cancer

          -  Adenocarcinoma histology of any variant, including adenosquamous histology

          -  Wild-type for mutations in EGFR, KRAS and ALK

          -  &lt; 100 cigarettes smoked lifetime OR known to harbor a RET rearrangement

          -  Measurable disease

          -  At least one prior systemic therapy (adjuvant or palliative)

          -  Life expectancy of greater than 4 weeks

          -  Adequate tumor tissue for the correlative analyses on study, or must undergo a biopsy
             to obtain adequate tissue

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding

          -  Chemotherapy within 4 weeks of entering study, or lack of recover from adverse events
             to grade 1 or less due to systemic agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier

          -  Radiation therapy within 2 weeks prior to entering study

          -  Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to entering the study

          -  Receiving any other investigational agents

          -  Known untreated, symptomatic or progressive brain metastases; presence of
             carcinomatous meningitis; history of intracranial hemorrhage or brain metastases
             requiring chronic steroids

          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic
             composition to sunitinib

          -  Use of certain inhibitors and inducers of CYP3A4

          -  Grade 3 or 4 hemoptysis or hemorrhage within 4 weeks prior to study entry

          -  History of significant bleeding disorder unrelated to cancer

          -  Poorly controlled hypertension

          -  Severe cardiovascular disease

          -  Prolongation of corrected QT interval

          -  History of a different malignancy except: cervical cancer in situ, basal or squamous
             cell carcinoma of the skin, low risk centralized prostate cancer

          -  HIV positive on combination antiretroviral therapy
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Geoffrey Oxnard, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Geoffrey Oxnard, MD</last_name>
    <phone>6176326234</phone>
    <email>geoffrey_oxnard@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02214</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rebecca Heist, MD</last_name>
      <phone>617-726-1838</phone>
      <email>rheist@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rebecca Heist, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Isreal Deaconess Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daniel Costa, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>617-667-9236</phone>
      <email>dcosta@bidmc.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel Costa, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham and Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Geoffrey Oxnard, MD</last_name>
      <phone>617-632-6234</phone>
      <email>geoffrey_oxnard@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffrey Oxnard, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Geoffrey Oxnard, MD</last_name>
      <phone>617-632-6234</phone>
      <email>geoffrey_oxnard@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Geoffrey Oxnard, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 30, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 9, 2013</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Geoffrey Oxnard, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prinicipal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
