<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="322">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01820754</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00038093</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01820754</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Circulating T Cells and Tumor Infiltrating Lymphocytes (TILs) During / After Pre-Surgery Chemotherapy in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</brief_title>
  <acronym>TOP1201 IPI</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Circulating T Cells and Tumor Infiltrating Lymphocytes With Specificities Against Tumor Associated Antigens During and After Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy and Phased Ipilimumab in Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate whether the combination of neoadjuvant chemotherapy
      (chemotherapy before surgery) plus ipilimumab for lung cancer increases the number of
      patients with detectable circulating T cells with specificities against tumor associated
      antigens (TAA) from zero percent (0%) of patients prior to therapy to 20% of patients after
      neoadjuvant chemotherapy plus ipilimumab.

      This is an open label Phase 2 trial. Patients with clinical stage IB (&gt;4 cm), II, (N0-2)
      non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) and no prior therapy for the current diagnosis of lung
      cancer will be eligible for the study. Subjects will receive 3 cycles of neoadjuvant
      chemotherapy (paclitaxel + cisplatin/carboplatin). Ipilimumab will be administered during
      Cycles 2 and 3 of standard chemotherapy and for up to 4 cycles alone after surgery. Subjects
      will undergo standard clinically indicated surgical resection of their lung cancer as deemed
      appropriate by their surgeon.

      Standard diagnostic and staging work up will be performed including: pathologic/histologic
      diagnosis of NSCLC, Positron Emission Tomography (PET)/Computed Tomography (CT) scan, brain
      imaging, and mediastinoscopy. Three cycles of neoadjuvant chemotherapy will be given.
      Ipilimumab will be added to neoadjuvant chemotherapy for cycles 2 and 3. Standard surgical
      evaluation and therapy will be performed following completion of neoadjuvant therapy. Two
      cycles of single agent ipilimumab will be given after surgery (adjuvantly), followed by 2
      cycles of maintenance therapy.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators propose studying the cell mediated effects of ipilimumab in combination
      with chemotherapy in the neoadjuvant setting for NSCLC. The overall immune assessment
      strategy for the proposed ipilimumab neoadjuvant trial will be based on the hypothesis that
      1) T cells with specificities against tumor associated antigens expressed by the patient's
      progressing NSCLC are present, but functionally impaired, at baseline, and 2) that the
      immunomodulatory effects of chemotherapy plus ipilimumab will impact the suppressive
      mechanisms, restoring functional reactivity to important anti-tumor effector cell
      populations.

      An important potential biomarker for anti-tumor immune response is the proliferation and
      stimulation of circulating T cells with specificities against tumor associated antigens
      (TAA). At baseline few patients with cancer have populations of circulating T cells with
      specificities against TAA above the detectable level of 0.05% CD8 lymphocytes. The primary
      endpoint of this clinical trial will be to determine if the addition of ipilimumab to
      neoadjuvant chemotherapy for non-small cell lung cancer increases the percentage of patients
      with circulating T cells with specificities against TAA. We will also measure tumor
      infiltrating lymphocytes in resected tumors.

      Study Interventions:

      The investigational agent, ipilimumab, will be added to neoadjuvant chemotherapy for cycles
      2 and 3. Standard surgical evaluation and therapy will be performed following completion of
      neoadjuvant therapy. Two cycles of single agent ipilimumab will be given after surgery
      (adjuvantly), followed by 2 cycles of maintenance therapy.

      Neoadjuvant:

      Cycle 1: Paclitaxel 175 mg/m2 IV over 3 hours followed by cisplatin 75 mg/m2 over 60 minutes
      or carboplatin AUC (Area Under Curve) 6 (capped at 900 mg)over 30-60 minutes on day 1 (every
      21 days x 1 cycle) Cycles 2 and 3: Ipilimumab 10mg/kg IV over 90 minutes, Paclitaxel 175
      mg/m2 over 3 hours followed by cisplatin 75 mg/m2 or carboplatin AUC 6 (capped at 900 mg)IV
      over 30-60 minutes (every 21 days x 2 cycles) Surgery: Standard surgical evaluation will
      occur at least 21 days after the last dose (Cycle 3) of chemotherapy followed by surgical
      therapy.

      Post-surgical Therapy: (Total of 4 doses of ipilimumab will be given post-operatively):

      Adjuvant: Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV every 3 weeks x 2 doses, beginning 4 weeks postoperative
      (up to 10 weeks if needed for recovery) Maintenance: Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV every 12 weeks x
      2 doses

      Correlative Science Measures: Study specific research blood and tissue test(s) will be
      conducted:

      Blood Specimens:

      •Peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) isolated from freshly drawn anti-coagulated blood
      will be analyzed for circulating T cells with specificities against tumor-associated
      antigens (TAA) at 4 time points, namely 1) Baseline prior to treatment, 2) cycle 2, prior to
      ipilimumab therapy, 3) 21-36 days after completion of cycle 3 chemotherapy prior to surgery,
      and 4) 3-6 weeks after adjuvant ipilimumab dose #2. Additionally, PBMC from each of the time
      points will be analyzed for the presence of circulating populations of regulatory T cells,
      myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSC), as well as activated and exhausted T cells.

      Tissue Specimens:

      •Tumor infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) will be isolated from the patient's resected tumor
      and analyzed for infiltrating T cells with specificities against tumor-associated antigens.
      Additionally, TIL will be analyzed for the presence of infiltrating populations of
      regulatory T cells, myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSC), as well as activated and
      exhausted T cells.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of subjects with detectable circulating T cells after treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The primary objective of this trial is to determine the percentage of early stage lung cancer patients with detectable circulating T cells specific against TAA (tumor associated antigen) after receiving platinum based neoadjuvant chemotherapy plus ipilimumab before surgery. Based on Duke intracellular cytokine staining (ICS) assessments over the past 8 years, &quot;detectable&quot; circulating T cells with specificity against TAA are defined as a CD8, CD4, and double positive (DP) (CD4+CD8+) lymphocyte percentage of ≥ 0.05% with each value also being at least twice that of the background unstimulated control value.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility and tolerability of neoadjuvant chemotherapy plus ipilimumab and surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Number of subjects experiencing any of the criteria listed below:
Number of subjects receiving 3 doses of preoperative therapy
Number of subjects undergoing surgical exploration within 42 days of day 1 of the last cycle of neoadjuvant chemotherapy
Number of subjects undergoing lobectomy having surgery-related mortality
Number of subjects experiencing dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) during neoadjuvant therapy. DLT will be defined as treatment-related: ≥ Grade 4 hematologic toxicity (excluding neutropenia without fever or infection) or ≥ Grade 3 non-hematologic toxicity (excluding fatigue, nausea, vomiting, peripheral neuropathy, chemotherapy infusion reaction to carboplatin or paclitaxel)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median Disease-Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Disease-free survival (DFS) is defined as the time from surgical resection to disease recurrence (first disease recurrence or death, whichever comes first) after surgery. Patients alive who had not recurred as of the last follow-up had DFS censored at the last follow-up date. The Kaplan-Meier estimator will be used to estimate median DFS and its 95% confidence interval.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects experiencing a metastasis by site of metastasis</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Patterns of Metastasis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patterns of pathologic response and response evaluation criteria in solid tumor (RECIST) response</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Within each category of RECIST response, the number of subjects experiencing a pathologic complete response, pathologic partial response, and no pathologic response. RECIST evaluation will be conducted after completion of neoadjuvant therapy. Pathologic response will be evaluated in the resected tumor as follows:
No Pathologic Response: No evidence of cell death or tumor necrosis
Pathologic Partial Response: ≥30% tumor necrosis or cell death
Pathologic Complete Response: No evidence of viable tumor in surgical specimen (includes lung tissue and dissected lymph nodes)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ipilimumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Neoadjuvant (Pre-Surgery): Cycles 2 and 3: Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV over 90 minutes Adjuvant (Post-Surgery): Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV every 3 weeks times 2 doses beginning 4 weeks postoperative ( up to 10 weeks if needed for recovery) Maintenance: Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg/IV every 12 weeks times 2 doses</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Neoadjuvant (Pre-Surgery): Cycles 2 and 3: Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV over 90 minutes
Adjuvant (Post-Surgery): Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV every 3 weeks times 2 doses beginning 4 weeks postoperative ( up to 10 weeks if needed for recovery)
Maintenance: Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg/IV every 12 weeks times 2 doses</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ipilimumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Yervoy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paclitaxel, Cisplatin, Carboplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>Neoadjuvant (Pre-Surgery) Cycle 1: Paclitaxel 175 mg/m2 IV over 3 hours , followed by Cisplatin 75 mg/m2 IV over 60 minutes or carboplatin AUC 6 IV over 30-60 minutes on day 1(Every 21 days x 1 cycle)
Cycles 2 and 3: Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV over 90 minutes, Paclitaxel 175 mg/m2 IV over 3 hours , followed by Cisplatin 75 mg/m2 IV over 60 minutes or carboplatin AUC 6 IV over 30-60 minutes on day 1(Every 21 days x 2 cycles)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ipilimumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Taxol, Platinol, Paraplatin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Patients are eligible to be in the study if they meet all of the following criteria:

          -  Histologically or cytologically documented non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC)

          -  Clinical stage IB (≥4cm per CT), Stage IIA/IIB, or Stage III (N0-2) amenable to
             surgical resection

          -  Patients must be deemed a surgical candidate

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1

          -  No prior chemotherapy for current diagnosis of lung cancer

          -  Age is ≥ (greater than or equal to) 18 years

          -  No active invasive malignancy in the past 2 years other than non-melanoma skin
             cancer. Cancers that are in-situ are not considered invasive

          -  Signed written informed consent including Health Insurance Portability and
             Accountability Act (HIPAA) authorization according to institutional guidelines

          -  Adequate Organ Function:

               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) or absolute granulocyte count (AGC) ≥1500 per
                  microliter (uL)

               -  Platelets ≥ 100,000 per uL

               -  Total bilirubin ≤(less than or equal to)1.5 milligram per deciliter (mg/dL)

               -  Creatinine clearance ≥ 45 milliliter per minute (mL / min); (Creatinine &lt; 2mg /
                  dL to receive cisplatin)

               -  Serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase / Serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase
                  (SGOT/SGPT) ≤ 2.5x institutional upper limit normal (ULN)

          -  Females of child-bearing potential (not surgically sterilized and between menarche
             and 1 year post menopause) must test negative for pregnancy within 48 hours prior to
             any initial study procedure based on a serum pregnancy test. Both sexually active
             males and females of reproductive potential must agree to use a reliable method of
             birth control, as determined by the patient and their health care team, during the
             study and for 3 months following the last dose of study drug. If subject uses
             appropriate contraceptive methods (the use of two forms at the same time) from the
             time of the initial serum pregnancy test, then the subsequent pregnancy test can be
             done within 72 hours of receiving study drug administration. If appropriate
             contraceptive measures are not begun immediately with the first serum pregnancy test,
             then subsequent serum pregnancy tests must be done within 48 hours prior to the study
             drug administration

          -  Patients must agree to research blood sampling to participate in study

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Patients will be excluded from the study if they meet any of the following criteria:

          -  Have had treatment within the last 30 days with a drug that has not received
             regulatory (Food and Drug Administration (FDA)) approval for any indication at the
             time of study entry

          -  Concurrent administration of any other anti-tumor therapy

          -  Inability to comply with protocol or study procedures

          -  Active infection requiring intravenous (IV) antibiotics, antifungal or antiviral
             agents, that in the opinion of the investigator would compromise the patient's
             ability to tolerate therapy

          -  Major surgery (other than definitive lung cancer surgery) within two weeks of study
             or other serious concomitant systemic disorders that, in the opinion of the
             investigator, would compromise the safety of the patient or compromise the patient's
             ability to complete the study

          -  Myocardial infarction (MI) having occurred less than 6 months before inclusion, any
             known uncontrolled arrhythmia, symptomatic angina pectoris, active ischemia, or
             cardiac failure not controlled by medications

          -  Contraindication to corticosteroids

          -  Unwillingness to stop taking herbal supplements while on study

          -  Female patients who are pregnant or breast-feeding

          -  Autoimmune disease. Patients with a history of inflammatory bowel disease, including
             ulcerative colitis and Crohn's Disease, are excluded from this study, as are patients
             with a history of symptomatic disease (e.g., rheumatoid arthritis, systemic
             progressive sclerosis [scleroderma], systemic lupus erythematosus, autoimmune
             vasculitis [eg, Wegener's Granulomatosis]); motor neuropathy considered of autoimmune
             origin (e.g. Guillain-Barre Syndrome and Myasthenia Gravis)

          -  Any non-oncology vaccine therapy used for prevention of infectious diseases (for up
             to 1 month before or after any dose of ipilimumab)

          -  A history of prior treatment with ipilimumab or prior CD137 agonist or CTLA 4
             inhibitor or agonist

          -  Prisoners or patients who are compulsorily detained (involuntarily incarcerated) for
             treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (e.g., infectious) illness
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Neal Ready, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke University Medical Center / Thoracic Oncology Program</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Debra Shoemaker, RN</last_name>
    <phone>919-681-4768</phone>
    <email>debra.shoemaker@dm.duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ann-Marie Peters, RN</last_name>
    <phone>919-681-7258</phone>
    <email>annemarie.peters@dm.duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Debra Shoemaker, RN</last_name>
      <phone>919-681-4768</phone>
      <email>debra.shoemaker@dm.duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Ann-Marie Peters, RN</last_name>
      <phone>919-681-7258</phone>
      <email>annemarie.peters@dm.duke.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Neal Ready, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>June 3, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 26, 2013</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Non Small Cell</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
