<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="118">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02475213</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CP-MGA271-03</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02475213</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety Study of MGA271 in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Refractory Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Open-Label, Dose Escalation Study of MGA271 in Combination With Pembrolizumab in Patients With B7-H3-Expressing Melanoma, Squamous Cell Cancer of the Head and Neck, Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer and Other B7H3 Expressing Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>MacroGenics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>MacroGenics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety of MGA271 in combination with Keytruda
      (pembrolizumab) when given to patients with B7-H3-expressing melanoma, squamous cell
      carcinoma of the head and neck (SCCHN), non small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), and other B7-H3
      expressing cancers. The study will also evaluate what is the highest dose of MGA271 that can
      be given safely when given with pembrolizumab. Assessments will also be done to see how the
      drug acts in the body (pharmacokinetics (PK), pharmacodynamics) and to evaluate potential
      anti-tumor activity of MGA271 in combination with pembrolizumab.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a Phase 1 open-label, dose escalation, cohort expansion, and efficacy
      follow-up study of MGA271 administered intravenously (IV) on a weekly schedule for up to 51
      doses in combination with IV pembrolizumab administered on an every-3-week schedule for up
      to 17 doses.

      The dose escalation phase is designed to characterize the safety and tolerability of the
      combination of MGA271 and pembrolizumab and to define the maximum tolerated or maximum
      administered dose (MTD/MAD). Patients with methothelioma, urethelial cancer, NSCLC, SCCHN,
      clear cell renal cell carcinoma (ccRCC), ovarian cancer, melanoma, thyroid cancer, triple
      negative breast cancer (TBNC), pancreatic cancer, colon cancer, soft tissue sarcoma, or
      prostate cancer will be enrolled in this study phase.

      In the cohort expansion phase, 3 cohorts of 16 patients each will be enrolled to further
      evaluate the safety and potential efficacy of the combination administered at the MTD/MAD
      dose in patients with melanoma, NSCLC, and SCCHN. Pre- and on-study biopsies are required
      for melanoma patients in the cohort expansion phase.

      The efficacy follow-up period consists of the 2-year period after the final dose of study
      drug.

      All tumor evaluations will be carried out by both Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid
      Tumors (RECIST) and immune-related response criteria (irRC).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Adverse Events, Serious Adverse Events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>7 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>PK of MGA271 in combination with pembrolizumab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants that develop anti-drug antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Proportion of patients who develop anti-MGA271 antibodies, immunogenicity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in tumor volume</measure>
    <time_frame>Weeks 6, 15, 24, 33, 42, 51</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Anti-tumor activity of MGA271 in combination with pembrolizumab using both conventional RECIST 1.1 and immune-related RECIST criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Head and Neck Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Mesothelioma</condition>
  <condition>Urethelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Clear Cell Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Thyroid Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Triple Negative Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Colon Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Soft Tissue Sarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MGA271 plus pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>MGA271: Fc-optimized, humanized monoclonal antibody. Pembrolizumab: Keytruda; human programmed death receptor-1 (PD-1)-blocking antibody approved by the US Food and Drug Administration for the treatment of patients with unresectable or metastatic melanoma and disease progression following ipilimumab and, if BRAF V600 mutation positive, a BRAF inhibitor, or with advanced (metastatic) non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) whose disease has progressed after other treatments and with tumors that express a protein called PD-L1. Keytruda is approved for use with a companion diagnostic, the PD-L1 IHC 22C3 pharmDx test, the first test designed to detect PD-L1 expression in non-small cell lung tumors.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MGA271</intervention_name>
    <description>MGA271 is administered by IV infusion once per week for up to 51 doses.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MGA271 plus pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Pembrolizumab is administered by IV infusion every 3 weeks for up to 17 doses.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MGA271 plus pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologically-proven, unresectable, locally advanced or metastatic melanoma, SCCHN,
             NSCLC, and other cancers that express B7-H3.

          -  Melanoma that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5 prior
             systemic treatments for unresectable locally advanced or metastatic disease, or
             melanoma patients who are intolerable of or have refused standard cancer therapy.
             Pre- and on-study biopsy required.

          -  SCCHN that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5 prior systemic
             treatments for metastatic or recurrent disease deemed to be incurable. Patient who
             refuse radical resection for recurrent disease or are intolerant of or refused
             standard first line therapy are eligible to enroll

          -  NSCLC that has progressed during or following 1 - 5 prior systemic therapies for
             unresectable locally advanced or metastatic disease (at least one docetaxel,
             gemcitabine, or platinum analogue based therapy), or are intolerant of or refused
             standard cancer therapy. For squamous cell carcinoma, or adenocarcinoma without known
             activating mutation: the prior systemic therapy is at least one platinum analogue.
             For adenocarcinoma with known activating driver mutation: the prior systemic therapy
             is at least TKI directed

          -  Mesothelioma that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 3 prior
             systemic treatments for unresectable locally advanced or metastatic disease. The
             prior systemic chemotherapy must have included a pemetrexed (anti-folate)-based
             regimen in combination with platinum agent. For patients in whom pemetrexed was
             contraindicated or not tolerated or not an approved therapy (e.g., peritoneal
             mesothelioma), prior therapy with a first-line platinum-based regimen is required.

          -  Urothelial cancer arising in the bladder, renal pelvis, ureter or urethra that has
             progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5 prior systemic treatments for
             unresectable locally advanced or metastatic disease (includes anti-PD-L1,anti-PD-1,
             but excludes other experimental therapies). Patients must have received at least one
             platinum-containing regimen (e.g., gemcitabine/cisplatin [GC], dose-dense
             methotrexate/vinblastine/doxorubicin/cisplatin [DDMVAC], or
             carboplatinum/gemcitabine). No more than 5 prior systemic regimens allowed.

          -  Thyroid cancer that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5 prior
             chemotherapy regimen(s). Prior therapy excludes experimental therapies given in Phase
             1 trials.

          -  Pancreatic cancer that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 3
             prior chemotherapy regimens. Prior therapy excludes experimental therapies given in
             Phase 1 trials.

          -  Ovarian cancer that has progressed during or following at least 2 and up to 4 prior
             therapeutic regimens (e.g., 2 prior platinum containing regimens or if platinum
             resistant, a liposomal doxorubicin or topotecan containing regimen). Prior therapy
             excludes experimental therapies given in Phase 1 trials

          -  Colon cancer that has progressed during or following at least 2 and up to 4 prior
             therapeutic regimens (e.g., fluoropyrimidine and/or irinotecan and/or oxaliplatin
             and/or anti-EGFR antibody containing regimens). Prior therapy excludes experimental
             therapies given in Phase 1 trials.

          -  Prostate cancer that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5 prior
             therapeutic regimens (e.g., abiraterone, enzalutamide, docetaxel). Prior therapy
             excludes experimental therapies given in Phase 1 trials.

          -  Soft tissue sarcoma that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5
             prior therapeutic regimens. Prior therapy excludes experimental therapies given in
             Phase 1 trials.

          -  TNBC that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5 prior therapeutic
             regimens. Prior therapy excludes experimental therapies given in Phase 1 trials.

          -  ccRCC that has progressed during or following at least 1 and up to 5 prior
             therapeutic regimens. Prior therapy excludes experimental therapies given in Phase 1
             trials.

          -  Measurable disease per RECIST 1.1 criteria

          -  Easter Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 or 1

          -  Acceptable laboratory parameters and adequate organ reserve.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with a history of symptomatic central nervous system metastases, unless
             treated and asymptomatic

          -  Patients with history of autoimmune disease with certain exceptions such as vitiligo,
             resolved chilhood atopic dermatitis, psoriasis not requiring systemic therapy within
             the past 2 years, patients with history of Grave's disease that are now euthyroid
             clinically and by lab testing

          -  History of allogeneic bone marrow, stem cell, or solid organ transplant

          -  Treatment with systemic cancer therapy or investigational therapy within 4 weeks of
             first study drug administration; radiation within 2 weeks; corticosteroids (greater
             than or equal to 10 mg prednisone or equivalent per day) or other immune suppressive
             drugs within 2 weeks of first study drug administration

          -  Trauma or major surgery within 4 weeks of first study drug administration

          -  History of clinically-significant cardiovascular disease; gastrointestinal
             perforation; gastrointestinal bleeding, acute pancreatitis or diverticulitis within 4
             weeks of first study drug administration

          -  Active viral, bacterial, or systemic fungal infection requiring parenteral treatment
             within 7 days of first study drug administration

          -  Known history of hepatitis B or C infection or known positive test for hepatitis B
             surface antigen or core antigen, or hepatitis C polymerase chain reaction (PCR)

          -  Known positive testing for human immunodeficiency virus or history of acquired immune
             deficiency syndrome

          -  Known hypersensitivity to recombinant proteins, polysorbate 80, or any excipient
             contained in the drug or vehicle formulation for MGA271 or pembrolizumab.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James Vasselli, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>MacroGenics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Soyoung Yun</last_name>
    <phone>240 552-8058</phone>
    <email>yuns@macrogenics.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Moffitt Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland Greenbaum Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jagdish Shetty, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>410-328-7680</phone>
      <email>jshetty@umm.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dan Zandberg, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Palak Thaker</last_name>
      <phone>212-304-5552</phone>
      <email>pt2433@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Naiyer Rizvi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania/Abramson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Phoung, RN</last_name>
      <email>david.phoung@uphs.upenn.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Maryann Ghallagher, RN</last_name>
      <phone>215-662-7758</phone>
      <email>maryann.gallagher@uphs.upenn.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Charu Aggarwal, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South Texas Accelerated Research Therapeutics, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Leslie Jimenez, RN, MSN</last_name>
      <phone>210-593-5252</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anthony Tolcher, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 3, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>June 16, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Malanoma, Non small cell lung cancer, SCCHN</keyword>
  <keyword>Other B7H3 expressing cancers</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triple Negative Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
