<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="508">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02590003</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1403013529</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02590003</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Single Agent Versus Combination Chemotherapy to Treat High-risk Elderly With Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Phase II Trial of Combination Versus Single Agent Chemotherapy in High-risk Elderly Patients With Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Institutional Review Board</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will enroll elderly patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer who are at
      high risk of developing chemotherapy toxicity (side effects). Patients will receive
      treatment with either a platinum-based doublet chemotherapy with carboplatin/nab-paclitaxel
      or single agent nab-paclitaxel of chemotherapy. Response to treatment and treatment toxicity
      will be compared in the two treatment groups to determine the best treatment strategy for
      this group of patients.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this trial is to compare the treatment failure-free survival rate
      in high-risk elderly patients, identified by geriatric assessment, treated with either a
      platinum-based doublet chemotherapy with carboplatin/nab-paclitaxel or single agent
      nab-paclitaxel in advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Treatment failure-free survival is
      the most appropriate primary outcome as it captures excessive toxicity due to chemotherapy
      in addition to death and disease progression.

      The secondary objectives are to evaluate grade 3-5 toxicities, overall response rate,
      progression free survival, symptom assessment, and overall survival between the two
      randomization arms.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment failure-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>start of treatment to disease progression/recurrence, up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>start of treatment to disease progression, up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>randomization to death from any cause, up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>grade 3-5 adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>from time of first treatment though week 13</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Assessment (measured by FACT-L Symptom Assessment Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Assessment (measured by FACT-L Symptom Assessment Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>week 6</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>symptoms are measured following 2 21-day cycles of chemotherapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Assessment (measured by FACT-L Symptom Assessment Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>week 12</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>symptoms are measured following 4 21-day cycles of chemotherapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Non-small Cell Lung</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Platinum-based doublet chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Carboplatin AUC 5 30 minute infusion IV on day 1
Nab-paclitaxel 100mg/mg2 30 minute infusion IV on days 1, 8 of a 21 day cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single agent chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>-Nab-paclitaxel 100mg/mg2 30 minute infusion IV on days 1, 8 of a 21 day cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carboplatin</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Platinum-based doublet chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nab-paclitaxel</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Platinum-based doublet chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single agent chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Patient able and willing to comply with study procedures as per protocol, including
             the geriatric assessment at the time of study enrollment.

          2. Patient able to understand and willing to sign and date the written voluntary
             informed consent form (ICF) at screening visit prior to any protocol-specific
             procedures.

          3. Patients must have histological or cytological confirmed primary non-small cell lung
             cancer (adenocarcinoma, large cell carcinoma, squamous, or unspecified). Disease must
             be stage IV Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC). Disease may be either newly diagnosed
             or recurrent after previous surgery and/or irradiation.

          4. Patients may have measurable or non-measurable disease documented by CT or MRI. The
             CT from a combined PET/CT may be used to document only non-measurable disease.
             Measurable disease must be assessed within 30 days prior to registration per response
             evaluation criteria in solid tumors (RECIST) v1.1. Pleural effusions, ascites and
             laboratory parameters are not acceptable as the only evidence of disease. Non-
             measurable disease must be assessed within 30 days prior to registration. All disease
             must be assessed and documented on the Baseline Tumor Assessment Form.

          5. Prior chemotherapy for curative intent is permitted providing the cytotoxic
             chemotherapy was completed ≥12 months prior to enrollment. Patients must have a CT or
             MRI scan of the brain to evaluate for CNS disease within 30 days prior to
             registration. Patient must not have brain metastases unless: (1) metastases have been
             treated and have remained controlled for at least two weeks following treatment, AND
             (2) patient has no residual neurological dysfunction off corticosteroids for at least
             1 day. Any radiation therapy completed prior to chemotherapy, except gamma-knife
             radiosurgery, 1 week prior to chemotherapy.

          6. Age &gt;70 years of age at time of signing of the informed consent form.

          7. Life expectancy of greater than 12 weeks.

          8. ECOG performance status 0-2 (See Appendix A)

          9. Patients must have a comprehensive geriatric assessment and chemotherapy toxicity
             assessment score between 10-17 (See Appendix B, D)

         10. Patients must have normal organ and marrow function as defined below:

               -  Leukocytes &gt;3,000/mcL

               -  ANC &gt; 1,500 cells/mm3 Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0g/dL

               -  Platelets &gt;100,000 cells/mm3

               -  Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 mg/dL (unless there is a known history of Gilberts
                  Syndrome).

               -  AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT) ≤2.5 X institutional upper limit of normal

               -  Alkaline phosphatase &lt; 2.5 X upper limit of normal in the absence of liver or
                  bone metastasis, or ≤ 5.0 × upper limit of normal range if bone or liver
                  metastases

               -  Creatinine clearance &gt;25 mL/min or creatinine &lt;1.5 mg/dL

         11. HIV-positive patients on combination antiretroviral therapy are eligible if they have
             been on ARVs for ≥6 months and undetectable viral loads.

         12. Patients must not have documented evidence of acute hepatitis or have an active or
             uncontrolled infection.

         13. No other prior malignancy is allowed except for the following: adequately treated
             basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in-situ cervical cancer, adequately treated
             Stage I or II cancer from which the patient is currently in complete remission, or
             any other cancer from which the patient has been disease-free for 5 years.

         14. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document
             in English or a Spanish consent &quot;short form&quot;. If language other than English or
             Spanish, then interpreter will be used to sign English consent form.

         15. Patients must have &lt; Grade 2 pre-existing peripheral neuropathy (per CTCAE)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Patients who have had palliative chemotherapy prior to entering the study &lt;12 months
             from enrollment or those who have not recovered from adverse events due to agents
             administered more than 4 weeks earlier.

          2. Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents or have received
             immunotherapy.

          3. Known EGFR or ALK mutated disease (molecular testing not required prior to study
             entry)

          4. History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic
             composition to carboplatin, or nab-paclitaxel.

          5. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with
             study requirements.

          6. Preexisting peripheral neuropathy of Grade 2, 3, or 4 (per Common Terminology
             Criteria for Adverse Events v4.0)

          7. Evidence of active brain metastases, including leptomeningeal involvement (prior
             evidence of brain metastasis are permitted only if treated and stable and off therapy
             for ≥ 2 weeks prior to signing Informed consent form. Magnetic Resonance Imaging of
             the brain (or Computed Tomography scan w/contrast) is preferred for diagnosis.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>71 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rogerio Lilenbaum, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06511</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rogerio Lilenbaum, MD</last_name>
      <phone>203-785-7564</phone>
      <email>rogerio.lilenbaum@yale.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 4, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 12, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
