<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="323">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02283749</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BrUOG 301</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02283749</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>BrUOG L301 With Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer and Bone Metastases</brief_title>
  <official_title>BrUOG L301: Xofigo Following Frontline-Line Chemotherapy For Patients With Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer and Bone Metastases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Angela Taber MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Rhode Island Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Miriam Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brown University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study patient's will receive the medicine Xofigo which is a radioactive drug that is
      FDA approved to treat prostate cancer that has spread to the bones. Xofigo has not
      previously been tested to treat lung cancer that has spread to the bones. Your doctors are
      studying the effects, good and bad, of Xofigo when used to treat lung cancer that has spread
      to the bones.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of symptomatic skeletal events (SSE) in patients receiving Xofigo with NSCLC and bone metastases</measure>
    <time_frame>Approximately every 2 months for up to a year</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Non Small Cell Lung Cancer With Bone Metastatses</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Xofigo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Xofigo, 50 kBq/kg body weight, will be administered in the nuclear medicine department as a bolus intravenous (IV) injection (up to 1 minute) at intervals of every 4 weeks for up to 6 cycles.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Xofigo</intervention_name>
    <description>This is a radio-isotope</description>
    <arm_group_label>Xofigo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Radium -223</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        Age ≥ 18 years. Advanced non-small cell lung cancer with bone metastases. Stable or
        responding disease after completion of initial systemic chemotherapy as defined by RECIST
        criteria. Site to submit confirmation to BrUOG.

        At least 3 weeks must have elapsed since completion of last chemotherapy or radiation
        prior to first dose of Xofigo. Patients are not permitted to receive any form of
        'maintenance' chemotherapy or biologic/targeted anticancer therapy while being treated on
        this study Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks (3 months). Patients with treated brain
        metastases are allowed, but must have brain imaging showing evidence of stability since
        most recent treatment for brain mets, prior to first dose of Xofigo. Scan must be sent to
        BrUOG with registration information before patient is registered on study.

        Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status of 0 - 1. Required entry
        laboratory parameters within 14 days of study entry: White Blood Cell Count (WBC) ≥
        3,000/mm3; Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥ 1,500/mm3; Platelet (PLT) count ≥
        100,000/mm3; Hemoglobin (Hgb) &gt; 9g/dl, Total bilirubin level ≤ 1.5 x institutional upper
        limit of normal (ULN); Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT)
        ≤ 2.5 x ULN ; Creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN; Albumin &gt; 2.5 g/dL.

        Concurrent treatment with bisphosphonates and denosumab is allowed. Information on start
        and stop date and drug with dose to be sent to BrUOG if patient to be treated
        concurrently.

        Prior skeletal related events (pathologic fracture, radiation or surgery to bone, or
        spinal cord compression) are allowed if they have been managed and now patient is stable
        for 4 weeks prior to study entry. Must submit how events managed to BrUOG for
        documentation to confirm eligibility criterion. (For example, if a patient experienced a
        SSE and had radiation for 2 weeks they must then be stable for 4 weeks after the
        completion of radiation prior to study entry) Subjects must be able to understand and be
        willing to sign the written informed consent form.

        All acute toxic effects related to prior treatment(s) must have resolved to NCI-CTCAE v4
        Grade 1 or less at the time of signing the Informed Consent Form (ICF) except for
        alopecia.

        Women of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test performed within
        7 days prior to the start of study drug. Post-menopausal women (defined as no menses for
        at least 1 year) and surgically sterilized women are not required to undergo a pregnancy
        test.

        Subjects (men and women) of childbearing potential must agree to use adequate
        contraception beginning at the signing of the ICF until at least 30 days after the last
        dose of study drug. The definition of adequate contraception will be based on the judgment
        of the treating physician.

        Willing and able to comply with the protocol, including follow-up visits and examinations

        Exclusion Criteria:

        Received systemic therapy with radionuclides (e.g., strontium-89, samarium-153,
        rhenium-186, or rhenium-188, or Radium Ra 223 dichloride) for the treatment of bony
        metastases No prior invasive malignancy within the prior two years. However, patients with
        an early stage malignancy that is not expected to require treatment in the next 2 years
        (such as early stage, resected breast cancer or asymptomatic prostate cancer) are eligible
        Untreated brain metastases. Any other serious illness or medical condition that in the
        investigator's opinion would interfere with protocol treatment, such as but not limited
        to: Any active infection ≥ National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for
        Adverse Events (NCI-CTCAE) version 4 Grade 2: Cardiac failure New York Heart Association
        (NYHA) III or IV Women who are pregnant or breast-feeding. Inability to comply with the
        protocol and/or not willing or who will not be available for follow-up assessments.

        Any condition which, in the investigator's opinion, makes the subject unsuitable for trial
        participation.

        Concurrent anti-cancer therapy (chemotherapy, radiation therapy, surgery, immunotherapy,
        biologic therapy, or tumor embolization) other than Ra 223 dichloride.

        Major surgery within 28 days of starting study drug. Central venous catheter placement is
        not considered major surgery.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rhode Island Hospital and The Miriam Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Providence</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02903</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kristen M Mitchell</last_name>
      <phone>401-863-3000</phone>
      <email>kristen_mitchell@brown.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kayla Rosati, EdM</last_name>
      <phone>4018633000</phone>
      <email>kayla_rosati@brown.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Angela Taber, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Richard Noto, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Don Yoo, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thomas DiPetrillo, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 17, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>October 30, 2014</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brown University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Angela Taber MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>NCSLC</keyword>
  <keyword>lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>non small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>bone metastases</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
