<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="248">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02737501</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AP26113-13-301</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02737501</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ALTA-1L Study: A Phase 3 Study of Brigatinib Versus Crizotinib in ALK-positive Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>ALTA-1L</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 3 Multicenter Open-label Study of Brigatinib (AP26113) Versus Crizotinib in Patients With ALK-positive Advanced Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ariad Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ariad Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Phase 3 Multicenter Open-label Study of Brigatinib (AP26113) versus Crizotinib in
      ALK-positive Advanced Lung Cancer Patients
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this phase III, randomized, open-label, comparative, multicenter,
      international study is to compare the efficacy and safety of brigatinib to that of
      crizotinib in anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK)-positive locally advanced or metastatic
      non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients who have not previously been treated with an ALK
      inhibitor. Participants will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to receive either brigatinib, 90
      milligrams (mg) orally once daily (QD) for 7 days, then a 180 mg orally QD, or crizotinib,
      250 mg orally twice daily (BID). Participants will receive treatment until disease
      progression, intolerable toxicity, consent withdrawal, or death. The total estimated
      duration of the study is at least 5 years, including 2 years to accrue patients, with at
      least 3 years for treatment and follow-up.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS) as assessed by a blinded Independent Review Committee (bIRC)</measure>
    <time_frame>At least 36 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At least 36 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Defined as the proportion of the patients who are confirmed to have achieved CR or PR using RECIST v. 1.1 criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracranial ORR</measure>
    <time_frame>At least 36 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Defined as the proportion of the patients who have achieved CR or PR in the CNS.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracranial PFS</measure>
    <time_frame>At least 36 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Defined as the time from randomization until first CNS disease progression is documented, or death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>At least 36 months.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Defined as the time from randomization until death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life (HRQoL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Until 30 days after the last dose of study treatment.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Defined as the perceived quality of the patient's life, which includes self-reported multidimensional measures of physical and mental health.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Until at least 30 days after the last dose of study treatment.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>To evaluate the safety and tolerability of brigatinib in the Intention to Treat (ITT) population. Measured by routine physical and laboratory evaluations, ECG, and adverse event (AE) monitoring.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Steady state pharmacokinetic (PK) parameter: Maximum Plasma Concentration [Cmax]</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 months.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>PK samples will be taken to assess limited elements of PK in the Treated population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Steady state pharmacokinetic (PK) parameter: Minimum plasma concentration [Cmin]</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 months.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>PK samples will be taken to assess limited elements of PK in the Treated population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Steady state pharmacokinetic (PK) parameter: Area Under the Curve [AUC]</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 months.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>PK samples will be taken to assess limited elements of PK in the Treated population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Steady state pharmacokinetic (PK) parameter: Time to maximum plasma concentration (Tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 months.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>PK samples will be taken to assess limited elements of PK in the Treated population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Steady state pharmacokinetic (PK) parameter: Apparent oral clearance [CL/F]</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 months.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>PK samples will be taken to assess limited elements of PK in the Treated population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">270</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Advanced Malignancies</condition>
  <condition>Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Brigatinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Brigatinib will be administered orally to eligible patients with locally advanced or metastatic ALK+ NSCLC naïve to ALK inhibitors at a dose of 90 mg QD for 7 days, then 180 mg QD, continuously, with or without food until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, withdrawal of consent or death.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Crizotinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Crizotinib will be administered to eligible patients with locally advanced or metastatic ALK+ NSCLC naïve to ALK inhibitors as 250 mg orally BID, with or without food until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, withdrawal of consent or death.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Brigatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Brigatinib will be administered orally to eligible patients with locally advanced or metastatic ALK+ NSCLC naïve to ALK inhibitors at a dose of 90 mg QD for 7 days, then 180 mg QD, continuously, until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, withdrawal of consent or death.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Brigatinib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Xalkori (crizotinib)</intervention_name>
    <description>Crizotinib will be administered to eligible patients with locally advanced or metastatic ALK+ NSCLC naïve to ALK inhibitors as 250 mg orally BID, until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, withdrawal of consent or death.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Crizotinib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Crizotinib</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Have histologically or cytologically confirmed stage IIIB (and not a candidate for
             definitive multimodality therapy) or stage IV NSCLC.

          2. Must have documented ALK rearrangement.

          3. Have sufficient tumor tissue available for central analysis.

          4. Have at least 1 measurable (i.e., target) lesion per RECIST v1.1.

          5. Recovered from toxicities related to prior anticancer therapy to NCI CTCAE v 4.0
             grade ≤1.

          6. Are a male or female patient ≥18 years old.

          7. Have adequate organ function, as defined by the study protocol.

          8. Have Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤2.

          9. Have normal QT interval on screening ECG evaluation, defined as QT interval corrected
             (Fridericia) (QTcF) of ≤450 milliseconds (msec) in males or ≤470 msec in females.

         10. For female patients of childbearing potential, have a negative pregnancy test
             documented prior to randomization.

         11. For female and male patients who are fertile, agree to use a highly effective form of
             contraception, as defined by the study protocol.

         12. Provide signed and dated informed consent indicating that the patient has been
             informed of all pertinent aspects of the study, including the potential risks, and is
             willingly participating.

         13. Have the willingness and ability to comply with scheduled visit and study procedures.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Previously received an investigational antineoplastic agent for NSCLC.

          2. Previously received any prior TKI, including ALK-targeted TKIs.

          3. Previously received more than 1 regimen of systemic anticancer therapy for locally
             advanced or metastatic disease.

          4. Received chemotherapy or radiation within 14 days of first dose of study drug, except
             stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS) or stereotactic body radiation therapy (SBRT).

          5. Received anti-neoplastic monoclonal antibodies within 30 days of the first dose of
             study drug.

          6. Had major surgery within 30 days of the first dose of study drug, minor surgical
             procedures such as catheter placement or minimally invasive biopsies are allowed.

          7. Have been diagnosed with another primary malignancy other than NSCLC, except for
             adequately treated non-melanoma skin cancer or cervical cancer in situ; definitively
             treated non-metastatic prostate cancer; or patients with another primary malignancy
             who are definitively relapse-free with at least 3 years elapsed since the diagnosis
             of the other primary malignancy.

          8. Have symptomatic CNS metastases (parenchymal or leptomeningeal) at screening or
             asymptomatic disease requiring an increasing dose of corticosteroids to control
             symptoms within 7 days prior to randomization.

          9. Have current spinal cord compression (symptomatic or asymptomatic and detected by
             radiographic imaging). Patients with leptomeningeal disease and without cord
             compression are allowed.

         10. Be pregnant, planning a pregnancy, or breastfeeding

         11. Have significant, uncontrolled, or active cardiovascular disease, as defined by the
             study protocol.

         12. Have uncontrolled hypertension.

         13. Have a history or the presence at baseline of pulmonary interstitial disease,
             drug-related pneumonitis, or radiation pneumonitis.

         14. Have an ongoing or active infection.

         15. Have a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection.

         16. Have a known or suspected hypersensitivity to brigatinib or its excipients and/or
             crizotinib or its excipients.

         17. Have malabsorption syndrome or other gastrointestinal (GI) illness or condition.

         18. Have any condition or illness that, in the opinion of the investigator, would
             compromise patient safety or interfere with the evaluation of the study drug.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>David Kerstein, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(617) 494-0400</phone>
    <email>David.Kerstein@ARIAD.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sergio Santillana, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(617) 494-0400</phone>
    <email>Sergio.Santillana@ARIAD.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Camidge, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 12, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 30, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-small cell lung carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Epithelial lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Squamous cell carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Large cell carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Adenocarcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Anaplastic Lymphoma Kinase (ALK)</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced Cancers</keyword>
  <keyword>Brigatinib</keyword>
  <keyword>AP26113</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Crizotinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
