<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="539">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00034216</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>020179</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>02-C-0179</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00034216</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Collection of Blood From Patients With Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Biospecimen Acquisition From Human Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Federal Government</authority>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will collect blood from patients with cancer to study the level of cells which
      decrease the immune response (suppressor cells) before and after chemotherapy. Patients 18
      years of age and older with cancer may participate. This study does not involve treatment.

      Participants will have about 50 ml (3 tablespoonfuls) of blood drawn. Depending on their
      condition, patients may be invited to enroll in a clinical research study involving
      chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or surgery. Additional 40-ml blood samples may be drawn during
      the course of treatment.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:

        -  To date, the underlying mechanisms of tumor-specific immune suppression have not been
           well understood in cancer patients, nor has the effect of chemotherapy on these been
           well characterized.

        -  cTC analysis potentially provides valuable information regarding the genetic and
           molecular profile of tumors and may predict progression-free survival (PFS) and overall
           survival (OS) earlier than the standard evaluation techniques using radiological scans.

        -  Profiling of miRNA expression in serum exosomes from healthy controls an cancer
           patients might be a useful diagnostic test for early cancer detection with non-invasive
           methods.

        -  Microtubule-associated modifications are attractive biomarkers.

        -  Results suggest that urinary soluble Met may have utility as a bladder cancer marker
           for screening, treatment follow-up and clinical trial design.

        -  The role of commensal gut microbiota in both the innate and adaptive immune responses
           to tumors as well as with the use of anticancer agents is under study.

      Objectives:

        -  Analyze biospecimens such as tissue, urine, saliva, stool and blood components, which
           include serum, leukocytes, peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC), and circulating
           tumor cells (cTC), of human subjects.

        -  Analyze normal and/or tumor serum and tissue samples to identify mechanisms of drug
           related adverse events, and correlate these with treatment toxicity and clinical
           parameters.

        -  Undertake genetic analysis of both prokaryotic and eucaryotic samples for advanced
           mutational analysis.

      Eligibility:

        -  Patients whose biospecimens are of interest to NIH investigators.

        -  18 year of age or older.

      Design:

      Patient cases will be evaluated at NCI or Interventional Radiology, NIH Clinical Center.
      Blood, tissue, urine, saliva or other samples may be collected at the initial visit and at
      follow-up visits.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2002</start_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <study_design>Time Perspective: Prospective</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Analyze tissue, urine, saliva, and blood components, which include serum, leukocytes, and circulating tumor cells (cTC), of human subjects.</measure>
    <time_frame>On-going</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Undertake genetic analysis of both procariotic and eucariotic samples for advanced mutational analysis.</measure>
    <time_frame>On-going</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Analyze normal and/or tumor serum and tissue samples to identify mechanisms of drug related adverse events, and correlate these with treatment toxicity and clinical parameters.</measure>
    <time_frame>On-going</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Colon Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Liver Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:

        Patients 18 years of age and older are eligible.

        Patients must have a performance status of ECOG 0, 1, 2, or 3 for admission to this
        protocol.

        INCLUSION FOR APHERESIS:

        Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 10 mg/dL and platelet count &gt; 75,000/mm(3)

        Weight greater than 25 kg

        HIV negative

        Prothrombin Time within normal limits

        Partial Thromboplastin Time within normal limits

        Medically indicated central line in place or adequate peripheral venous access

        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:

        Children will not be eligible.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James L Gulley, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sheri A McMahon, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-9812</phone>
    <email>smcmahon@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>James L Gulley, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-4916</phone>
    <email>gulleyj@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>(888) NCI-1937</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2002-C-0179.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shimizu J, Yamazaki S, Sakaguchi S. Induction of tumor immunity by removing CD25+CD4+ T cells: a common basis between tumor immunity and autoimmunity. J Immunol. 1999 Nov 15;163(10):5211-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10553041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jonuleit H, Schmitt E, Stassen M, Tuettenberg A, Knop J, Enk AH. Identification and functional characterization of human CD4(+)CD25(+) T cells with regulatory properties isolated from peripheral blood. J Exp Med. 2001 Jun 4;193(11):1285-94.</citation>
    <PMID>11390435</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Levings MK, Sangregorio R, Roncarolo MG. Human cd25(+)cd4(+) t regulatory cells suppress naive and memory T cell proliferation and can be expanded in vitro without loss of function. J Exp Med. 2001 Jun 4;193(11):1295-302.</citation>
    <PMID>11390436</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 11, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>April 24, 2002</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Suppressor Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>T-cells</keyword>
  <keyword>CD4+/CD25+ Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood Sample</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>No</is_fda_regulated>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
