<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="99">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02649673</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCRI REFMAL 314</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02649673</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>LCL161 Plus Topotecan for Patients With Relapsed/Refractory Small Cell Lung Cancer and Select Gynecologic Malignancies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase Ib Dose-Escalation Study of LCL161 in Combination With Oral Topotecan for Patients With Relapsed/Refractory Small Cell Lung Cancer (SCLC) and Select Gynecologic Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>SCRI Development Innovations, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>SCRI Development Innovations, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This trial will investigate the combination of two anti-cancer agents to treat patients with
      relapsed/refractory small cell lung cancer (SCLC) and ovarian cancers. Oral topotecan has US
      FDA approval for treating select gynecological cancers and SCLC. LCL161 is an
      investigational product that has been shown in clinical trials to work together with other
      anti-cancer agents. In this trial, investigators will determine the optimal dose of LCL161
      and topotecan to administer to patients with relapsed/refractory SCLC and ovarian cancers,
      and examine the safety profile of the drug combination.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, multicenter, non-randomized dose-escalation study of oral LCL161
      administered in combination with oral topotecan. Topotecan is US FDA approved for treating
      metastatic ovarian cancer, stage IV-B cervical cancer, and small cell lung cancer (SCLC).
      LCL161, an investigational product, is an oral small-molecule antagonist of inhibitors of
      apoptosis proteins (IAPs). Preclinical data suggests that IAP antagonists work in synergy
      with other anti-cancer agents. This study is designed to evaluate the combination of these
      two agents in patients with SCLC and ovarian cancers where treatment with topotecan would be
      appropriate. The study will be conducted in 2 parts. In the dose-escalation part of the
      study, patients with relapsed/refractory SCLC and gynecologic malignancies will be eligible
      for enrollment to determine the optimal dose of the drug combination to be administered.
      Patients can continue treatment until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. The
      dose-expansion part of the study is limited to patients with ovarian cancer and
      relapsed/refractory SCLC (2 cohorts with 12 patients each) to further assess safety and
      preliminary anti-tumor activity. Up to 52 patients are planned for enrollment at 3 centers
      in the U.S.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs) as a measure of safety and tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days (one cycle)</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>The maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of the LCL161/topotecan combination is defined as the highest dose that results in dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs) for 2 of 6 patients during the first 21 days (1 cycle) of treatment, assessed using National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE) v4.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of acute and chronic treatment-emergent adverse events to further assess safety of the regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>weekly for first 3 weeks then every 3 weeks thereafter, projected 6 months.</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>The frequency and severity of AEs for all patients receiving at least one dose of treatment will be analyzed per NCI CTCAE v4.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best overall response</measure>
    <time_frame>every 6 weeks, projected 6 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Preliminary anti-tumor activity associated with combination treatment will be described using the best overall response recorded from start of treatment until disease progression, assessed per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) v1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">52</enrollment>
  <condition>Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LCL161+topotecan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose Escalation: Groups of 3-6 patients per dose level (DL) will initiate treatment in escalating doses until the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) is reached. MTD is defined as the highest combination of doses that results in dose-limiting toxicities for 2 of 6 patients per dosing group.
LCL161: orally, 1200 mg/week (DL 1 and DL 2) on Days 1, 8, 15 of each 21-day cycle. Maximum dose not to exceed 1200 mg/week.
topotecan: orally, 1.8 mg/m2 per day (DL 1); 2.3 mg/m2 per day (DL 2) for first 5 days of each 21-day cycle. Maximum dose not to exceed 2.3 mg/m2 per day.
Dose Expansion: 24 additional patients will be treated at the MTD in 2 cohorts (SCLC-12 patients; ovarian cancer-12 patients)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LCL161</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>LCL161+topotecan</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Topotecan</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>LCL161+topotecan</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hycamtin®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        KEY POINTS:

          -  Dose Escalation Portion: Must have histological diagnosis of relapsed/refractory SCLC
             or gynecological malignancy for which topotecan would be indicated.

          -  Dose Expansion Portion: Must have histological diagnosis of relapsed/refractory SCLC
             or ovarian cancer for which topotecan would be indicated.

          -  Patients with ovarian cancer must have evidence of recurrent epithelial ovarian,
             fallopian tube, or primary peritoneal cancer and must have previously received a
             platinum- and taxane-based chemotherapy regimen.

          -  Patients with SCLC must have received platinum-based chemotherapy.

          -  Measurable or non-measurable (but evaluable) disease

          -  Adequate organ function

          -  Life expectancy ≥ 12 weeks.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients with brain metastases may be enrolled if radiation and/or surgery have been
             completed and a serial evaluation by computed tomography or magnetic resonance
             imaging over 2 months demonstrates stable disease.

          -  More than 3 prior cytotoxic chemotherapy regimens given in the metastatic setting.

          -  Patients who are currently receiving certain medications that cannot be discontinued
             prior to starting study drug (including but not limited to: corticosteroids, chronic
             immunosuppressive treatment, CYP2C8 inhibitors, CYP3A substrates.)

          -  Clinically significant heart disease.

          -  Patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding.

          -  Women of childbearing potential unless they are using highly effective methods of
             contraception during dosing and for at least 6 months after study treatment.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeffrey Infante, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>SCRI Development Innovations, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>SCRI Development Innovations</last_name>
    <phone>1-877-MY-1-SCRI</phone>
    <email>asksarah@scri-innovations.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Florida Cancer Specialists-Sarasota</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sarasota</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oklahoma University Health Science Center/Stephenson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tennessee Oncology PLLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 25, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 5, 2016</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lung carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>topotecan</keyword>
  <keyword>Hycamtin</keyword>
  <keyword>ovarian neoplasms</keyword>
  <keyword>LCL161</keyword>
  <keyword>IAP inhibitors</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Topotecan</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
