<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="156">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02546986</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CC-486-NSCL-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02546986</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Efficacy Study of CC-486 With MK-3475 to Treat Locally Advanced or Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Multicenter, Randomized, Placebo Controlled, Double Blind Study to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of CC-486 (Oral Azacitidine) in Combination With Pembrolizumab (MK-3475) Versus Pembrolizumab Plus Placebo in Subjects With Previously Treated Locally Advanced or Metastatic Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Celgene Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Celgene Corporation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>France: Agence Nationale de Sécurité du Médicament et des produits de santé</authority>
    <authority>France: Committe for the Protection of Personnes</authority>
    <authority>France: Conseil National del'Ordre des Médecins</authority>
    <authority>Germany: Ethics Commission</authority>
    <authority>Germany: Federal Institute for Drugs and Medical Devices</authority>
    <authority>Greece: Ethics Committee</authority>
    <authority>Greece: National Organization of Medicines</authority>
    <authority>Italy: Ethics Committee</authority>
    <authority>Italy: The Italian Medicines Agency</authority>
    <authority>Spain: Ethics Committee</authority>
    <authority>Spain: Agencia Espanola de Medicamentos y Productos Sanitarios</authority>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether the combination therapy of CC-486 (oral
      azacitidine) and pembrolizumab provides improved patient outcomes compared to pembrolizumab
      alone in subjects with previously treated locally advanced or metastatic non-small cell lung
      cancer.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2, multicenter, international, randomized, placebo controlled, double-blind
      study to assess the safety and efficacy of CC-486 and pembrolizumab combination therapy
      versus pembrolizumab plus placebo in previously treated subjects with locally advanced or
      metastatic Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) who have received one prior platinum-based
      chemotherapy regimen.

      Approximately 90 subjects will be randomized 1:1 to receive CC-486 plus pembrolizumab or
      placebo plus pembrolizumab as follows:

        -  Arm A: CC-486 300 mg administered orally daily on days 1-14 plus pembrolizumab 200 mg
           administered as a 30-minute IV infusion on day 1 of a 21-day cycle

        -  Arm B: Placebo administered orally daily on days 1-14 plus pembrolizumab 200 mg
           administered as a 30-minute IV infusion on day 1 of a 21-day cycle Safety will be
           evaluated by an independent data monitoring committee (DMC). A safety analysis will be
           performed in the first 10 subjects in each arm after the last enrolled subject has
           completed 1 cycle of treatment.

      Randomization will be stratified between treatment arms by:

      - Histology (non-squamous versus squamous) The decision to discontinue a subject, which will
      not be delayed or refused by the Sponsor, remains the responsibility of the treating
      physician. However, prior to discontinuing a subject, the Investigator may contact the
      medical monitor and forward appropriate supporting documents for review and discussion.

      The study will be conducted in compliance with the International Council on Harmonisation
      (ICH) of Technical Requirements for Registration of Pharmaceuticals for Human Use/Good
      Clinical Practice (GCP) and applicable regulatory requirements.

      Primary analysis will be conducted when 70 PFS events have occurred.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Double Blind (Subject, Caregiver, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor), Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 12 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The time from the randomization date to disease progression assessed by Investigator according to RECIST version 1.1 guideline or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with Stable Disease (SD) for ≥ 18 weeks measured via CT scan or MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Stable disease is defined as neither sufficient shrinkage to qualify for partial response nor sufficient increase to qualify for progressive disease, taking as reference the smallest sum of the longest diameter of target lesions while on study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with Complete Response (CR) measured via CT scan or MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Complete response is defined as the disappearance of all target lesions. Any pathological lymph nodes (whether target or non-target) must have reduction in short axis to &lt;10 mm.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with Partial Response (PR) measured via CT scan or MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Partial response is defined as at least a 30% decrease in the sum of the longest diameter of target lesions, taking as reference the baseline sum diameters.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with Disease Control Rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The percentage of subjects who have achieved stable disease for 18 weeks or more, complete response, or partial response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The time from the date of randomization to the date of death (any cause). Subjects who are alive will be censored at the last time that the subject was known to be alive. The OS analysis may also be conducted at the time when 70 deaths occur, in addition to when the primary analysis is performed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects who achieved Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The percentage of subjects that achieve a confirmed complete or partial response as assessed by the Investigator using RECIST version 1.1 guideline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics ‐ Maximum Observed Concentration (Cmax) for CC-486</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximatly 2 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Maximum observed plasma concentration, obtained directly from the observed concentration versus time data.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics - Area Under the Curve (AUC) for CC-486</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximatly 2 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Area under the concentration-time curve from Time 0 to the time of the last quantifiable concentration, calculated by linear trapezoidal method when concentrations are increasing and the logarithmic trapezoidal method when concentrations are decreasing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics ‐Time to Maximum Concentration (Tmax) for CC-486</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximatly 2 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time to Cmax, obtained directly from the observed concentration versus time data</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics ‐ Terminal Half-Life (t1/2) for CC-486</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximatly 2 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Terminal phase half-life in plasma, calculated as [(ln 2)/Tz]]. t1/2 will only be calculated when a reliable estimate for z can be obtained</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics ‐ Apparent Total Body Clearance (CL/F) for CC-486</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximatly 2 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Apparent total clearance, calculated as [Dose/AUCinf]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics ‐ (Apparent Volume of Distribution (Vz/F) for CC-486</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximatly 2 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Apparent volume of distribution, calculated as [(CL/F)/Tz ]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>Number of participants with adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CC-486 plus Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this experimental arm, subjects will receive a combination of two investigational drugs, CC-486 and pembrolizumab.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab plus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this control arm, subjects will receive an active comparator, the investigational drug pembrolizumab. Placebo will also be administered in order to allow blinding of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CC-486</intervention_name>
    <description>Each cycle will be 21 days. CC-486 will be administered orally at a dose of 300 mg daily on days 1-14 of each 21-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CC-486 plus Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Oral Azacitidine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Each cycle will be 21 days. Pembrolizumab will be administered as a 30-minute IV infusion on day 1 of each 21-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CC-486 plus Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab plus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MK-3475</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Each cycle will be 21 days. Placebo will be administered orally daily on days 1-14 of each 21-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab plus Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

        - 1. Subject is ≥ 18 years of age at the time of signing the informed consent form.

        2. Subject has histologically or cytologically confirmed squamous or non-squamous NSCLC.
        3. Subject has stage IIIB or IV NSCLC (American Joint Committee on Cancer [AJCC] Staging
        Manual, 7th edition [Edge, 2009]) and was pretreated with only 1 prior systemic platinum
        based chemotherapy. 4. Subject has provided a formalin fixed tumor tissue sample from a
        biopsy of a tumor lesion either at the time of or after the diagnosis of metastatic
        disease has been made AND from a site not previously irradiated to assess for PD-L1
        status. Fine needle aspirates, endobronchial ultrasound (EBUS) or cell blocks are not
        acceptable. Needle or excisional biopsies, or resected tissue is required. Archival tissue
        may be acceptable.

        Submission of formalin-fixed paraffin embedded tumor tissue sample blocks are preferred;
        if submitting unstained slides, the slides should be freshly cut and submitted to the
        testing laboratory within 14 days from site slide sectioning date otherwise a new specimen
        will be requested. 5. Subject has radiographically-documented measurable disease, as per
        RECIST 1.1.

        6. Subject has an ECOG performance status of 0 to 1. 7. Subject has adequate organ
        functions, evidenced by the following:

          1. AST (SGOT), ALT (SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x upper limit of normal range (ULN), or ≤ 5 x ULN range
             if liver metastasis present

          2. Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN

          3. Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN

          4. Potassium within normal range, or correctable with supplements 8. Subject has
             adequate bone marrow function, evidenced by the following:

        a. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 109 cells/L b. Platelets ≥ 100 x 109 cells/L c.
        Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL d. International normalized ratio (INR) or prothrombin time (PT) ≤ 1.5
        x ULN unless subject is receiving anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or PTT is within
        therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants e. Activated partial thromboplastin
        time (aPTT) ≤ 1.5 x ULN unless subject is receiving anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or
        PTT is within therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants 9. Female of
        childbearing potential (FCBP) (defined as a sexually mature woman who 1) has not undergone
        a hysterectomy (the surgical removal of the uterus) or bilateral oophorectomy (the
        surgical removal of both ovaries) or, 2) if ≥ 45 years old has not been naturally
        postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months (ie, has had menses at any time during
        the preceding 24 consecutive months)) must:

          1. Have two negative pregnancy tests as verified by the Investigator prior to starting
             study therapy. She must agree to ongoing pregnancy testing during the course of the
             study, and after end of study treatment. This applies even if the subject practices
             true abstinence* from heterosexual contact.

          2. Either commit to true abstinence* from heterosexual contact (which must be reviewed
             on a monthly basis) or agree to use, and be able to comply with two effective methods
             of contraception without interruption, 28 days prior to starting IP, during the study
             therapy (including dose interruptions), and for 120 days after discontinuation (or
             longer if required by local requirements) of study therapy. The two methods of
             contraception can either be two barrier methods or a barrier method plus a hormonal
             method to prevent pregnancy. 10. Male subjects must practice true abstinence* (which
             must be reviewed on a monthly basis) or agree to the use a condom during sexual
             contact with a pregnant female or a female of childbearing potential while
             participating in the study, during dose interruptions and for at least 3 months
             following investigational product discontinuation (or longer if required by local
             requirements), even if he has undergone a successful vasectomy.

             * True abstinence is acceptable when this is in line with the preferred and usual
             lifestyle of the subject. Note: Periodic abstinence (eg, calendar, ovulation,
             symptothermal, postovulation methods) and withdrawal are not acceptable methods of
             contraception. 11. Subject is willing to adhere to the study visit schedule and other
             protocol requirements.

             12. Subject understands and voluntarily signs an informed consent document prior to
             any study related assessments/procedures are conducted.

             Exclusion Criteria:

             - 1. Subject with non-squamous histology has known or unknown sensitizing EGFR and/or
             positive ALK mutation. Note: Subjects with squamous histology and unknown EGFR and
             ALK mutational status are eligible. 2. Subject has received more than one line of
             therapy for stage IIIB or IV disease 3. Subject has been previously treated with
             azacitidine (any formulation), decitabine, or any other hypomethylating agent. 4.
             Subject has received prior therapy with any other anti-PD-1, or PD-L1 or PD-L2 agent
             or an antibody targeting other immuno-regulatory receptors or mechanism, including
             participation in any other pembrolizumab trial and treatment with pembrolizumab.

        a. Examples of such antibodies include (but are not limited to) antibodies against
        indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase (IDO), PD-L1, IL-2R, glucocorticoid-induced tumor necrosis
        factor receptor (GITR). 5. Subject has had a prior monoclonal antibody within 4 weeks
        prior to study Day 1 or who has not recovered (i.e. ≤ Grade 1 or at baseline) from adverse
        events due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier. 6. Subject is currently
        participating and receiving study therapy or has participated in a study of an
        investigational agent and received study therapy or used an investigational device within
        4 weeks prior to administration of pembrolizumab and CC-486 7. Subject has previous severe
        hypersensitivity reaction to another monoclonal antibody (mAb). 8. Subject has a known or
        suspected hypersensitivity to azacitidine, mannitol, or any other ingredient used in the
        manufacture of CC-486 (see the Azacitidine IB). 9. Subject has had radiotherapy ≤ 4 weeks
        or limited field radiation for palliation 10. Subject has received radiation therapy to
        the lung that is &gt; 30 Gy within 6 months of the first dose of trial treatment 11. Subject
        has received a live-virus vaccination within 30 days of planned treatment start. Seasonal
        flu vaccines that do not contain live virus are permitted. 12. Subject has not recovered
        from the acute toxic effects of prior anticancer therapy, radiation, or major
        surgery/significant trauma. 13. Subject has an active infection requiring therapy. 14.
        Subject has had an allogenetic tissue/solid organ transplant. 15. Subject has active
        autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment within the past 2 years (eg, with
        use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive drugs). Replacement
        therapy (eg, thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid replacement therapy for
        adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a form of systemic treatment.
        16. Subject has known active Hepatitis B, Hepatitis C or tuberculosis. Active Hepatitis B
        is defined as a known positive HBsAg result. Active Hepatitis C is defined by a known
        positive Hep C Ab result and known quantitative HCV ribonucleic acid (RNA) results greater
        than the lower limits of detection of the assay. 17. Subject has had any other malignancy
        within 5 years prior to randomization, with the exception of adequately treated in situ
        carcinoma of the cervix, uterus, or nonmelanomatous skin cancer (all treatment of which
        should have been completed 6 months prior to enrollment). 18. Subject has a history of
        inflammatory bowel disease (eg, Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis), celiac disease (ie,
        sprue), prior gastrectomy or upper bowel removal, or any other gastrointestinal disorder
        or defect that would interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion
        of the IP and/or predispose the subject to an increased risk of gastrointestinal toxicity.
        19. Subject has persistent diarrhea or clinically significant malabsorption syndrome or
        known sub-acute bowel obstruction ≥ Grade 2, despite medical management 20. Subject has
        significant active cardiac disease within the previous 6 months including unstable angina
        or angina requiring surgical or medical intervention, significant cardiac arrhythmia, or
        New York Heart Association (NYHA) class 3 or 4 congestive heart failure. 21. Subject has
        history of interstitial lung disease (ILD) OR a history of pneumonitis that has required
        oral or IV steroids. Subjects whose pneumonitis was solely as a result of radiation
        therapy for their NSCLC would not be excluded from the study unless they received oral/IV
        steroids to manage the pneumonitis. 22. Subject has a known history or current diagnosis
        of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, regardless of treatment status. 23.
        Subject has any other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical condition that would,
        in the Investigator's judgment, contraindicate patient participation in the clinical study
        (eg, chronic pancreatitis, etc.). 24. Subject with uncontrolled or symptomatic central
        nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis Subjects with controlled
        and asymptomatic CNS metastases may participate in this trial. The patient must have
        completed any prior treatment for CNS metastases (must include radiotherapy and/or
        surgery) ≥ 28 days (≥ 14 days for stereotactic radiosurgery) and, if on corticosteroid
        therapy, should be receiving a stable dose of no greater than 4 mg/d dexamethasone (or
        equivalent anti-inflammatory potency of another corticosteroid) for at least 14 days
        before start of study treatment). Patients must not be receiving corticosteroids for brain
        metastases. 25. Subject has not recovered from the acute toxic effects (Common Terminology
        Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] grade ≤ 1) of prior anticancer therapy, radiation, or
        major surgery/significant trauma (except alopecia or other toxicities not considered a
        safety risk for the subject at the Investigator's discretion). 26. Subject has an impaired
        ability to swallow oral medication. 27. Subject is pregnant or breast feeding. 28. Subject
        has any condition that confounds the ability to interpret data from the study.

        29. Subject is or has an immediate family member (spouse or children) who is
        investigational site or sponsor staff directly involved with this trial, unless
        prospective Institutional Review Board (IRB) approval (by chair or designee) is given
        allowing exception to this criterion for a specific subject.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Abderrahim (Rahim) Fandi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Celgene</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Associate Director Clinical Trial Disclosure</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-260-1599</phone>
    <email>clinicaltrialdisclosure@celgene.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Palo Verde Hematology Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glendale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCLA Hematology Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Georgetown University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20057</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Cancer and Blood Center, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30607</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64132</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington Univ School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>St. Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North Shore Hematology Oncology Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>East Setauket</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11733-3456</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Israel Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10003</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NYU Langone Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10016</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt Univ Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232-6307</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Leon Berard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <zip>69008</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Amiens Picardie- Hôpital Nord</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <zip>13915</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU Rennes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rennes</city>
        <zip>35033</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Toulouse</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Gustave Roussy IGR Centre de Lutte Contre le Canc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif</city>
        <zip>94805</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Evangelische Lungenklinik Berlin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>13125</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Helios Klinikum Emil Von Behring</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>14165</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Klinikum Esslingen GmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Esslingen Am Neckar</city>
        <zip>73730</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitatsklinikum Koln</name>
      <address>
        <city>Köln</city>
        <zip>50937</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Klinik Lowenstein gGmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Löwenstein</city>
        <zip>74245</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sotiria Chest Hospital of Athens</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <zip>11527</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Attikon General University Hospital of Athens</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <zip>124 62</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IASO General</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <zip>15562</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Agioi Anargyroi Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ilio</city>
        <zip>13122</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro Di Riferimento Oncologico</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aviano</city>
        <zip>33081</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria Policlinico Vittorio Emanuele</name>
      <address>
        <city>Catania</city>
        <zip>95122</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ospedale San Raffaele S.r.l.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <zip>20132</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Nazionale Dei Tumori</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <zip>20133</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Nazionale Per Lo Studio E La Cura Dei Tumori Fondazione Giovanni Pascale</name>
      <address>
        <city>Napoli, Campania</city>
        <zip>80131</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O.U. Maggiore della Carità</name>
      <address>
        <city>Novara</city>
        <zip>28100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Policlinico Universitario Campus Biomedico Di Roma</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <zip>128</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital De Cruces</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baracaldo</city>
        <zip>48903</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Vall D'hebrón</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Ramon y Cajal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28034</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fundacion Jimenez Daaz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28040</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clinico San Carlos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28040</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital General Universitario de Valencia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46014</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Greece</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 11, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>August 20, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CC-486</keyword>
  <keyword>Azacitidine</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral azacitidine</keyword>
  <keyword>Methyltransferase inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypomethylation</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypomethylating agent</keyword>
  <keyword>Epigenetic</keyword>
  <keyword>MK-3476</keyword>
  <keyword>Penbrolizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Keytruda</keyword>
  <keyword>PD-1</keyword>
  <keyword>PD-L1</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Metastatic non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
