<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="461">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02403193</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PBFCC07</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02403193</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial of PBF-509 in Patients With Advanced NSCLC</brief_title>
  <acronym>AdenONCO</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase I Trial of PBF-509 in Patients With Advanced Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Palobiofarma SL</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Palobiofarma SL</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the safety, tolerability and feasibility of an
      adenosine A2a receptor antagonist (PBF-509) during a phase I dose escalation trial in
      advanced or metastatic non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A single institution phase I clinical trial is proposed administering 3 escalating doses of
      PBF-509 to immunotherapy naïve, locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC patients to evaluate
      its safety and tolerability.

      The main objectives of the proposed Phase I trial will be:

        1. To evaluate the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics of the adenosine A2A receptor
           antagonist (A2AR) PBF-509 antagonist in lung cancer patients.

        2. To evaluate the preliminary efficacy of the adenosine A2AR antagonist PBF-509 in lung
           cancer patients.

      The lead-in phase I will evaluate 3 escalating doses of PBF-509 in stage IV NSCLC patients.

      Trial design: A traditional 3+3 design will be followed. Cohorts of 3 to 6 eligible patients
      will be treated with escalating doses of oral PBF-509. If a dose limiting toxicity (DLT)
      occurs, then 3 additional patients will be entered at the same dose level. If no more DLTs
      occur, dose escalation will proceed to the next dose level assuming/as long as all patients
      at the previous dose level completed 4 weeks of treatment.

      Assessment of toxicity: Toxicities at baseline and on study will be graded according to the
      Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 4.0 (CTCAE v4.0). DLTs will be
      assessed during cycle 1 only. DLTs will be defined as grade 4 rash, grade 3/4
      nausea/vomiting refractory to anti-emetics, grade 3/4 diarrhea refractory to anti-diarrhea
      medications, QTc prolongation ≥500 msec or &gt;480 msec on ≥2 occasions, other grade 3/4
      non-hematologic toxicity, grade 4 hematologic toxicity, or treatment-related death occurring
      within cycle 1. DLTs of special interest include grade 3 or higher pneumonitis, colitis, and
      any other autoimmune endocrinopathies (hypophysitis, thyroiditis).

      The 15 patients expected to be enrolled in the trial will be seen weekly and observed
      through a 28-day DLT period before initiating enrollment to the following cohort. Patients
      who develop a DLT will be allowed to continue on study at the immediately lower dose level
      for PBF-509, at the discretion of the treating physician, and only after the adverse event
      has resolved to grade ≤1.

      PBF-509 will be administered twice daily throughout every 28-days cycle. Subjects will enter
      follow-up either after confirmation of progressive disease (PD) or completion of 12 months
      of treatment.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>The safety evaluation will be based on the treated Population, which includes all subjects who receive any dose of investigational product, and will include AEs, SAEs, laboratory evaluations and ECG results. Summary statistics will be provided for AEs, SAEs, and AE grade, severity, and relationship to investigational product.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to PBF-509 peak concentration in plasma &quot;Tmax&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the time (in minutes) to reach the maximum &quot;PBF-509&quot; concentration in plasma samples of patients after oral administration of PBF-509.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to PBF-509 peak concentration in plasma at steady state &quot;Tmax,ss&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the time (in minutes) to reach the maximum &quot;PBF-509&quot; concentration in plasma samples of patients during a dosing interval at steady state.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PBF-509 peak concentration in plasma &quot;Cmax&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the maximum plasma concentration (ng/mL) of PBF-509 observed after administration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PBF-509 peak concentration in plasma at steady state&quot;Cmax,ss&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the maximum plasma concentration (ng/mL) of PBF-509 observed during a dosing interval at steady state.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The area under PBF-509 plasma concentration-time curve to infinite time &quot;AUC(0-inf)&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the area under the concentration-time curve from zero up to ∞ with extrapolation of the terminal phase. &quot;AUC(0-inf)&quot; will be given in Amount·time/ volume units</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The area under PBF-509 plasma concentration-time curve up to time 't' &quot;AUC(0-t)&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the area under the concentration-time curve from zero up to a definite time t. &quot;AUC(0-t)&quot; will be given in Amount·time/ volume units.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The area under PBF-509 plasma concentration-time curve over the dosing interval &quot;AUC(0-τ)&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the area under the concentration-time curve over the dosing interval. &quot;AUC(0-τ)&quot; will be given in Amount·time/ volume units.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PBF-509 half-life in plasma &quot; t½&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the terminal half-life of PBF-509 in plasma. &quot;t½&quot; will be given in hours (h)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PBF-509 apparent volume of distribution following extravascular administration&quot;Vd/F&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the apparent volume of distribution during terminal phase after oral / extravascular administration. &quot;Vd/F&quot; will be given in Volume or volume/kg units.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PBF-509 total body clearance following extravascular administration &quot;Cl/F&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the apparent total plasma or serum clearance of drug after oral administration. &quot;Cl/F&quot; will be given in the Volume/ time or volume/ time/ kg units.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The PBF 509 accumulation index &quot;Rac&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>8 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The parameter will be calculated from plasma samples collected at days 1 and 8 after drug administration.
It will consist in the accumulation ratio calculated from Cmax,ss at steady state and Cmax after single dosing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy as measured by Objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>ORR: Response and progression will be evaluated in this study using the new international criteria proposed by the revised Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) guideline (version 1.1). Changes in the largest diameter (unidimensional measurement) of the tumor lesions and the shortest diameter in the case of malignant lymph nodes are used.
The same method of assessment and the same technique should be used to characterize each identified and reported lesion at baseline and during follow-up. Radiographic assessments will be performed every 2 cycles of 28 days administration. Imaging-based evaluation methods as chest x-ray, conventional computed tomography (CT) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) will be used.
Only those patients who have measurable disease present at baseline, have received at least one cycle of therapy, and have had their disease re-evaluated will be considered evaluable for ORR response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy as measured by Disease control rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The disease control rate (DCR) will be estimated considering the following variables:
Complete response (CR), Partial response (PR) and stable disease (SD) as described by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) guideline (version 1.1).
These variables will be assessed based on Imaging-based evaluation methods as chest x-ray, conventional computed tomography (CT) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) that will be performed every 2 cycles of 28 days administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy as measured by duration of response (DoR)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Duration of response (DoR) is defined as the duration from the first documentation of objective response (OR) to the first documented disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy as measured by progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Progression-free survival (PFS) will be measured from the start of treatment until the documentation of disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first. For subjects who are alive and progression-free at the time of data cut-off for analysis, PFS will be censored at the last tumor assessment date.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy as measured by overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overall survival (OS) will be determined as the time from the start of treatment with PBF-509 until death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509 _80 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be orally administered with 80 mg of PBF-509 twice daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509 _160 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be orally administered with 160 mg of PBF-509 twice daily.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509 _320 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be orally administered with 320 mg of PBF-509 twice daily.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509_640 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be orally administered with 640 mg of PBF-509 twice daily.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PBF-509</intervention_name>
    <description>PBF-509: 80 mg, PO, twice daily (BID)
1 capsule of PBF-509 formulated in 80 mg gelatin capsules will be administered orally, twice daily, during 28-day cycle.
Subjects will enter follow-up either after confirmation of progressive disease (PD) or completion of 12 months of treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509 _80 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PBF-509</intervention_name>
    <description>PBF-509: 160 mg, PO, twice daily (BID)
2 capsules of PBF-509 formulated in 80 mg gelatin capsules will be administered orally, twice daily, during 28-day cycle.
Subjects will enter follow-up either after confirmation of progressive disease (PD) or completion of 12 months of treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509 _160 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PBF-509</intervention_name>
    <description>PBF-509: 320 mg, PO, twice daily (BID)
4 capsules of PBF-509 formulated in 80 mg gelatin capsules will be administered orally, twice daily, during 28-day cycle.
Subjects will enter follow-up either after confirmation of progressive disease (PD) or completion of 12 months of treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509 _320 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PBF-509</intervention_name>
    <description>PBF-509: 640 mg, PO, twice daily (BID)
8 capsules of PBF-509 formulated in 80 mg gelatin capsules will be administered orally, twice daily, during 28-day cycle.
Subjects will enter follow-up either after confirmation of progressive disease (PD) or completion of 12 months of treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PBF-509_640 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Histological or cytological diagnosis of NSCLC.

          2. Progressed on or intolerant to a platinum-containing doublet

          3. No limits to the prior lines of treatment

          4. EGFR mutation with deletion 19 or L858R mutation (Exon 21) or ALK rearrangement
             positive must have failed prior TKI therapy.

          5. ECOG performance status of 0/1

          6. Age greater than 18 years.

          7. Adequate bone marrow, renal and hepatic function

          8. Able and willing to give valid written consent for available archival tumor samples

          9. Written informed consent and any locally-required authorization obtained from the
             subject prior to performing any protocol-related procedures, including screening
             evaluations

         10. Subject is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study

         11. Female subjects must either be of non-reproductive potential or have to use non
             hormonal contraceptive measures, such as, occlusive cap (diaphragm or cervical/vault
             cap) with spermicide or condom.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Progressive, symptomatic, untreated Brain Metastases

          2. Pregnancy or breast feeding

          3. Serious uncontrolled medical disorder or active infection that would impair the
             patient's ability to receive study treatment.

          4. Concurrent use of other anticancer approved or investigational agents is not allowed.

          5. Autoimmune disorder Prior malignancy in past 2 years. See the protocol for more
             detail.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alberto Chiappori, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Moffitt Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nahomi Castro Palomino, PhD</last_name>
    <email>ncastro@palobiofarma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H.Lee Moffitt Cancer center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alberto Chiappori, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01691924?term=pbf-509&amp;rank=1</url>
    <description>Randomized, Double Blind, Placebo Controlled &quot;first in-human&quot; Study to Assess the Safety and Tolerability of Single Ascending Oral Doses of PBF-509 in Male Healthy Volunteers&quot;</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02111330?term=pbf-509&amp;rank=2</url>
    <description>Randomized, double blind, placebo controlled, parallel groups study to assess the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetic profile of PBF-509 (80 mg, 160 mg and 240 mg) after multiple oral doses&quot; in healthy volunteers&quot;</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>March 29, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 17, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Adenosine A2a receptor antagonist</keyword>
  <keyword>NSCLC</keyword>
  <keyword>PBF-509</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>check point inhibitor</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
