<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="506">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 16, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02452268</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AT-ONC-101</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CRADA #02949</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02452268</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Subcutaneous Recombinant Human hetIL-15 (IL15/sIL-15Ra) in Adults With Metastatic Cancers</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Study of Subcutaneous Recombinant Human hetIL-15 (IL15/sIL-15Ra) in Adults With Metastatic Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Admune Therapeutics LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Admune Therapeutics LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Phase 1 trial will define the side effect profile and the maximum tolerated dose (MTD)
      of hetIL-15, in subjects with advanced metastatic cancers. hetIL-15 is synthetic version of
      a protein normally made in the human body to stimulate white blood cells and may be able to
      boost the number or activity of these cells to attack these cancers
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1, single center clinical trial. The design is open label, single arm, dose
      escalation in subjects with advanced metastatic cancers who have failed standard treatments
      and for which curative or palliative measures either do not exist or are not associated with
      a survival advantage. The study population involves male or female subjects, at least 18
      years old who have a confirmed diagnosis of cancer that is now metastatic and refractory to
      or inappropriate for standard medical treatments.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) of subcutaneous hetIL-15. Dose limiting toxicities (DLT) will be evaluated at each visit during Cycle 1.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of hetIL-15 as determined by DLTs during Cycle 1.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of hetIL-15, including T½ and Cmax.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize the pharmacodynamic effects of hetIL-15 on the percentages and absolute numbers of circulating lymphocytes and T-cell subsets (naive, central, or effector memory subsets) by flow cytometry and the plasma levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the antitumor activity of hetIL-15</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Skin Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Renal Cell Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>hetIL-15</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single treatment arm, dose escalation administered subcutaneously (SC) on MWF for 2 consecutive weeks.
Cycle length 28 days.
Occurrence of a dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) leads to the expansion to 6 subjects.
MTD is the dose prior to the dose level where ≥ 2/6 subjects have a DLT.
A total of 9 subjects will be treated at the MTD.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>hetIL-15</intervention_name>
    <description>Subcutaneous administration of hetIL-15 three times a week for two consecutive weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>hetIL-15</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>IL-15/sIL-15Ra, heterodimeric IL-15</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          1. Histologically confirmed solid tumor malignancy that is metastatic or unresectable
             and have progressed on at least 1 prior therapy and for whom standard curative or
             palliative measures do not exist or are associated with minimal subject survival
             benefit.

             Evaluable or measurable disease, defined as by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid
             Tumors (RECIST).

          2. Recovered to ≤ grade 1 NCI CTCAE version 4.0 from toxicity of prior chemotherapy or
             biologic therapy administered more than 4 weeks earlier.

          3. Subjects on bisphosphonates for any cancer or on hormone therapy for prostate cancer
             may continue this therapy. However, subjects with prostate cancer must have confirmed
             metastatic disease that has progressed despite hormonal therapy producing castrate
             levels of testosterone.

          4. Age ≥18 years.

          5. ECOG performance status ≤1 (Karnofsky ≥70%).

          6. Normal organ and marrow function:

               -  leukocytes ≥3,000/mcL

               -  absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1,500/mcL

               -  platelets ≥100,000/mcL

               -  total bilirubin within normal institutional limits

               -  AST/ALT ≤2.5 × ULN

               -  creatinine &lt;1.5 × institutional ULN OR

               -  creatinine clearance ≥60 mL/min/1.73 m2 for subjects with serum creatinine
                  levels &gt;1.5 × higher than ULN.

          7. DLCO/VA and FEV1 ≥ 50% of predicted on PFTs.

          8. Subjects with inactive central nervous system (CNS) metastasis are eligible..

          9. Women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception
             prior to study entry, during the treatment portion of the study and for 4 months
             after completion of hetIL-15 administration.

         10. Able to provide written informed consent.

         11. Life expectancy &gt; 3 months.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          1. Prior IL-15 treatment or cytotoxic therapy, immunotherapy, radiotherapy, major
             surgery, antitumor vaccines or monoclonal antibodies in the 4 weeks prior or for
             checkpoint inhibitors such as anti-CTLA-4 or anti PD1/PD-L1 or nitrosoureas or
             mitomycin C for 6 weeks prior to C1D1.

          2. Primary brain cancers or active CNS metastases should be excluded from this clinical
             trial

          3. History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic
             composition to hetIL-15.

          4. Concurrent anticancer therapy (including other investigational agents) with the
             exception of hormone therapy for prostate cancer.

          5. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac
             arrhythmia, cognitive impairment, active substance abuse, or psychiatric
             illness/social situations that, in the view of the Investigator, would preclude safe
             treatment or the ability to give informed consent and limit compliance with study
             requirements.

          6. HIV positive patients.

          7. Positive hepatitis B or C serology.

          8. History of severe asthma or absolute requirement for chronic inhaled corticosteroid
             medications.

          9. History of autoimmune disease, with the exception of an autoimmune event associated
             with prior ipilimumab (anti-CTLA-4) therapy that has been completely resolved for
             more than 4 weeks prior to C1D1.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kevin C Conlon, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kevin C Conlon, MD</last_name>
    <phone>301-402-2913</phone>
    <email>conlonkc@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Institute, National Institute of Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kevin C. Conlon, MD</last_name>
      <phone>301-402-2913</phone>
      <email>conlonkc@mail.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kevin C. Conlon, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>January 4, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>March 2, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
