<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="212">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 22, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01431209</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>283-11</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01431209</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ruxolitinib Phosphate (Oral JAK Inhibitor INCB18424) in Treating Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Diffuse Large B-Cell or Peripheral T-Cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Multicenter, Investigator Initiated Study of Oral Ruxolitinib Phosphate for the Treatment of Relapsed or Refractory Diffuse Large B-cell and Peripheral T-cell Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Nebraska</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Incyte Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Nebraska</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies how well giving ruxolitinib phosphate (oral JAK inhibitor
      INCB18424) works in treating patients with relapsed or refractory diffuse large B-cell or
      peripheral T-cell non-hodgkin lymphoma and are ineligible to stem cell transplant or have
      recurrent disease after stem cell transplant. Ruxolitinib phosphate may stop the growth of
      cancer cells by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Assess the overall response rate (ORR) of subjects with relapsed diffuse large B-cell
      lymphoma (DLBCL) and peripheral T-cell lymphoma (PTCL) who are relapsed or refractory to
      front-line treatment and ineligible for stem cell transplantation or have recurrent disease
      after stem cell transplantation to oral ruxolitinib.

      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Evaluate safety of oral ruxolitinib in subjects with DLBCL and PTCL. II. Determine
      progression-free survival (PFS), duration of response, and overall response (OS) in subjects
      with DLBCL and PTCL.

      TERTIARY OBJECTIVES:

      I. Explore the relationship between responses to oral ruxolitinib and alterations in gene
      expression profiling (GEP) signatures as well as biomarker immunophenotypic changes related
      to JAK2/STAT3, NF-κB, BCR, PI3K/AKT, and mTOR pathways.

      II. Evaluate potential effect of oral ruxolitinib exposure on JAK2/STAT3 pathway inhibition
      in serial tumor samples.

      OUTLINE:

      Patients receive ruxolitinib phosphate (oral JAK inhibitor INCB18424) orally (PO) twice
      daily (BID). Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or
      unacceptable toxicity.

      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 1 year and
      then every 6 months thereafter.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients achieving overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>after 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of treatment-emerged adverse events (new or worsening from baseline) as summarized by severity and type according to National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after study treatment has ended</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of complete or partial remission documented to date of recurrence/progression, death due to any cause, or lost to follow-up, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The Kaplan-Meier method will be used to estimate the median duration of response and its 95% confidence interval (CI).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of start of treatment to the date of event defined as the first documented progression or death due to any cause, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The Kaplan-Meier method will be used to estimate PFS and its 95% CI.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of start of treatment to date of death due to any cause, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The Kaplan-Meier method will be used to estimate the median OS time and its 95% CI.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral T-cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Adult Diffuse Large Cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Adult T-cell Leukemia/Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oral ruxolitinib phosphate)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive ruxolitinib phosphate (oral JAK inhibitor INCB18424) PO BID. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>oral JAK inhibitor INCB18424</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients receive ruxolitinib phosphate (oral JAK inhibitor INCB18424) PO BID. Courses repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oral ruxolitinib phosphate)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>oral Janus-associated kinase inhibitor INCB18424</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>laboratory biomarker analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oral ruxolitinib phosphate)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pharmacological study</intervention_name>
    <description>Correlative studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (oral ruxolitinib phosphate)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Subjects must have histologically documented relapsed or refractory disease, with a
             diagnosis of one of the following lymphoid malignancies: Diffuse Large B-cell
             Lymphoma, Peripheral T-cell Lymphoma (any subtype). Subjects must have received at
             least one prior systemic chemotherapy and must have either received an autologous
             stem cell transplant, refused or been deemed ineligible for an autologous stem cell
             transplant

          -  Subjects must be willing and able to have a fresh tumor biopsy prior to start of
             study treatment for research evaluations

          -  Subjects must have measurable lesions (at least one target lesion measuring 2 cm in
             diameter) by computerized tomography (CT) scan, and/or measurable lymphoma cutaneous
             lesions

          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0-2

          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,000/mm^3

          -  Platelet count &gt;= 75,000/mm^3

          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 8.0 g/dL

          -  Serum creatinine =&lt; 2.0 g/dL or calculated creatinine clearance &gt;= 60mL/min
             (Cockcroft-Gault Method)

          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) =&lt; 2.5 x
             institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) or =&lt; 5 x ULN if liver involved by lymphoma

          -  Bilirubin &lt; 2.0 x ULN unless subject has Gilbert's disease, low-grade hemolysis, or
             liver involvement with lymphoma

          -  At least 2 weeks since prior chemotherapy, biological therapy, radiation therapy,
             major surgery, other investigational, or anti-cancer therapy that is considered
             disease-directed and recovered from prior toxicities to Grade 0-1 at least 2 weeks
             prior to investigational therapy

          -  Females will be either postmenopausal for at least 1 year or surgically sterile for
             at least 3 months OR Females of child-bearing potential must have a negative
             pregnancy test at screening and agree to take appropriate precautions to avoid
             pregnancy from screening through follow-up

          -  Males must agree to take appropriate precautions to avoid fathering a child from
             screening through follow-up

          -  Able to comprehend and willing to sign an Informed Consent Form (ICF)

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  History of or active central nervous system (CNS) malignancy

          -  Allogeneic stem cell transplant within the last 6 months, or active-graft-versus-host
             disease following allogeneic transplant, or subjects currently on immunosuppressive
             therapy following allogeneic transplant

          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing active
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situation that would limit compliance with
             study requirements as judged by treating physician; subjects receiving antibiotics
             that are under control may be included in the study

          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding women

          -  Clinically symptomatic and uncontrolled cardiovascular disease

          -  History of myocardial infarction, severe/unstable angina, or symptomatic congestive
             heart failure, within the 6 months prior to study drug administration

          -  Current or recent history (&lt; 21 days prior to start of treatment) of a clinically
             significant bacterial, viral, fungal, parasitic or mycobacterial infection

          -  History of other malignancy, with the exception of squamous cell carcinoma of the
             skin, basal cell carcinoma of the skin, cervical intraepithelial neoplasia, or other
             malignancies that have been in remission for at least 3 years

          -  Presence of a malabsorption syndrome possibly affecting drug absorption (e.g.,
             Crohn's disease or chronic pancreatitis)

          -  Any prior or concomitant use of another JAK inhibitor

          -  Known active hepatitis B or C, or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection

          -  Subjects who, in the opinion of the Investigator, are unable or unlikely to comply
             with the dosing schedule and study evaluations
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Julie M Vose, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Nebraska</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Susan Blumel, RN</last_name>
    <phone>402-559-9183</phone>
    <email>sblumel@unmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mark O Hatfield-Warren Grant Magnuson Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Peggy Shovlin, RN</last_name>
      <phone>301-594-6597</phone>
      <email>mshovlin@mail.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wyndham Wilson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Melissa Harvey</last_name>
      <phone>507-266-3784</phone>
      <email>harvery.melissa@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thomas Witzig, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Nebraska Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68198-7830</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Susan Blumel, RN</last_name>
      <phone>402-559-9183</phone>
      <email>sblumel@unmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Julie Vose, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas, MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Javier R R Knickerbocker, APN</last_name>
      <phone>713-792-2860</phone>
      <email>jknicker@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yasuhiro Oki, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>December 2, 2014</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>September 5, 2011</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Nebraska</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Julie M Vose, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Neumann M. and Mildred E. Harris Professor, Chief, Division of Hematology/Oncology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>No</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia-Lymphoma, Adult T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Peripheral</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
