<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="69">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 22, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02445976</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INO-VT-464-CL-003</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>VMT-VT-464-CL-003</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02445976</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Once-daily Oral VT-464 in Patients With Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer Progressing on Enzalutamide or Abiraterone.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Single-arm, Phase 2 Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of VT-464 in Patients With Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer Progressing on Enzalutamide or Abiraterone.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Innocrin Pharmaceutical</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Prostate Cancer Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Prostate Cancer Clinical Trials Consortium</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Innocrin Pharmaceutical</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical study is to determine the safety and efficacy of VT-464, a
      lyase-selective inhibitor of CYP17 and an androgen receptor antagonist, in patients with
      castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC) who have been previously treated with
      enzalutamide or abiraterone.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase 2 clinical trial of VT-464 (an oral, potent and lyase-selective CYP17
      inhibitor) in chemotherapy-naïve men with castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC)
      progressing on enzalutamide or abiraterone. A maximal 148 patient Simon two-stage design
      will be used to assess treatment efficacy. The study will be conducted in four different
      clinical cohorts separated by prior exposure to enzalutamide or abiraterone acetate, and
      prior response to the agent (37 patients per cohort).
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Allocation: Non-Randomized, Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Parallel Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of patients who have a PSA response by 12 weeks of starting treatment with VT-464</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>PSA response to VT-464 within the first 12 weeks of treatment defined by a ≥ 50% decrease in serum PSA.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of patients who have a PSA response at 12 weeks of starting treatment with VT-464</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>PSA response to VT-464 at 12 weeks of treatment defined by a ≥ 50% decrease in serum PSA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The median rPFS and 6-month rPFS rate</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The rPFS with VT-464 will be evaluated using CT and bone scans.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The radiologic response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The radiologic response rate with VT-464 will be evaluated using CT and bone scans.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>36 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The overall response rate with VT-464 will be evaluated using scheduled follow-up for up to 3 years after discontinuing VT-464.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability assessed by the collection of adverse events will occur from the start of dosing with VT-464 until one month after dosing is discontinued.</measure>
    <time_frame>10 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarkers that predict clinical outcomes to VT-464 in CRPC patients who have progressed on enzalutamide or abiraterone.</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Both circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) and circulating tumor cells (CTCs) from patients will be evaluated to help predict response status to VT-464.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">148</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Enzalutamide - Responded</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>VT-464: given orally once daily in 28-day cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Enzalutamide - No Response</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>VT-464: given orally once daily in 28-day cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Abiraterone - Responded</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>VT-464: given orally once daily in 28-day cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Abiraterone - No Response</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>VT-464: given orally once daily in 28-day cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>VT-464: given orally once daily in 28-day cycles</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral VT-464 given once daily, in continuous 28-day cycles at the recommended Phase 2 dose</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Enzalutamide - Responded</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Enzalutamide - No Response</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Abiraterone - Responded</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prior Abiraterone - No Response</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>VT-464</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria

          1. Patients must have documented histological or cytological evidence of adenocarcinoma
             of the prostate.

          2. Patients must have received enzalutamide or abiraterone for CRPC. Patients who have
             received combination enzalutamide/abiraterone or combination ARN509/abiraterone as
             part of ongoing clinical trials are allowed and will be included in &quot;Prior
             Abiraterone&quot; arm of this study. Prior treatment with sequential
             enzalutamide-abiraterone or abiraterone-enzalutamide will not be allowed. Prior
             treatment with first-generation AR antagonists (i.e., bicalutamide, nilutamide,
             flutamide) before abiraterone or enzalutamide is allowed.

          3. Patients must have demonstrated disease progression while on enzalutamide and/or
             abiraterone.

             Progressive disease is defined by one or more of the following:

               -  A rise in PSA on two successive determinations at least one week apart and PSA
                  level ≥2ng/ml.

               -  Soft-tissue progression defined by RECIST 1.1

               -  Bone disease progression defined by PCWG2 with two or more new lesions on bone
                  scan

          4. Patients must have a minimum serum PSA level of ≥2 ng/ml that is rising based on the
             PCWG2 criteria.

          5. Patients must be ≥18 years of age.

          6. Patients must have castrate levels of testosterone (&lt;50 ng/dl [1.74 nmol/l]).

          7. Patients must have undergone orchiectomy, or have been on LHRH agonists or
             antagonists, for at least 3 months prior to drug initiation. Patients on LHRH
             agonists/antagonists must remain on these agents for the duration of the study.

          8. Patients must have an ECOG Performance Score of 0-1.

          9. Patients must have adequate hematopoietic function as evidenced by:

               -  WBC ≥3,000/µl

               -  ANC ≥1,500/µl

               -  Platelet count ≥100,000/µl

               -  HGB ≥10 g/dl

         10. Patients must have adequate hepatic function as evidenced by AST/ALT levels &lt;3X the
             ULN and bilirubin levels of &lt;2.0 mg/dl.

         11. Patients must have adequate renal function as evidenced by a serum creatinine of &lt;2.0
             mg/dl.

         12. Patients must have K+ &gt;3.5 mEq/l.

         13. Patients or their legal representatives must be able to provide written informed
             consent.

         14. Patients must have discontinued enzalutamide or abiraterone/prednisolone ≥4 weeks
             prior to study drug initiation.

         15. Patients who have partners of child-bearing potential must be willing to use at least
             two forms of effective birth control (one form must be a barrier method) during the
             treatment period and for 90 days after last dose of VT-464. Patients must also agree
             to not donate sperm through 90 days following the last dose of VT-464.

        Exclusion Criteria

          1. 1. Patients who have received prior cytotoxic chemotherapy for castration-resistant
             prostate cancer. Prior docetaxel for castration-sensitive disease is permitted.

          2. Patients who have received TAK-700 (Orteronel®), TOK-001 (Galeterone®), ARN-509 or
             any other therapeutic investigational product directed towards the androgen receptor
             (AR) or androgen biosynthesis. Patients who receive ARN-509 in combination with
             abiraterone as part of a clinical trial are allowed.

          3. Patients who have received ketoconazole, aminoglutethimide, or high-dose estrogen for
             CRPC.

          4. Patients who have completed sipuleucel-T (Provenge ®) treatment within 30 days of
             study drug initiation.

          5. Patients on 5 alpha reductase inhibitors such as finasteride (PROSCAR®, PROPECIA®),
             or dutasteride (AVODART®) within 3 months from study drug initiation.

          6. Patients who require pharmacologic or replacement doses of systemic corticosteroids
             or who have received systemic corticosteroids within 30 days of study drug
             initiation; use of topical, inhaled or ophthalmic steroids is permitted.

          7. Patients who have received any therapeutic investigational agent within 2 weeks of
             study drug initiation.

          8. Patients who have received palliative radiotherapy within 4 weeks of study drug
             initiation.

          9. Patients who have received herbal products or alternative therapies that may decrease
             PSA levels or that may have hormonal anti-prostate cancer activity (e.g., saw
             palmetto, PC-SPES, PC-HOPE, St. John's wort, selenium supplements, grape seed
             extract, etc.) within 4 weeks of study drug initiation or plans to initiate treatment
             with these products/alternative therapies during the entire duration of the study.

         10. Patients with active CNS metastases from prostate cancer. Patients with treated
             epidural disease are eligible to enroll. Patients with treated brain metastases can
             be included as long as &gt;4 weeks have elapsed since last treatment (radiotherapy or
             surgery) for brain metastases, the patient is neurologically and radiographically
             stable, and is not receiving corticosteroids for brain metastases. Patients with
             untreated brain metastases are excluded. Brain imaging (CT or MRI) is not required at
             baseline if brain metastases are not clinically suspected.

         11. Patients with a history of adrenal insufficiency. Patients who have received systemic
             corticosteroids for &gt;2 weeks within 6 months of study drug initiation (including
             those receiving prednisolone with abiraterone) must have adrenal insufficiency ruled
             out by a morning plasma cortisol concentration ≥500 nmol/l or a plasma cortisol
             response to an ACTH stimulation test that is deemed clinically normal.

         12. Patients with a history within the last 3 years of another invasive malignancy
             (excluding non-melanoma skin cancer).

         13. Patients with a QTcF interval of &gt;470 msec; if the Screening ECG QTcF interval is
             &gt;470 msec, it may be repeated, and if repeat ≤470 msec, the patient may be enrolled.

         14. Patients with a history of clinically significant cardiac arrhythmias including
             ventricular tachycardia, ventricular fibrillation, torsades de pointes and second
             degree or third degree atrioventricular heart block without a permanent pacemaker in
             place. Patients with resolved or rate-controlled atrial fibrillation/atrial flutter
             are allowed.

         15. Patients with NYHA Class III or IV congestive heart failure, unstable angina,
             myocardial infarction/acute coronary syndrome within the preceding 6 months.

         16. Patients with diabetes mellitus who have had more than 2 episodes of diabetic
             ketoacidosis in the preceding 12 months.

         17. Inadequately controlled hypertension (defined as blood pressure &gt;150mmHg systolic
             and/or &gt;100 mmHg diastolic despite antihypertensive medication) or any history of
             hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy.

         18. Patients with a history of seizure within the past 2 years or those who require
             prophylactic anti-seizure medications are excluded.

         19. History of loss of consciousness or transient ischemic attack within 12 months before
             study drug initiation.

         20. Patients who have known active HIV, Hepatitis B, or Hepatitis C infections.

         21. Patients with any other medical, psychiatric, or social condition, including
             substance abuse, which in the opinion of the Investigator would preclude safe
             participation in the study.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Joel Eisner, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>919-237-9536</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Flanagan</last_name>
      <phone>617-582-8313</phone>
      <email>David_Flanagan@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mary-Ellen Taplin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karmanos Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brenda Dickow</last_name>
      <phone>313-576-9372</phone>
      <email>dickowb@karmanos.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ulka Vaishampayan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GU Research Network</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68130</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lyndsay Morton</last_name>
      <phone>402-697-2214</phone>
      <email>lmorton@gucancer.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Luke Nordquist, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shady Prestol</last_name>
      <phone>646-227-2140</phone>
      <email>prestols@mskcc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Howard Scher, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carolina Urologic Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Myrtle Beach</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29572</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Salie Hinson</last_name>
      <phone>843-449-1010</phone>
      <email>shinson@atlanticurologyclinics.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Neal Shore, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virginia Oncology Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamton</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23666</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wendi Gobhardt</last_name>
      <phone>757-213-5813</phone>
      <email>wendi.gobhardt@usoncology.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Fleming, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Washington</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kelly Crowder</last_name>
      <email>kcrowder@seattlecca.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Monica Dherin</last_name>
      <phone>206-288-6389</phone>
      <email>mdherin1@seattlecca.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bruce Montgomery, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Wisconsin Carbone Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53715</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mary Jane Staab</last_name>
      <phone>608-263-7107</phone>
      <email>mjs@medicine.wisc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Glenn Liu, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2015</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>May 21, 2015</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>May 13, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>mCRPC</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic</keyword>
  <keyword>castration-resistant prostate cancer</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
