<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="182">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd
 and an XML DTD at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.dtd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on June 22, 2016</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02336451</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CLDK378A2205</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02336451</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase II Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Oral Ceritinib in Patients With ALK-positive NSCLC Metastatic to the Brain and/or to Leptomeninges</brief_title>
  <acronym>Ascend-7</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Multi-center, Open-label, Five-arm Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Oral Ceritinib Treatment for Patients With ALK-positive Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) Metastatic to the Brain and/or to Leptomeninges</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Novartis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <authority>United States: Food and Drug Administration</authority>
    <authority>New Zealand: Ministry of Health</authority>
    <authority>Canada: Health Canada</authority>
    <authority>Hong Kong: Department of Health</authority>
    <authority>Spain: Agencia Española de Medicamentos y Productos Sanitarios</authority>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase II, multi-center, open-label, five-arm study in which the efficacy and
      safety of oral ceritinib treatment will be assessed in patients with NSCLC metastatic to the
      brain and/or to leptomeninges harboring a confirmed ALK rearrangement, using the FDA
      approved Vysis ALK Break Apart FISH Probe Kit (Abbott Molecular Inc.) test and scoring
      algorithm (including positivity criteria). If documentation of ALK rearrangement as
      described above is not locally available, a test to confirm ALK rearrangement must be
      performed by a Novartis designated central laboratory. Patients must wait for the central
      laboratory result of the ALK rearrangement status before initiating treatment with
      ceritinib.
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Approximately 125 patients diagnosed with ALK-positive metastatic NSCLC (according to the
      7th edition of the AJCC [American Joint Committee on Cancer] Cancer Staging Manual) and
      active lesions in the brain and/or diagnosed with leptomeningeal carcinomatosis will be
      included in the study, approximately 30 patients in each of the Arms 1 to 4 and
      approximately 5 patients in Arm 5.

        -  Arm 1 will include patients with metastases in the brain without evidence of
           leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, previously treated with radiation to the brain and with
           prior exposure to an ALKi.

        -  Arm 2 will include patients with metastases in the brain without evidence of
           leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, previously untreated with radiation to the brain but
           with prior exposure to an ALKi.

        -  Arm 3 will include patients with metastases in the brain without evidence of
           leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, previously treated with radiation to the brain but with
           no prior exposure to an ALKi.

        -  Arm 4 will include patients with metastases in the brain without evidence of
           leptomeningeal carcinomatosis, previously untreated with radiation to the brain and
           with no prior exposure to an ALKi

        -  Arm 5 will include any patients with leptomeningeal carcinomatosis with or without
           evidence of active lesion at the baseline Gadoliniumenhanced brain MRI. Note: Previous
           treatment with ALK inhibitors other than crizotinib is not allowed in Arms 1, 2, and 5.

      Ceritinib will be administered orally once daily at a dose of 750 mg (five 150 mg capsules)
      on a continuous dosing schedule. The treatment period will start on Cycle 1 Day 1.

      Complete tumor assessments including gadolinium enhanced brain MRI will be repeated at Week
      8 (on Cycle 3 Day 1) and every 8 weeks (i.e. every 2 cycles) thereafter or earlier if
      clinically indicated. Safety evaluations will include (S)AEs, physical examination, vital
      signs, ECGs, laboratory parameters and WHO performance status. Blood and CSF samples for PK
      will also be collected.
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design>Endpoint Classification: Safety/Efficacy Study, Intervention Model: Single Group Assignment, Masking: Open Label, Primary Purpose: Treatment</study_design>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overall response rate (ORR), defined as the proportion of patients with a best overall confirmed response of CR or PR in the whole body as assessed per RECIST 1.1 by the investigator</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>The DCR is defined as the proportion of patients with a best overall response of CR, PR or SD in the whole body, as assessed per RECIST 1.1 by the investigator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Intracranial Response Rate (OIRR) per modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>• Overall Intracranial Response Rate (OIRR) by Investigator and BIRC for patients with measurable brain metastases at baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracranial Disease Control Rate (IDCR) per modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Intracranial Disease Control Rate (IDCR) at 24 weeks and overall by Investigator and BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to intracranial tumor response (TTIR) per modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time to intracranial tumor response (TTIR) by Investigator and BIRC for patients with measurable brain metastases at baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of intracranial response (DOIR) per modified RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Duration of intracranial response (DOIR) by Investigator and BIRC for patients with measurable brain metastases at baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Extracranial Response Rate (OERR) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overall Extracranial Response Rate (OERR) by Investigator and BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extracranial Disease Control Rate (EDCR) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Extracranial Disease Control Rate (EDCR) at 24 weeks by Investigator and BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to extracranial tumor response (TTER) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time to extracranial tumor response (TTER) by Investigator and BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of extracranial response (DOER) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Duration of extracranial response (DOER) by Investigator and BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR) (whole body) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overall response rate (ORR) by BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate (DCR) (whole body) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Disease control rate (DCR) by BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to tumor response (TTR) (whole body) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Time to tumor response (TTR) by Investigator and BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR) (whole body) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Duration of response (DOR) by Investigator by BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS) (whole body) per RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Progression free survival (PFS) by Investigator by BIRC</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overal survival</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Overal survival (OS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>Yes</safety_issue>
    <description>AEs, ECGs and laboratory abnormalities</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of ceritinib in study population</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <safety_issue>No</safety_issue>
    <description>Cmax on C2D1 and Cmin concentrations of ceritinib in plasma.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">125</enrollment>
  <condition>ALK-positive NSCLC Metastatic to the Brain and/or to Leptomeninges.</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LDK378</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>LDK378 will be administered orally once daily at a dose of 750 mg (five 150 mg capsules) on a continuous dosing schedule. The treatment period will start on Cycle 1 Day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LDK378</intervention_name>
    <description>LDK378 (ceritinib) 750 mg once daily, orally administered</description>
    <arm_group_label>LDK378</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ceritinib</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of metastatic NSCLC according to
             the 7th edition of the AJCC Cancer Staging Manual. In addition, the NSCLC must harbor
             an ALK rearrangement, as assessed using the FDA approved Vysis ALK Break Apart FISH
             Probe Kit (Abbott Molecular Inc.) test and scoring algorithm (including positivity
             criteria). If documentation of ALK rearrangement as described above is not locally
             available, a test to confirm ALK rearrangement must be performed by a Novartis
             designated central laboratory. Patients must wait for the central laboratory result
             of the ALK rearrangement status before initiating treatment with ceritinib

          -  At least one extracranial measurable lesion as defined by RECIST 1.1. A previously
             irradiated site lesion may only be counted as a target lesion if there is clear sign
             of progression since the irradiation.

          -  Patients may or may not have neurological symptoms but must be able to swallow and
             retain oral medication. Be neurologically stable within at least 1 week prior to the
             first dose of study drug.

          -  Patients may have received prior chemotherapy, crizotinib (other ALK inhibitors are
             not allowed), biologic therapy or other investigational agents. Patients must have
             recovered from all toxicities related to prior anticancer therapies to grade ≤ 1
             (CTCAE v 4.03). Patients with any grade of alopecia are allowed to enter the study.

          -  Patient has life expectancy ≥ 6 weeks.

          -  Patient has a WHO performance status 0-2.

        Patients in Arm 1 to 4 must also meet the following inclusion criteria:

        - Patients must have active brain metastases from NSCLC, confirmed by Gadolinium-enhanced
        MRI without concomitant leptomeningeal carcinomatosis. Dose of steroids must be stable for
        5 days before the baseline brain MRI.

        Patients in Arm 5 must also meet the following inclusion criteria:

        - Patients must be diagnosed with leptomeningeal carcinomatosis.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patients who need whole brain radiation to control the brain metastases. Patients
             will not be eligible unless treated brain lesions are progressive or new brain
             lesions are observed since the post whole brain radiation therapy MRI.

          -  Planning of any brain local treatment (including but not limited to surgery,
             stereotactic radiosurgery, whole brain radiation, intrathecal chemotherapy) following
             the administration of the first dose of study drug.

          -  Patient with a concurrent malignancy or history of a malignant disease other than
             NSCLC that has been diagnosed and/or required therapy within the past 3 years.
             Exceptions to this exclusion include the following: completely resected basal cell
             and squamous cell skin cancers, and completely resected carcinoma in situ of any
             type.

          -  Patient has impairment of GI function or GI disease that may significantly alter the
             absorption of ceritinib (e.g., ulcerative diseases, uncontrolled nausea, vomiting,
             diarrhea, or malabsorption syndrome).

          -  Patient is receiving unstable or increasing doses of corticosteroids.

          -  Patient has other severe, acute, or chronic medical conditions including uncontrolled
             diabetes mellitus or psychiatric conditions or laboratory abnormalities that in the
             opinion of the investigator may increase the risk associated with study
             participation, or that may interfere with the interpretation of study results.

        Other protocol-defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply.
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Both</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-669-6682</phone>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone_ext>+41613241111</phone_ext>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>USC/Kenneth Norris Comprehensive Cancer Center SC-3</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maria Brown</last_name>
      <phone>323-865-0463</phone>
      <email>Maria.Brown@med.usc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Barbara J. Gitlitz</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California San Francisco SC</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94101</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Scott Hammond</last_name>
      <phone>415-514-6241</phone>
      <email>hammonds@cc.ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matthew Gubens</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University Medical Center SC-5</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Richard A Quick</last_name>
      <phone>650-724-1388</phone>
      <email>richardq@stanford.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joel Neal</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lynn Cancer Institute SC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boca Raton</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33486</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julie Gelms</last_name>
      <phone>561-955-4539</phone>
      <email>apadolina@brrh.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Edgardo Santos</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University Health Goshen Center for Cancer SC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Goshen</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46526</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Keith Margraf</last_name>
      <phone>574-364-2974</phone>
      <email>kmargraf@goshenhealth.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ebenezer Kio</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Regional Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>South Bend</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46601</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mary Jane Danner</last_name>
      <phone>+1 574 647 3305</phone>
      <email>mdanner@beaconhealthsystem.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thomas Reid, III</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana Farber Cancer Institute SC-12</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Karly Griffin</last_name>
      <phone>617-632-6749</phone>
      <email>Karly_Griffin@DFCI.HARVARD.EDU</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Patrick Y Wen</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic Foundation Burkhardt Brain Tumor</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marci Ciolfi</last_name>
      <phone>216-444-8923</phone>
      <email>ciolfim@ccf.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Manmeet Ahluwalia</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State Comprehensive Cancer Center/James Cancer Hospital Ohio State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Catherine Schweitzer</last_name>
      <phone>614-293-2268</phone>
      <email>Catherine.Schweitzer@osumc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erin Bertino</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southwestern Regional Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tulsa</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>74133</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amber Selvidge</last_name>
      <phone>918-286-5448</phone>
      <email>amber-selvidge@ouhsc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel Nader</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seattle Cancer Care Alliance SC-2</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98109-1023</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joseph Lograsso</last_name>
      <phone>206-288-6272</phone>
      <email>jlograss@seattlecca.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christina Baik</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Auckland</city>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 2M9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille cedex 20</city>
        <zip>13915</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75970</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif Cedex</city>
        <zip>94805</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bad Berka</city>
        <zip>99437</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gauting</city>
        <zip>82131</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Köln</city>
        <zip>50937</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pokfulam</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Livorno</city>
        <state>LI</state>
        <zip>57124</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monza</city>
        <state>MB</state>
        <zip>20900</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Messina</city>
        <state>ME</state>
        <zip>98158</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <state>MI</state>
        <zip>20133</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <state>MI</state>
        <zip>20141</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Perugia</city>
        <state>PG</state>
        <zip>06129</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aviano</city>
        <state>PN</state>
        <zip>33081</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Parma</city>
        <state>PR</state>
        <zip>43100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orbassano</city>
        <state>TO</state>
        <zip>10043</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Napoli</city>
        <zip>80131</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <state>Korea</state>
        <zip>05505</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <state>Korea</state>
        <zip>06351</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <state>Korea</state>
        <zip>110 744</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NKI-AVL, Department of Thoracic-Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <zip>1066 CX</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>E.F. Smit, Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>0031-20-5122958</phone>
      <email>e.smit@nki.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>E.F. Smit, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Petersburg</city>
        <state>Russia</state>
        <zip>197342</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <zip>115478</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>169610</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Malaga</city>
        <state>Andalucia</state>
        <zip>29010</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Majadahonda</city>
        <state>Madrid</state>
        <zip>28222</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28034</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28040</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tainan 704</city>
        <state>Taiwan ROC</state>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>10002</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>112</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE1 9RT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novartis Investigative Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sutton</city>
        <zip>SM2 5PT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
    <country>Singapore</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2016</verification_date>
  <lastchanged_date>February 18, 2016</lastchanged_date>
  <firstreceived_date>January 8, 2015</firstreceived_date>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ALK-positive, NSCLC, brain metastasis</keyword>
  <is_fda_regulated>Yes</is_fda_regulated>
  <is_section_801>Yes</is_section_801>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm  -->
    <mesh_term>Ceritinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                -->
</clinical_study>
